<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>深入理解计算机系统 003-Bits,Bytes,andInteger</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/12/15213-003/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/12/15213-003/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2025年10月02日 08:32<br>发言人   00:00<br>I guess one thing I and the rest of the staff request is that you, whenever you have a question, you first read the book and then you re-read the assignment, and you maybe reread it again. And then you ask us, because a lot of the questions we’re getting are ones where we just say, look at this page of the book, look at this paragraph, the assignment, look at this part of the file that you were given. And so, I mean, there’s a lot of stuff. And I understand how sometimes it’s easy to miss things, not saying don’t ever ask questions, but just before you ask your questions, try and figure out if I really sort of come through the resources I have available to see if the answer to my question can be found there. So anyways, enjoy the lab.<br>我猜我和其他员工要求的一件事是，每当你有问题时，先读这本书，然后再读一遍任务，也许再读一遍。然后你问我们，因为我们得到的很多问题都是这样的: 看看书的这一页，看看这一段，看看你被分配的文件的这一部分。所以，我的意思是，有很多东西。我理解有时候很容易错过事情，不是说永远不要问问题，但在你问问题之前，试着弄清楚我是否真的通过现有的资源来找到我问题的答案。所以无论如何，享受这个实验室。</p><span id="more"></span><p>发言人   00:55<br>So today is sort a second part of a two part lecture on integers and integer arithmetic.<br>今天是关于整数和整数算术的两部分讲座的第二部分。</p><p>发言人   01:02<br>Last time we looked at representations about how bit patterns can be interpreted as either unsigned numbers, meaning they range between 0 and 2 to the word size -1, or as twos complement numbers, which is the most usual way to represent what are sometimes called sine numbers, ones that can be either negative or positive. And by the way, there are other ways to represent sign numbers out there. Tooth complement is so overwhelmingly the most used system that that’s what we concentrate on today. What we’ll do is now go beyond the representations of these values to talk about arithmetic operations on them and some of their properties. And what we’ll do in general is talk about the unsigned case, which is in some ways easier to understand and more intuitive. And then talk about the two’s complement case.<br>上次我们看了关于位模式如何被解释为无符号数字的表示，这意味着它们的范围在0和2之间，或者作为二进制补码数字，这是表示有时被称为正弦数字的最常用方法。可以是负面的也可以是正面的。顺便说一下，还有其他的方法来表示符号数字。牙齿补足是绝大多数最常用的系统，这就是我们今天关注的重点。我们现在要做的是超越这些值的表示，讨论对它们的算术运算和它们的一些属性。一般来说，我们会谈论未签名的情况，这种情况在某些方面更容易理解，也更直观。然后谈论两者的补充情况。</p><p>发言人   02:03<br>So the basic rule on this is if you take two numbers that range between up to the maximum value of an unsigned number and you add them, then in principle, you might need to get an extra bit to represent that sum If you want to represent the true sum, the sort of integer sum of those two numbers, because you’re doubling it. And unfortunately, we can’t just go out and add more bits to your computer indefinitely. So we just stop it at some point and say, well, whatever happen to be in that sort of next over bit position? We’re just going to drop it and pretend it doesn’t exist and say that the result of addition is just whatever the W bit pattern you get if you only consider the first w bits out of it with no warning, no messages, no error or anything. This is just it happens silently.<br>因此，基本规则是，如果您将两个范围在无符号数字最大值之间的数字相加，那么原则上，如果您想表示真实的总和，您可能需要获得额外的位来表示该总和。这两个数字的整数和，因为你正在加倍它。不幸的是，我们不能无限制地向您的计算机中添加更多的位。所以我们只是在某个时候停止它，然后说，好吧，无论发生在那种下一个比特位置的是什么？我们只是要放下它，假装它不存在，并说如果你只考虑其中的前W位，而没有警告，没有消息，没有错误或任何东西，那么加法的结果就是你得到的w位模式。这只是静静地发生的事情。</p><p>发言人   03:05<br>For to complement this is not such a hard thing to understand. It can be thought of as just modular arithmetic computing modulo the two to the word size. So I’m going to use some examples. And this time I’ve got them worked out a little more carefully, won’t get mixed up as much, and we’ll use a word size of 4 here. And as I mentioned last time, it really helps with this to do the examples with small word sizes to get your intuition for it, rather than trying to write out 30 two-two bit numbers, 60 two-four bit numbers, or something like that.<br>因为补充这一点并不难理解。它可以被看作是模块化的算术计算，将两者取模为单词大小。所以我将使用一些例子。这次我让他们更仔细地制定，不会混淆太多，我们这里将使用单词大小为4。正如我上次提到的，用小字大小的例子来获得你的直觉确实有帮助，而不是试图写出30个2-2位数字，60个2-4位数字或类似的东西。</p><p>发言人   03:45<br>So if you think about in the unsigned case. A 4 b number. Means that it will range between 0 and 2 to the 4th -1 or 15. And so let’s just do a few examples of cases where it overflows. So if you add 13 to 5.<br>所以如果你考虑未签名的情况。一个4 b数字。意味着它的范围将在0到2到第4个1或15之间。所以让我们举几个它溢出的例子。所以如果你把13加到5。</p><p>发言人   04:21<br>First of all, you know, I assume already that you just add binary numbers the way you learned in school, just doing carries and so forth, except it’s all module 2. So this is zero carry 1, 1, 0 carry 1, 0 carry one. So in principle, to represent the sum, which is this is 5, So to represent 18, you need 5 b, not 4. But we’re just going to conveniently drop that number and say that this is actually two, which of course, is what 18 modules 16 is. So the unsigned case is really pretty straightforward.<br>首先，你知道，我已经假设你只是像在学校学到的那样添加二进制数，只是做进位等等，除了所有的模块2。所以这是零进位1，1，0进位1，0进位1。所以原则上，要表示总和，这是5，所以要表示18，你需要5 b，而不是4。但我们只是方便地放弃这个数字，并说这实际上是2，这当然是18个模块16的意思。所以未签名的案件真的非常简单。</p><p>发言人   05:13<br>And we can visualize this in this picture is in the book too, by saying if you are representing.<br>我们可以想象这张图片也在书中，通过说明你是否在代表。</p><p>发言人   05:21<br>On the x and y axis, what they call u and v are values between 0 and 15, the range of possible unsigned numbers. And if we were to add those, we could get a sum that’s up to as much as 30. Which would in principle, require 5 b to represent, but what we’ll do is we’ll just by dropping that most significant bit, what we do is sort of create a cliff that when you roll over from 15 to 16, instead, it drops all the way down to 0. And that’s referred to as an overflow. And then from there, we’ll build up to the maximum value here will be 14, which is 30 -16. So what we’ve done is basically, as this picture shows, when we overflow, we effectively subtract off 2 to the w from the sum and keep it within the representable range of w bit numbers.<br>在x轴和y轴上，它们所称的u和v是0到15之间的值，这是可能的无符号数字的范围。如果我们将这些相加，我们可以得到最多30的总和。原则上，需要5个b来表示，但我们要做的是通过放下最高有效位，我们所做的是创建一个悬崖，当你从15翻转到16时，它会一直下降到0。这被称为溢出。然后从那里开始，我们将积累到这里的最大值为14，即30 -16。所以我们所做的基本上是，正如这张图片所示，当我们溢出时，我们有效地从总和中减去2到w，并将其保持在w位数字的可表示范围内。</p><p>发言人   06:21<br>So that’s unsigned two comple The first thing I want to convince you of is that two’s complement edition looks just like regular edition. In other words, I can perform subtraction, addition, subtraction of numbers by using this two’s complement representation for negative numbers. So let me just show you some examples of that.<br>所以这是未签名的两个comple，我想说服你的第一件事是，两个的补充版看起来就像普通版一样。换句话说，我可以通过使用这两个负数的补码表示来执行数字的减法，加法，减法。让我给你看一些例子。</p><p>发言人   06:57<br>So first of all, remember that what range of values, what’s the smallest number that could be represented with a 4 b? The most negative number, 4 b, two’s complement number -8. And the largest plus seven, thank you. So let’s just do some examples if we took.<br>首先，请记住值的范围是什么，可以用4 b表示的最小数字是什么？最负数4 b，2的补码数-8。还有最大的加七个，谢谢。所以，如果我们采取行动，让我们做一些例子。</p><p>发言人   07:27<br>This number 1, 1 0 1 as a T’s complement number is -3. And we add it to 5. We’ll get what we got before.<br>这个数字1、0作为T的补数是-3。我们把它加到5上。我们会得到我们之前得到的。</p><p>发言人   07:52<br>And we’re going to ignore whatever carry bit it is. And so the result is 2. And lo and behold, that’s what 5 -3 is. So it seems like magic because it is. And that’s part of the reason why I choose complement is sort of the most commonly used way of representing S numbers. The same hardware, the same algorithms that are used for doing addition. It works for either unsigned or two S complement numbers.<br>我们将忽略它的任何携带位。所以结果是2。瞧，这就是5 -3。所以它看起来像魔法，因为它就是。这就是我选择补码是表示S数最常用方式的部分原因。用于加法的相同硬件和相同算法。它适用于无符号或两个补码数。</p><p>发言人   08:32<br>And this works as well. Just to show you, if the overflow goes, the resulting sum goes the other way. So if I have -3, -5, and plus three, and I add those together.<br>这也行得通。只是为了向您展示，如果溢出消失，结果总和会相反。所以，如果我有-3、-5和 + 3，我把它们加在一起。</p><p>发言人   09:04<br>I’ll get 1, 1, 1, 0, which is -2. So again, if you use the patterns for the same rule for addition as you do with the unsigned case, you’ll get two complement arithmetic. So let’s look at a few cases where the two S complement overflows.<br>我会得到1，1，1，0，即-2。因此，如果您将模式用于与无符号情况相同的加法规则，您将得到两个补码算术。因此，让我们来看一些两个S补码溢出的情况。</p><p>发言人   09:36<br>So if we take three.<br>那么，如果我们拿三个。</p><p>发言人   09:46<br>And.<br>而且。</p><p>发言人   09:54<br>Minus six. And we add them together. We’ll get 1, 1, 1, 0. We’re going to drop off the carry, which is what, 7? So we’ve added two negative numbers, and it’s become positive. And that’s referred to as a negative overflow.<br>-6。然后我们把它们加在一起。我们会得到1，1，1，0。我们要把东西放下，什么是7？所以我们添加了两个负数，它变成了正数。这被称为负溢出。</p><p>发言人   10:24<br>And the reason, of course, is the number -9 can’t be represented in a 4 b chooses complement number. It overflowed. You’ll notice that the plus seven, of course, differs from -9 by 16, and that’s not next. And then going the other direction, if we had two large positive numbers. So if we had 7. And 5?<br>当然，原因是数字-9不能在4 b选择补码数字中表示。它溢出了。你会注意到，加7当然不同于-9乘16，这不是下一个。如果我们有两个大的正数，然后朝着另一个方向前进。如果我们有7个。And 5?</p><p>发言人   11:10<br>We’ll get -6. So this was 7 plus 5. Is -4? And so this is referred to as positive overflow. We’ve taken two.<br>我们会得到-6。所以这是7加5。是-4吗？因此这被称为正溢出。我们已经拿了两个。</p><p>发言人   11:38<br>Positive numbers and added them together and gotten a negative result. And you can see this, by the way, if you think about this addition, we took 7 and 5 would be 12. And this is the bit level representation of 12. It’s just that because this is now the sine bit, we think of that as -4, not positive 12. And so that’s the idea of two’s complement overflow. And you can see there’s two different cases here. One is where number the. Sum was, if we looked at the true sum, the number that you’d get, for example, 12 is too big to represent. And so when we think of that as a twos complement number, it becomes now a negative number. So that’s positive overflow.<br>将正数相加得到否定的结果。顺便说一下，如果你考虑这个加法，我们拿了7和5，就是12。这是12的位级表示。只是因为这现在是正弦位，我们认为那是-4，而不是正的12。这就是2的补码溢出的想法。你可以看到这里有两种不同的情况。一个是数字所在的地方。总和是，如果我们看看真正的总和，你得到的数字，例如12太大了，无法代表。所以当我们把它看作是一个二零补数时，它现在就变成了一个负数。所以这是正溢出。</p><p>发言人   12:33<br>Similarly, if we have two negative numbers and we add them together so that the sum is too small, too negative to represent, then those become positive numbers. That’s negative overflow. And you can see that in this picture, the same idea as before, except there’s three regions. This is the, and by the way, now you’ll see our numbers range between -8 and positive c, and the sum will also range between -8 and positive 7. But there’s these three regions. One is where everything’s fine, it’s within the representable range, the other is where the sum was so far toward the negative side that it becomes positive, or where it’s so high on the positive side that it becomes negative. And so part of data web, you’ll learn to understand these quite in quite precisely.<br>同样地，如果我们有两个负数，我们把它们相加，使得总和太小、太负而无法表示，那么它们就变成正数。这就是负面溢出。你可以看到这张图片和之前的想法一样，只是有三个区域。顺便说一句，现在你会看到我们的数字范围在-8和正c之间，总和也在-8和正7之间。但是有这三个地区。一种是一切都很好，在可表示的范围内，另一种是总和远远接近负值而变成正值，或者正值太高而变成负值。因此，作为数据网络的一部分，你将学会非常精确地理解这些。</p><p>发言人   13:44<br>But that’s the idea. And it’s a little bit counterintuitive to say. So somehow I can accept the idea that modular arithmetic for unsigned numbers, there’s some sort of mathematical beauty to modular arithmetic. And this just looks like kind of useless from a. Operational characteristic. But it’s the way it is. We’re stuck with it. And multiplication is basically the same idea. In fact, all the operations are basically the same idea.<br>但这就是我的想法。这样说有点违反直觉。因此，我可以接受这样的想法，即无符号数的模块化算术，具有某种数学美感。而这看起来只是有点没用。运营特点。但事情就是这样。我们被它卡住了。乘法基本上是相同的思想。事实上，所有的操作基本上都是相同的想法。</p><p>发言人   14:23<br>If you can’t represent it within the word size, you just take the lower w bits. So all this complicated notation here is just a way of saying, in principle, if you take two w bit numbers and multiply them together, you need the result may require as much as two times w bits to represent before addition. It’s w plus 1 multiplication. You actually have to double because you’re potentially squaring the largest number. And so again, we don’t want to just keep doubling our word size over and over again, we’ll run out of bits very quickly that way, and so we just truncate it at w bits and.<br>如果您无法在单词大小内表示它，则只需采用较低的w位。所以这里所有这些复杂的符号只是一种说法，原则上，如果你把两个w位数字相乘，你需要的结果可能需要两倍的w位才能表示出来。这是w加1乘。你实际上必须翻倍，因为你可能要平方最大的数字。所以再次强调，我们不想一遍又一遍地让我们的字数翻倍，这样我们很快就会用完位数，所以我们只需要将其截断为w位。</p><p>发言人   15:14<br>For the unsettling, it’s, again, modular arithmetic. It’s something that you can kind of understand and believe, but. And so again, let’s just do a few examples. And I won’t try workout. Multiplying in binary is like multiplying in decimal. You do a big table and it takes a long time. So I won’t try to do that. But let me just show a few examples.<br>令人不安的是，这是模块化算术。这是你可以理解和相信的事情，但是。再说一遍，让我们举几个例子。我不会尝试锻炼。二进制乘法就像十进制乘法。你做一张大桌子，需要很长时间。所以我不会尝试这样做。但让我举几个例子。</p><p>发言人   15:54<br>So if I multiply three times 5 is of course, equal to 15. And in an unsigned number, I can represent that. So, that’s OK. But if I multiply five times 5.<br>所以，如果我乘三乘5，当然等于15。在一个无符号的数字中，我可以表示它。所以，没关系。但是如果我乘五次5。</p><p>发言人   16:23<br>Then that would have a representation. If I were to think about it, as possibly as many as 8 b, it would have a representation.<br>那么就会有一个代表。如果我考虑一下，可能多达8个b，它将有一个代表性。</p><p>发言人   16:39<br>With an extra bit. And I’m going to throw this part away. And so I’d call that 9, which of course, is equal to 25 mod 16.<br>多一点。我要把这部分扔掉。所以我称之为9，当然，它等于25 mod 16。</p><p>发言人   16:56<br>And so that’s the general idea of it is regardless of whatever is in this upper part of the word, the product. I’m just going to discard that and only look at the lower one. And life gets a little more interesting with the two’s complement case. So let’s look at what that does. And the answer is even a little bit stranger in that you not only trunk throw away whatever high order bits happen to be there, but whatever bit gets left in this position will determine whether it’s a positive or a negative result, even though completely irrespective of the signs of the original two operands. So that can make you go all over the place.<br>这就是它的一般思想，无论这个词的上部是什么，产品。我只是打算放弃那个，只看下面的那个。随着两者的补充情况，生活变得更有趣了。让我们看看它的作用。答案甚至有点奇怪，因为你不仅扔掉了碰巧存在的任何高阶位，而且在这个位置留下的任何位都将决定它是正的还是负的结果，即使完全不考虑原始两个操作数的符号。这样可以让你走遍所有的地方。</p><p>发言人   18:03<br>So if we had five times 4 or 20. That would be represented. In this 8 b form.<br>如果我们有五个乘以4或20。这将被代表。在这个8 B形式中。</p><p>发言人   18:24<br>Like so. And we’d just call that four, right? Because we’re throwing this away. But if we did five times 5.<br>就像这样。我们就称它为四，对吧？因为我们要把这个扔掉。但是如果我们做了五次5。</p><p>发言人   18:40<br>As we saw before, that’s represented like this.<br>正如我们之前看到的，这就代表了这样。</p><p>发言人   18:51<br>And that? Now becomes, so we’re throwing away this and this becomes our sine bit. So the result is -8 plus 1 or -7. So you see, this is similar to an example we showed at the beginning of the first lecture, that you can have two positive numbers and multiply them and get a negative result because of the sort of quirks of this overflow question there.<br>那个呢？现在变成了，所以我们扔掉了这个，这变成了我们的正弦位。所以结果是-8加1或者-7。所以你看，这类似于我们在第一节课开始时展示的例子，你可以有两个正数，然后将它们相乘得到负面结果，因为这个溢出问题的怪癖。</p><p>发言人   19:26<br>Oh I’m just taking 25 and writing it in binary. Yeah, if you want to, you know, you start with the two numbers. I’m not going to do well. Actually, this one’s an easy one. There’s a trick for this. If you want to multiply a number by a power of two, we’re going to show that later. You just shift it left by two positions.<br>哦，我只是用二进制写25。是的，如果你想，你知道，你可以从这两个数字开始。我不会做得很好。实际上，这个很容易。这是有诀窍的。如果你想将一个数乘以2的幂，我们稍后会展示。你只需要将它向左移动两个位置。</p><p>发言人   19:56<br>So that one’s an easy one. Otherwise, you have to write out the table and sum all the results and all that stuff. I prefer to let computers do that.<br>所以这是一个容易的。否则，你必须写出表格并汇总所有结果和所有这些内容。我更喜欢让计算机来做这件事。</p><p>发言人   20:15<br>And again, the two complement stuff. One interesting feature is that it works for negative numbers too. If you do this trick of throwing away the high order bits, and you’ll have overflow cases like before because you’re throwing away information. The lower bits, if the number is representable, you’ll get the right result. So let me just demonstrate to that to you. So -3. But you remember this is equivalent to 13 as an unsigned number and. This is -2, which is equivalent to 14 as an unsigned number. So now if we multiply 13 times 14, you get 182. And that has a hex representation of B6.<br>再次，这两个补充的东西。一个有趣的特性是它也适用于负数。如果你使用这种丢弃高阶比特的技巧，就会出现像以前一样的溢出情况，因为你正在丢弃信息。在较低的位，如果数字是可表示的，你将得到正确的结果。让我向你们演示一下。所以-3。但你记得这相当于13作为一个无符号数。这是-2，相当于14作为一个无符号数。所以现在如果我们乘13乘14，你得到182。并且它的十六进制表示为b6。</p><p>发言人   21:30<br>And so just looking at the low order, 4 b are 0, 1, 1, 0 is 6. And indeed, that’s negative three times -2 is 6. So the point being, and I’m waving my hands here because I don’t want to go through all the details, but to complement multiplication also gives you, if you can do it using the exact same rules. And as you do for unsigned multiplication, same hardware, I should mention that there are instructions in the computer in ways that you can get the upper word of a multiplication 2. And those the bit patterns are different depending on whether it’s treated as two complement number versus unsigned different instructions for doing that computation, But 99% of the time or more, you just looking at this lower part of the product. And that’s the same whether it’s a tooth complement or an unsigned. And it handles negative numbers, positive, but it has these overflow characteristics.<br>所以仅仅看低阶，4 b是0，1，1，0是6。事实上，这是负数的三倍 – 2是6。所以重点是，我在这里挥手，因为我不想浏览所有的细节，但是如果你能使用完全相同的规则，补乘也会给你带来帮助。正如你对无符号乘法所做的那样，同样的硬件，我应该提到计算机中有一些指令，可以获得乘法2的上位单词。而这些位模式取决于它是否被视为两个补码数和无符号不同的指令来进行计算，但99% 以上的情况下，你只是看到乘积的这个下部。无论是牙齿补全还是无符号牙齿，都是一样的。它处理负数、正数，但它具有这些溢出特性。</p><p>发言人   22:45<br>So as I was talking about, there’s a trick we can do for multiplying by a power of two, which is just to shift the number to the left. And you’ll often see that when you have in your code, I want to multiply some number by 4. You’ll write in your C code. If you look at the assembly code, you’ll see that what the compiler generated just says. I’ll just shift it left by two. So in general, and you can see why this is true. By the way, if you think of the number. As the sum of the bits?<br>所以正如我所说的，我们可以做一个技巧来乘以2的幂，这只是将数字向左移动。你经常会看到，当你在代码中写代码时，我想把某个数字乘以4。你将用你的C代码编写。如果你查看汇编代码，你会发现编译器生成的代码只是说出来的。我会把它向左移动两点。总的来说，你可以明白为什么这是真的。顺便说一下，如果你想到数字。作为比特数的总和？</p><p>发言人   23:35<br>Where x sub I is the ith bit and x is the number it represents. If I shift everything left by two, what I’m effectively doing is increasing their weight by that number of positions. So let’s just shift by one. If I shift everything to the left by one.<br>其中，x sub I是第I个位，x是它代表的数字。如果我将所有东西左移两，我有效地做的是将它们的权重增加那么多个位置。那我们就转一个吧。如果我把所有东西向左移动一个。</p><p>发言人   24:02<br>Which we write like this in C 2, 2 less symbols. It’s like taking that sum, but now weighting the bits by 2 to the I plus one by one more. And of course, that’s equal to twice what the original sum was. And so we doubled the number. And that works. Even if you shift things so you lose some bits, they shift off to the left. All you’re doing is the way multiplication works anyhow, of truncating to W bit product.<br>我们这样用c2写，少了2个符号。这就像取那个总和，但现在将比特加权2到I加一加一。当然，这等于原始总和的两倍。所以我们将数字翻倍了。这行得通。即使你移动了一些东西，丢失了一些位，它们也会向左移动。你所做的只是乘法的工作方式，即截断为W位乘积。</p><p>发言人   24:48<br>You’ll see this, as I mentioned, quite often in compiled code, machine level code, that they’re doing shifts where you might expect them to be doing multiplications. And the reason for that is an optimization is historically, the multiplication instruction took a lot longer than a shift instruction, say one clock cycle to do a shift. And it used to be like 11, 1230 clock cycles to do a multiplication. Nowadays, like on computers, we use the shark machines, it only takes three clock cycles to do multiplication because they added a lot of hardware to do that. But three clock cycles is still more time than one. And so when you can get away with a shift, it’s generally a better idea. And the compiler has its own kind of judgment calls on when is it more efficient to substitute one operation for another?<br>正如我所提到的，在编译代码中，机器级别的代码中，你会经常看到这一点，它们正在进行移位，你可能期望它们进行乘法运算。而这样做的原因是从历史上看，乘法指令比移位指令花费了更长的时间，比如一个时钟周期来进行移位。它曾经需要大约11，1230个时钟周期来进行乘法运算。现在，就像在计算机上一样，我们使用鲨鱼机，只需要三个时钟周期就可以进行乘法，因为他们添加了很多硬件来实现这一点。但三个时钟周期仍然比一个时间更长。所以当你可以逃脱轮班时，通常是一个更好的主意。编译器有自己的判断要求，何时用一种操作代替另一种操作更有效？</p><p>发言人   25:53<br>Did I lose ground here?<br>我在这里失去了基础吗？</p><p>发言人   26:04<br>So the idea then, if we want to multiply something by two to the k, we just shift it left by k bit.<br>所以这个想法是，如果我们想将某物乘以二得到k，我们只需要将其向左移动k位。</p><p>发言人   26:21<br>It turns out that the same almost works for dividing by two as well, that if you want to divide something by a power of two, you can shift it right by in the same general idea. Only thing that becomes a little bit quirky is, well, what if the number you have is not actually divisible by that power of two?<br>事实证明，同样的方法几乎也适用于除以二，如果你想将某物除以二的幂，你可以按照同样的一般想法将其向右移动。唯一有点古怪的是，如果你拥有的数字实际上不能被2的幂整除呢？</p><p>发言人   26:52<br>So for example, if we had the number 0, 1. I want. I’m gonna use this.<br>例如，如果我们有数字0，1。我想要。我要用这个。</p><p>发言人   27:10<br>So that’s 6. So if we shift it right by one, we’ll get 0, 0, 1, 0. One, 1, thank you, which is 3. And that’s six divided by 2 is 3. If we shift that again. We’ll get one. But of course, you know that 3&#x2F;2 are 1.5. The rule on integer division is you round it down, round it towards 0, and so that goes to one. So this is what the unsigned case works fine. The signed case, which I don’t have a slide for.<br>那就是6。所以如果我们把它向右移动一，我们会得到0，0，1，0。1，1，谢谢，也就是3。6除以2就是3。如果我们再次转移。我们会得到一个。但是当然，你知道3&#x2F;2是1.5。整数除法的规则是你向下舍入，向0舍入，这样就得到1。所以这就是未签名案例运作良好的地方。签名的案子，我没有幻灯片。</p><p>发言人   28:07<br>It’s a little bit less pretty. Well, first of all, you notice if it’s a positive number, the shifting right is going to be the right thing, just as it is for unsigned. But let’s take a number that is.<br>它稍微不那么漂亮了。嗯，首先，你注意到如果它是一个正数，右移将是正确的事情，就像对无符号的情况一样。但让我们取一个数字。</p><p>发言人   28:29<br>Negative, so this is -6. Now, here’s where, remember I told you in the previous lecture, there’s two ways to do shifting. There’s logical shifting where you fill in with zeros, an arithmetic shifting where you fill in with ones. Guess where arithmetic shifting comes in this is it when you want to preserve the sine of a number while you’re dividing it by powers of 2. You want arithmetic shifts. So if we shift this by one, we’ll keep that sine bit and then copy the other ones over. So we just preserved this bit here and copied the other ones over. And this is -3. And so that’s good. But now if we shift again arithmetically. Well, get what?<br>这是负数，所以这是-6。现在，记住我在上一节课中告诉过你，这里有两种转移的方法。有逻辑移位，你用零填充，算术移位，你用一填充。猜猜算术移位的作用是什么？当你想保持一个数的正弦，同时将它除以2的幂时。你想要算术移位。所以如果我们将其移动一个，我们将保留那个正弦位，然后复制其他位。所以我们只是保留了这个位，并复制了其他的位。这是-3。这很好。但是现在如果我们再次算术转移。好吧，明白什么？</p><p>发言人   29:43<br>Nice too. I can see you guys need to know how to negate numbers, right? You don’t know that, so I’ll show you in a second. So here is a little bit problematic that we shifted. We want to divide by two, but the rule should be the same, that you should round toward 0. And what this is doing is it’s rounding toward minus infinity. It’s rounding toward a more negative number than the true thing. And so there’s a cute little trick that says, before you shift, before you divide by a power of two, before you do the shift, you should add a bias.<br>也不错。我明白你们需要知道如何否定数字，对吧？你不知道，所以我马上给你看。所以我们转移了一点问题。我们想要除以二，但规则应该是相同的，你应该四舍入到0。它所做的是向负无穷大四舍五入。它向一个比真实数字更负的四舍五入。所以有一个可爱的小技巧说，在你移动之前，在你除以2的幂之前，在你移动之前，你应该添加一个偏差。</p><p>发言人   30:34<br>Which, in this case, would just be one. And I’ll tell you where that comes from. And so if we add those numbers together, we’ll get 1, 1, 1, 0. And now when we do the shift on that, we’ll get 1, 1, 1, 1, and that’s -1. So there’s a trick.<br>在这种情况下，只有一个。我会告诉你这是从哪里来的。所以如果我们把这些数字相加，我们会得到1，1，1，0。现在当我们在上面进行转换时，我们会得到1，1，1，那就是-1。所以有一个小技巧。</p><p>发言人   30:58<br>And again, you’ll see the compiler doing this where you have in your code divide by 16, and it’ll add a bias. Then it will do a right shift instead of calling division. And by the way, division really, really is slow, even on a modern computer like what you have the shark machines, it takes 30 plus clock cycles. So anytime the compiler can avoid figure out a trick that does it with shifting and tweaking things around, it will.<br>再次，你会看到编译器在你的代码除以16的地方这样做，它会增加一个偏差。那么它将进行向右移动，而不是调用部门。顺便说一下，除法确实很慢，即使在像鲨鱼机器这样的现代计算机上，也需要30多个时钟周期。因此，只要编译器能够避免想出转移和调整事物的技巧，它就会做到。</p><p>发言人   31:30<br>So I realize I should tell you, there’s a couple ways you can.<br>所以我意识到我应该告诉你，有几种方法可以。</p><p>发言人   31:38<br>Negate a number that are handy to know if you ever have to do it in your head or on paper. And the standard way is what’s called complement and increment. So this is how do I go from x to minus x? So if I have a number. And I want to negate it, whether it’s currently a negative number or it’s a positive number. The same trick works. What I’ll do is complement it, meaning I’ll flip all of the bits. And then I’ll add one to that.<br>否定一个数字，它很方便知道你是否曾经在脑海中或在纸上做过。标准方式是所谓的补足和递增。这就是我如何从x到-x？如果我有一个号码。我想否定它，无论它是目前的负数还是正数。同样的把戏行得通。我要做的是补充它，意思是我会翻转所有的位。然后我会再添加一个。</p><p>发言人   32:21<br>And do the regular sum. And so this is 6. And this is -6. So if you ever have to do it by hand, that’s the way to do it, complement and increment. And it goes the other way. You’ll see if I complement this.<br>并做常规的总和。所以这是6。这是-6。所以，如果你必须手工完成，那就是方法，补充和增加。它是另一种方式。你会看到我是否补充了这个。</p><p>发言人   32:46<br>And I increment. It. Back to my previous number. So that’s a trick. It’s pretty much only useful when you do things on the blackboard or when you have to solve a problem in data web.<br>和I递增。它。回到我之前的号码。所以这是个小把戏。它几乎只有当你在黑板上做事情或者在数据网络中解决问题时才有用。</p><p>发言人   33:15<br>Anyways, this idea of of doing shifting to the right to do power of two division, actually, that’s the whole justification for arithmetic shifting in the first place, which by the way, and see, there’s no fixed requirement for how shifting works in C for signed numbers, for unsigned. It has to be a logical shift. Sine numbers, the C standard says there’s no fixed definition. The reality is, on our machines, most machines, just about every machine out there, when it’s a sine number, it’s two’s complement. And when you do a shift, it will be an arithmetic shift.<br>无论如何，这种向右移动以进行两除法的幂的想法实际上，这首先是算术移位的理由，顺便说一下，对于有符号的数字，对于无符号的数字，没有固定的要求。这必须是一个合乎逻辑的转变。正弦数字，C标准说没有固定的定义。现实情况是，在我们的机器上，大多数机器，几乎每台机器上，当它是正弦数时，它是2的补码。当你做一个移位时，它将是一个算术移位。</p><p>发言人   34:09<br>So getting back to then summarizing this integer arithmetic, you see that, first of all, whether it’s signed or unsigned, the addition or multiplication operations are the same, whether it’s an unsigned number or two’s comple. And it works, the negative stuff works out as long as you don’t have an overflow. And you can end up with an overflow, only one type of overflow for unsigned and two types for signed numbers. But it’s not like they just overflow and generate random numbers, a pattern to result what they are and how they can be interpreted.<br>所以回到总结这个整数算术，你会看到，首先，无论它是有符号的还是无符号的，加法或乘法操作都是相同的，无论它是无符号的数字还是2的整数。它会起作用，只要你没有溢出，负面的东西就会起作用。并且您最终可能会导致溢出，对于无符号数字只有一种类型的溢出，对于有符号数字只有两种类型。但它们并不只是溢出并生成随机数，而是一种模式来导致它们的存在以及如何解释它们。</p><p>发言人   35:03<br>So I talked about this a little bit last time and gave this example similar to this, but let me go over it a little bit more. One thing you might think of, wow, if this unsigned and signed stuff gets so murky, and we saw some funny examples last time, maybe we should just banished unsigned numbers from the universe and OAO L two’s complutum. And that’s exactly the rule that was adopted. For example, in Java, they said, is this too weird? Let’s just say every number is two’s comple The only trick they did was they put in a triple right shift. Means logical shift? This is Java, this is not C?<br>所以我上次谈了一点这个，并给出了与此类似的例子，但让我再详细介绍一下。有一件事你可能会想到，哇，如果这个无符号和有符号的东西变得如此模糊，我们上次看到了一些有趣的例子，也许我们应该把无符号的数字从宇宙中驱逐出去。这正是采用的规则。例如，在Java中，他们说，这太奇怪了吗？我们只能说每个数字都是2的comple，他们唯一的技巧就是进行了三个右移。这意味着逻辑转变？这是Java，这不是C？</p><p>发言人   36:04<br>Whereas the double is arithmetic.<br>而双精度是算术的。</p><p>发言人   36:17<br>Because they realize there’s a lot of cute little times when you want to play tricks with things and you need that logical right shift. So that’s actually one approach. Or other more modern languages and C are saying it’s okay to have signed and unsigned, but we don’t want them sort of mysteriously being cast back and forth in ways that the programmer might not recognize. And so you have to explicitly do a cast rather than implicitly. And I think that’s the better approach. But C, as I mentioned, does this implicit casting.<br>因为他们意识到，当你想玩弄事物时，有很多可爱的小时候，你需要逻辑上的右移。这实际上是一种方法。或者其他更现代的语言，C语言和C语言都说有签名和无签名是可以的，但我们不希望它们以程序员可能无法识别的方式神秘地来回转换。所以你必须明确地进行强制转换，而不是隐式地进行。我认为这是更好的方法。但是，正如我所提到的，C会进行隐式转换。</p><p>发言人   36:52<br>And so, as we saw for last time, what happens with this program when you run it? To count down through an array, do you remember? Well, I, if it’s unsigned, what will happen with this test? It always succeeds. So the thing will be in an infinite loop. Actually, what will happen is it will try to access, I will go down to 0, and then it will wrap around to become the largest possible ensign number, which is probably way out of bounds. And it will give a memory error, but it won’t do what’s supposed to be.<br>所以，正如我们上次看到的，当你运行这个程序时会发生什么？通过一个数组倒数，你还记得吗？好的，我，如果它是无符号的，这个测试会发生什么？它总是成功的。所以这个东西将会处于一个无限循环中。实际上，它会尝试访问，我将下降到0，然后它将环绕成为最大的可能的标志数字，这可能超出了界限。它会产生记忆错误，但它不会做应该做的事情。</p><p>发言人   37:40<br>And as I mentioned before, these things, there a lot of sneaky ways this problem can show up in ways you might never think of. So for example, the operator size of is defined to say how big a particular data type is, it’s a very useful operator. Its return value is what’s called a size underscore t, which is defined to be a long unsigned number. And so if we just throw in a. Constant like this. Then this subtraction we have AI is now int, but size of is unsigned. And so it will cast that to be unsigned implicitly. And when you compare it to 0, you’ll have the same problem as before.<br>正如我之前提到的，这些事情，这个问题可能会以你可能从未想过的方式出现。例如，运算符的大小被定义为特定数据类型的大小，这是一个非常有用的运算符。它的返回值称为大小下划线t，它被定义为一个长的无符号数字。所以如果我们只是投入一个。像这样不断。那么我们得到的这个减法现在是int，但size是无符号的。因此它会隐式地将其强制转换为无符号。当你将其与0进行比较时，你将遇到与之前相同的问题。</p><p>发言人   38:31<br>So just to show you that these things can sneak in very tricky ways. So one way to do that then is just don’t use unsigned like and make sure if this is.<br>所以只是为了告诉你，这些东西可以以非常棘手的方式偷偷溜走。因此，一种方法是不要使用未签名的像，并确保这是否是这样。</p><p>发言人   38:48<br>A possible unsigned number. You cast it to sign. You make sure that this is recognized and signed. But there’s another way that actually, at least there’s a fellow over at the Software Engineering Institute named Robert Secord who has written the books that are considered the. The gold standard for how to write secure code. He works for this organization called the Computer Emergency Response Team, which is out there tracking down bad things going on in computer security. And one of the things he and others have done is to try and come up with standards so that people who write programs well avoid some of the pitfalls that make their programs vulnerable to security of flaws to attack.<br>可能的无符号数字。你投它来签名。你要确保这被识别和签名。但实际上还有另一种方式，至少有一位名叫罗伯特·塞科德的软件工程研究所的研究员写了被认为是最重要的书。如何编写安全代码的黄金标准。他在一个名为计算机应急响应团队的组织工作，该团队正在追踪计算机安全方面的不良事件。他和其他人所做的事情之一就是尝试制定标准，以便编写程序的人能够避免一些使他们的程序容易受到安全漏洞攻击的陷阱。</p><p>发言人   39:43<br>And so his recommended technique is when I first saw this, it was so counterintuitive to me, it hardly made sense, right? So you start, and again, this is all unsigned arithmetic, So I’m starting to count down, and my test is when I is less than count. So here’s the thing, I started off smaller than count, and it’s only being decremented. So when would this test ever fail? When it overflows, when it wraps around, when I goes from 0 and counts down to what would now be u max, this test will fail, which is exactly when you want it to stop.<br>所以他推荐的技巧是，当我第一次看到这个时，它对我来说是如此违反直觉，几乎没有感知，对吗？所以你开始，再一次，这都是无符号算术，所以我开始倒计时，我的测试是当我小于计数时。所以事情是这样的，我一开始比计数小，它只是被减少了。那么，这个测试什么时候会失败呢？当它溢出，当它包裹时，当I从0计数到现在的最大值时，这个测试将失败，这正是你想要它停止的时候。</p><p>发言人   40:31<br>And his observation is in c with sine numbers. There’s no guarantee on what happens with overflowing. As I said, most people just assume it’s going to be too’s compliment. But if you really want to be careful, you shouldn’t assume anything outside of the C standard. And if you’re trying to write secure code, it’s probably a good idea to be cautious. Be conservative.<br>他的观察结果是在c和正弦数字之间。无法保证溢出会发生什么。正如我所说，大多数人只是假设这将是对太的赞美。但如果你真的想小心，你不应该假设C标准之外的任何事情。如果你试图编写安全的代码，保持谨慎可能是个好主意。保守一点。</p><p>发言人   40:55<br>On the other hand, the C standard guarantees that unsigned arithmetic will be modular arithmetic. So it guarantees that if you subtract 1 from 0, you’ll get the largest number that could be represented. So it will be OK. And in fact, he recommends, instead of using unsigned, which is on our machines, just a 32 b value that you call it a size t, which is a 64 b value. And write your code the way that I showed you. So I’ve actually started doing this. And once you kind of get used to it, it’s an okay way to write code, but it’s very strange looking initially. One thing I’ll point out is.<br>另一方面，C标准保证无符号算术将是模算术。因此，它保证了如果你从0中减去1，你将得到可以表示的最大数字。所以会没事的。实际上，他建议不要使用我们机器上的无符号，而只使用32 b的值，你称之为大小t，这是64 b的值。并以我展示的方式编写您的代码。所以我实际上已经开始这样做了。一旦你习惯了它，这是编写代码的一种不错的方式，但一开始看起来很奇怪。我要指出的一件事是。</p><p>发言人   41:47<br>What would happen if count were a sine number, an int, and it? Was less than 0? What would happen here? So I less than count what would happen.<br>如果count是一个正弦数，一个int数，它会发生什么？小于0？这里会发生什么？所以我数不清会发生什么。</p><p>发言人   42:14<br>And so it become a very large positive number. And this test would almost certainly succeed. So you have the same. This code doesn’t avoid the pitfall, it just shifts it to saying you better make sure you don’t test for this case beforehand before you get into it.<br>因此它成为一个非常大的正数。这个测试几乎肯定会成功。所以你有相同的。这段代码并不能避免这个陷阱，它只是将其转移到说你最好确保在进入这个案例之前不要事先测试它。</p><p>发言人   42:38<br>I think part of it is the observation that, man, if you want to be careful and write code, that that is guaranteed correct no matter what implementation goes on, as long as it’s within the C standard, It’s pretty tricky business. A question up there.<br>我认为其中的一部分是观察到，如果你想小心编写代码，那么无论执行什么实现，只要它在C标准内，都是相当棘手的业务。这里有一个问题。</p><p>发言人   43:02<br>Yes, which is unfortunate. So yes, that’s exactly the rule that it’s implicitly, silently, the C compiler doesn’t give any warnings.<br>是的，这很不幸。所以是的，这正是规则，它是隐式的，默默地，C编译器不发出任何警告。</p><p>发言人   43:14<br>You’ll never know. You cast it to unsigned. And as these examples show, when you stare at that code and you think about it, it’s really easy to have bugs that you just, you can look at it a thousand times and not realize that it’s a bug. It’s a very, and there’s examples, There are examples in the book of security flaws in sort of very important library software due to this problem exactly. So part of the reason we teach in the course is just so you appreciate that this is a quirk in this. And see that again, 99% of the time you’ll never even, it won’t bother you at all. But there will be some oddball cases that you can get in trouble with. So the other that you’ll find unsigned representation useful is, first of all, when you’re doing modular arithmetic, which is, for example, the way most encryption algorithms work, or when you’re using the bits not to represent numbers, but to represent sets the way I described it before, then you don’t’s easiest to just think of that as unsigned numbers.<br>你永远不会知道。你把它转换为未签名的。正如这些例子所展示的，当你盯着代码思考时，很容易出现bug，你可以看上几千次而没有意识到这是一个bug。这是一个非常，有例子，在书中有一些非常重要的图书馆软件安全漏洞的例子，正是由于这个问题。所以我们在这门课程中教授的部分原因只是为了让你欣赏这是其中的一个怪癖。再说一遍，99% 的时间你永远不会，它根本不会打扰你。但是也会有一些奇怪的情况，你可能会惹上麻烦。因此，你会发现无符号表示有用的另一个方面是，首先，当你在进行模算术时，例如，大多数加密算法的工作方式，或者当你使用比特不是代表数字，而是代表我之前描述的集合时，那么你最不容易把它想成无符号数字。</p><p>发言人   44:47<br>Okay, so the final thing to talk about today is some of the low level of representations of numbers within memory. And the main point is when you are running a program on a computer. From the programming perspective, even as an assembly level programmer, not just as AC programmer, in your mind, the memory is just this big array of bytes that’s numbered from 0 up to some maximum number. So for example, in the machines, we’re using the 64 b machines, an address is represented in 64 b. But in fact, the maximum address you’re allowed to use in current machines is 47 b.<br>好的，今天要讨论的最后一件事是记忆中数字的一些低水平表示。重点是当你在计算机上运行程序时。从编程的角度来看，即使是汇编级程序员，而不仅仅是交流程序员，在你的脑海中，内存只是一个大的字节数组，从0到某个最大数字编号。例如，在机器中，我们使用的是64 b机器，地址用64 b表示。但实际上，您在当前机器中允许使用的最大地址是47 b。</p><p>发言人   45:43<br>Two to the 47th is still a pretty big number. So that’s more memory than anyone’s able to buy right now anyhow. And so it’s a reasonable restriction. But the point is that logically, your program thinks that it has an array of that many bytes.<br>2到47号仍然是一个相当大的数字。因此，无论如何，这比任何人现在都能够购买的更多的记忆。所以这是一个合理的限制。但重点是，从逻辑上讲，你的程序认为它有一个这么多字节的数组。</p><p>发言人   46:01<br>Let’s try and figure out how big two to the 40 sevenths is. Anyone know it off the top of their head? So there’s a trick if you want to get an approximate idea, which is to say that two to the 10th, which is 110 24, is approximately equal to 10 to the third.<br>让我们试着弄清楚两个到40的七分之一有多大。有人知道它的头顶吗？所以如果你想要得到一个近似的想法，有一个技巧，也就是说2到10，也就是110 24，大约等于3的10。</p><p>发言人   46:31<br>You say, well, that’s really helpful. What it means is that 10 b worth of number is about the same as 3 decimal digits. So for example, to the. 20th? Is around 10 to the 6th, 2 to the 30th. It’s around 10 to the 9th, 2 to the 40th, around 10 to the 12th. And so that would tell you that two to the 48, 47th is around 128 times 10 to the 12th, which is 128 TB, right, Tara, 10 to the twelf.<br>你说，嗯，这真的很有帮助。它的意思是10 b的数字与3位十进制数字大致相同。例如，对于。20号？大约是10到6号，2到30号。大约是10到9号，2到40号，大约是10到12号。所以这就告诉你，2的48次方，47次方大约是128乘以10的12，也就是128 TB，对吧，塔拉，10的12次方。</p><p>发言人   47:26<br>So if you just want to say, get a quick figure for, and of course, these are approximations.<br>所以如果你只想说，得到一个快速的数字，当然，这些都是近似值。</p><p>发言人   47:33<br>But if you just want to get a quick handle on how big a number, what range of values can I represent with so many bits of it, this is a really easy trick to do that. So the point is, 128 TB, it’s a lot you can buy disk drives, a couple of disk drives will do that for you. You couldn’t buy enough DRAM on a normal budget to get that kind of memory. So that’s the current range of values. But logically, when you run a program, it thinks that it has that possible range. Now it doesn’t really, and in fact, what happens is that the operating system only allows certain regions within that memory to be referenced and other regions, if you try to access them, it will create a, it will a signal, an error, what they call a segmentation fault. But logically, at least, it’s as if you have this big array of bytes Now, in reality, and we’ll go into this when we talk about how the memory system works and virtual memory.<br>但是如果你只是想快速掌握一个数字的大小，我能用这么多位表示什么范围的值，这是一个非常简单的技巧。所以重点是，128 TB，你可以购买很多磁盘驱动器，几个磁盘驱动器就可以为你做到这一点。你无法以正常预算购买足够的DRAM来获得那种内存。这就是当前的值范围。但从逻辑上讲，当你运行一个程序时，它认为它有可能的范围。现在它并不是真的，事实上，发生的情况是操作系统只允许引用该内存中的某些区域，而其他区域，如果您尝试访问它们，它将创建一个信号，一个错误，他们称之为段故障。但从逻辑上讲，至少，就好像你现在有这么大的字节数组，实际上，当我们谈论内存系统和虚拟内存如何工作时，我们会深入探讨这个问题。</p><p>发言人   48:44<br>There’s this very complex combination of hardware and software. It gives the program this image of a very large, what you call flat space, just a big array of bytes, when in reality, it’s shuffling between different regions of your memory and even between your memory and your disk drive on your computer to make it implement this particular. Idea that you have this big array of bytes. And that’s all handled, as I said, by the operating system, by the computer hardware. And it’s largely invisible even to the machine level programmer, even people writing assembly code.<br>有一个非常复杂的硬件和软件组合。它给程序提供了一个非常大的图像，你称之为平坦空间，只是一个大的字节数组，而实际上，它正在你内存的不同区域之间，甚至在你的内存和计算机上的磁盘驱动器之间进行洗牌，以使其实现这个特定的功能。你有这么大的字节数组的想法。正如我所说，这一切都由操作系统、计算机硬件来处理。而且即使对于机器级程序员，甚至编写汇编代码的人来说，它也基本上是不可见的。</p><p>发言人   49:32<br>You’ll often hear the term word size and it can get very conf confusing nowadays because there’s no really fixed idea of what a word size is. But roughly speaking, the word size should be whatever the largest number is or the range, that sort of. Signifies how big a pointer is in this language? Or hardware wise, the largest sort of chunk of hardware for which there’s standard support for storing it for arithmetic operations and so forth. So when we say it’s a 64 b machine, what we mean is that regular and routinely manipulates 64 b values on arithmetic operations and also has pointers. The values of addresses are 64 b, even if for right now only 47 of those bits are usable, it’s still considered a 64 b machine. One thing that’s strange is in one of the features of. Of machines such as we have?<br>你经常会听到单词大小这个术语，现在它可能会变得非常混乱，因为对于单词大小并没有真正固定的概念。但粗略地说，单词大小应该是最大的数字或范围，那种类型。表示指针在这种语言中有多大？或硬件方面，最大的硬件块，有标准支持存储它以进行算术运算等。所以当我们说它是一台64 b的机器时，我们的意思是常规和常规地在算术运算中操作64 b的值，并且还有指针。地址的值是64 b，即使目前只有47位可用，它仍然被认为是64 b的机器。有一件事很奇怪，那就是它的一个特征。像我们这样的机器？</p><p>发言人   50:51<br>Is that if I compile a program using a GCC, is the standard compiler I can specify either I want it to be 64 b code or 32 b code as a flag? And it will actually generate two different kinds of object code as a result. And we’ll talk about these later. But for right now, the point is the hardware itself doesn’t necessarily define what the word size is. It’s a combination of the hardware and the compiler that determines what is the word size being used in this particular program. And that code can be run on. The point is that 64 b machines such as we have and most machines are nowadays, can in sort of a backward compatibility style, also execute 32 b code. And as we also saw, one of the other features is, even though it’s a 64 b word size, the data type int, without any other qualifiers to it, is just 32 b.<br>如果我使用GCC编译程序，标准编译器是否可以指定我希望它是64 b代码或32 b代码作为标志？它实际上会生成两种不同类型的目标代码。我们稍后再讨论这些。但就目前而言，关键是硬件本身并不一定定义单词大小。它是硬件和编译器的组合，确定这个特定程序中使用的单词大小。并且这些代码可以运行。关键是，像我们现在拥有的64 b机器一样，大多数机器都可以以一种向后兼容的方式执行32 b代码。正如我们所看到的，另一个特性是，即使它的字数大小为64 b，但没有任何其他限定符的数据类型int只有32 b。</p><p>发言人   52:07<br>There’s sort of this mixture of how big things are. So when people just say word or word size, and let’s say give a precise definition, that’s not a very meaningful term. And we’ll sort of throw it around when we mean sort of a generic chunk of bits without trying to assume that it has a particular number of bits to it.<br>事情有多大有点混合。所以当人们只说出单词或单词大小，假设给出一个精确的定义时，这并不是一个非常有意义的术语。当我们指的是一种通用的位块，而没有试图假设它有特定数量的位时，我们会把它扔掉。</p><p>发言人   52:39<br>Yes, so one of the things is if we ever get to 64 b words, it will be 16 PB, 18 PB, depending on how you define when those numbers get big. The error due to this approximation gets more significant. But something times 10 to the 15th bytes. But right now we can only get to 128 times 10 to the 12th.<br>是的，所以其中一件事是，如果我们达到64 b的话，它将是16 PB，18 PB，这取决于你如何定义这些数字变得很大的时候。由于这种近似而产生的误差变得更加显著。但是乘以10的第15个字节。但是现在我们只能得到128乘10的12次方。</p><p>发言人   53:15<br>So anyways, the idea that the memory itself is a series of bytes, but we can group those into blocks of words of different word sizes. And the way we do that is usually by assuming that the address of the word is the lowest valued address in it. We also will generally try to align these so that, for example, a 32 b word would be a line. So its first byte, its lowest byte, has all zeros in the first.<br>无论如何，内存本身是一系列字节的想法，但我们可以将它们分组为不同单词大小的单词块。我们通常的做法是假设单词的地址是其中价值最低的地址。我们通常也会尝试对它们进行对齐，例如，一个32 b的单词将是一行。因此它的第一个字节，它的最低字节，在第一个全部为零。</p><p>发言人   54:01<br>In the first 5 b positions, no, 30 two-women, sorry, the lowest 2 B. So as this example shows, the address is 0, 4, 8, and 12. They should have really written this in hex and said it’s C, I guess these are all in decimal anyhow. So yeah, these are decimal numbers, so 0, 4, 8, 12. So you see these are in multiples of 4 b boundaries. And similarly, the 64 b words are in multiples of 8, and those are known as aligned words. And we’ll generally, we’ll see that the compiler works pretty hard to keep things aligned because the hardware runs more efficiently that way. But the main point is that we can just take as many bytes as we want and collect them together and call it a word for whatever word size we need.<br>在前5个b的位置中，不，30个是两个女人，抱歉，最低的2个B。正如这个例子所示，地址是0、4、8和12。他们应该用十六进制写这个，并说它是C，我想这些都是十进制的。是的，这些是十进制数字，所以0、4、8、12。所以你会看到这些是以4 b边界的倍数为基础的。类似地，64 b的单词是8的倍数，这些被称为对齐单词。通常情况下，我们会看到编译器会非常努力地保持一致，因为这样硬件会更高效地运行。但主要的一点是，我们可以随心所欲地获取尽可能多的字节，并将它们收集在一起，然后根据我们需要的单词大小来称呼它。</p><p>发言人   55:01<br>I think we saw a variant of this table before, but this is the machines we’ll be working on. The standard int is still only 32 b, but if we qualify something as being wrong, then it will be 64 b. And we’ll tend to do that these two different floating point representations that we’ll talk about. And then the main feature of a 64 b machine is it has an 8 by or 64 b pointer as compared to 32.<br>我想我们之前见过这个表格的变体，但这是我们将要研究的机器。标准的int仍然只有32 b，但如果我们将某些东西限定为错误，那么它将是64 b。我们倾向于将这两种不同的浮点表示形式进行讨论。然后64 b机器的主要特点是它具有8 by或64 b指针，而32则不同。</p><p>发言人   55:34<br>Now, there’s one other kind of detail that says, okay, so if a word has multiple bytes in it, what order should those bytes be? Should it be? And there’s two basic ways this could go. One is that you put the bytes in what’s known as little Indian order, meaning that the first byte in the word is the least significant byte. And then the next, and then the next. And the final byte in the word is the most significant. Or you can flip that around. And those are called Little Indian and Big Indian.<br>现在，还有另一种细节说明，好的，如果一个单词有多个字节，这些字节应该是什么顺序？应该吗？有两种基本的方法可以实现。一种是你以所谓的小印度顺序放入字节，这意味着单词中的第一个字节是最低有效字节。然后是下一个，然后是下一个。并且单词中的最后一个字节是最重要的。或者你可以把它翻转过来。这些被称为小印度人和大印度人。</p><p>发言人   56:13<br>The sort of terms for that which comes from? English book called Gulliver’s Travels, which didn’t anticipate computers at all. But it’s an interesting story of how that comes about. So out there in the world, you’ll find both types of machines, big Indian and little Indian machines. It turns out that increasingly it’s getting hard to find big Indian machines. So literally all of x 86 is little Indian.<br>这种术语的来源是什么？英语书叫做《格列佛游记》，它根本没有预料到计算机。但这是一个有趣的故事，讲述了这是如何发生的。所以在世界上，你会发现两种类型的机器，大型印度机器和小型印度机器。事实证明，越来越难找到大型的印度机器了。所以字面上所有的x86都是小印度。</p><p>发言人   56:45<br>And it turns out Arm processors like what you have in almost every cell phone here is an Arm processor. And the hardware in those can actually be configured to run either way, big Indian or little. But when you’re running it on any of the standard operating systems that run on Arm processors. Then it’s running little Indian. So there used to be a brand called Sun Microsystems, and they were fairly common on campus and then back the Macintosh, before they were x 86 processors, they ran one called the Power PC, and that was a big Indian machine.<br>事实证明，几乎每部手机中都有Arm处理器。这些设备中的硬件实际上可以配置为运行任何一种方式，大印度或小印度。但是当你在任何在Arm处理器上运行的标准操作系统上运行它时。然后它正在运行小印度。所以曾经有一个品牌叫做Sun Microsystems，它们在校园里相当普遍，然后在Macintosh上，在x86处理器之前，他们运行一个叫做Power PC的机器，那是一个巨大的印度机器。</p><p>发言人   57:30<br>But those are long in the distant past. The internet’s about the only place out there when you send packets over the internet and you want to send 32 b words, they’re actually sent in big Indian order. And so at the network interface, you have to translate between those two.<br>但这些都在遥远的过去很久了。当你通过互联网发送数据包并且想要发送32个字时，互联网大概是唯一的地方，它们实际上是按照印度的大订单发送的。因此，在网络接口上，您必须在这两者之间进行转换。</p><p>发言人   57:51<br>So again, just to illustrate what I mean by this is think of a byte value, 4 B value like this. And remember that the way we write numbers is we put the most significant to the left and the least significant to the right. And so now with big Indian, instead of the intuitive one from that perspective, in that the bytes, if you write the words in memory from the smallest address up to the highest, the big Indian will sort of map to what you see, whereas the little Indian will look confusing. But you say 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, because 6, 7 is actually the least significant byte here. And so that comes first in little Indian order.<br>所以，再一次，为了说明我的意思，我认为这是一个字节值，像这样的4 B值。记住，我们书写数字的方式是将最重要的放在左边，最不重要的放在右边。所以现在有了大印度，而不是从那个角度来看直观的，在字节中，如果你从最小的地址到最高地址写入内存中的单词，大印度会有点映射到你看到的地方，而小印度会看起来很混乱。但是你说0，1，2，3，4，5，6，7，因为6，7实际上是这里最不重要的字节。所以这在小印度顺序中是第一位的。</p><p>发言人   58:46<br>And so it used to be people would get impassionate arguments about this. That’s sort of in the distant past. But, and people saying, you know. And the main feature in sort of argument of big Indianness is this feature here.<br>所以以前人们会对此进行无情的争论。这有点像是遥远的过去。但是，人们说，你知道的。而大印度性争论的主要特征就是这里的这个特征。</p><p>发言人   59:08<br>When you look at it, it’s easier to write down, but computers don’t really care. They’re happy either way. And so they just want one convention or another.<br>当你看着它时，写下来更容易，但计算机并不在乎。不管怎样，他们都很高兴。所以他们只想要一个或另一个约定。</p><p>发言人   59:17<br>And like I said, some hardware is can actually be by a sort of flag to flip it from being big Indian to little Indian. But the reality is most of the machines you will encounter, you’ll encounter little Indian machines nowadays. But just to give you an example, here’s some results that I got from actual machines. There used to be some machines around.<br>就像我说的，一些硬件实际上可以通过一种旗帜将其从大印度人转变为小印度人。但现实是，你会遇到的大多数机器，现在你会遇到一些小型印度机器。但只是为了给你一个例子，这里是我从实际机器上得到的一些结果。过去周围有一些机器。</p><p>发言人   59:40<br>So back in the old days, I could run this, I don’t even know where to get a big Indian machine anymore. So these are sort of a legacy, a result. But you’ll see the main feature is between a little Indian and a big Indian machine. When you have an integer, the bytes get flipped around so that the least significant byte comes first in a little Indian machine and last in a big Indian machine. And that’s true with negative numbers as well, that you’ll get the sine bits first. In a big Indian machine along, you’ll see that.<br>所以回到过去，我可以运行这个，我甚至不知道在哪里可以买到一个大的印度机器了。所以这些都是一种遗产，一种结果。但你会看到主要特点是介于一个小印度机器和一个大印度机器之间。当你有一个整数时，字节会被翻转，使得最低有效字节在小型印度机中首先出现，在大型印度机中最后。对于负数也是如此，你首先会得到正弦位。在印度的大型机器中，你会看到。</p><p>发言人   01:00:25<br>The only difference between a 32 b machine and a 64 b machine is you have more zeros or more ones depending on whether it’s a positive or negative number. And again, a sun. And if I had access to a 64 b machine, sun is now manufactured by a company called Oracle. So in principle, I could go get one of these machines and run this experiment. But it’s really not a very interesting experiment, so I won’t bother. So in principle, I could try it on a 64 b Oracle machine and show you something different.<br>32 b机器和64 b机器之间唯一的区别是你有更多的零或更多的一，这取决于它是正数还是负数。再说一次，太阳。如果我有机会使用64 b机器，那么sun现在由一家名为Oracle的公司制造。所以原则上，我可以去拿一台这样的机器来进行这个实验。但这真的不是一个非常有趣的实验，所以我不会打扰。所以原则上，我可以在64 b的Oracle机器上尝试一下，并向您展示一些不同的东西。</p><p>发言人   01:01:07<br>So one thing that kind of a useful tool, and the book goes through some examples of this, is a little program that will take a series of bytes starting at some position start and do it for however many bytes you request, and just print out in hex format the two hex digits that represent that byte value. And here, this term pointer. I’m using an unsigned care as a pointer type, sort of generic pointer type.<br>所以有一件有用的工具，这本书介绍了一些例子，就是一个小程序，它将获取从某个位置开始的一系列字节，并为您请求的字节数执行，并以十六进制格式打印出代表该字节值的两个十六进制数字。在这里，这个术语指针。我正在使用未签名的护理作为指针类型，有点像通用的指针类型。</p><p>发言人   01:01:51<br>And so again, if I run this on a x 86 machine. And I’m also, by the way, printing out the actual address that this character is stored at to. And so you’ll see that there’s these addresses with a lot of 7 F’s. What that means is it’s in the upper end of this 47 b address space. If you work it through 7 is three ones then. Enough hex digits here to correspond to. So there’s 11 hex digits beyond the 7. And you’ll see that these addresses are at successive bytes BCB, DBE, BF, and the values are 6 D3 b 0 0 0 0. This is the least significant byte. And these are the successive bytes.<br>再次强调，如果我在x86机器上运行这个。顺便说一下，我还在打印出这个字符存储在到的实际地址。所以你会看到这些地址有很多7个F。这意味着它位于这个47 b地址空间的上端。如果你通过7来工作，那么就是三个一。这里有足够的十六进制数字来对应。所以在7之外有11个十六进制数字。你会看到这些地址是连续的字节BCB，DBE，BF，并且值是6 D3 b 0。这是最低有效字节。这些是连续的字节。</p><p>发言人   01:02:52<br>And similarly, I can use this to examine pointers of various sorts. And I can examine different values and just get their low level byte representations. And so I did this back when I could get to a sun machine, had one way of representing a pointer.<br>同样地，我可以用它来检查各种指针。我可以检查不同的值并获取它们的低级字节表示。所以当我能够到达一台太阳机时，我就这样做了，有一种表示指针的方式。</p><p>发言人   01:03:12<br>And the main point is even across machines, whether it’s byte ordering or whatever, you’ll get different values for pointers. There’s no guarantee that when you load a program into one machine and run it, that it will use the same addresses as that same programming running on a different machine, even if actually they’re identical hardware and operating system. There can be variation because pointers, you can’t directly copy a pointer from one machine to another.<br>而且主要的一点是即使在机器上，无论是字节排序还是其他什么，你都会得到不同的指针值。不能保证当你将一个程序加载到一台机器上并运行它时，它将使用与在另一台机器上运行的相同程序相同的地址，即使它们实际上是相同的硬件和操作系统。可能会有变化，因为指针，你不能直接将指针从一台机器复制到另一台机器。</p><p>发言人   01:03:47<br>One thing about also is regardless of byte ordering, the ordering of of characters is the same. And so a string and C is always represented by a series of bytes where the final byte is 0 null, called null terminated, and the individual bytes correspond to the character codes for that number. And these character codes are just sometimes called Ascii format, which is a little bit old fashioned. By the way. There’s more modern character codes that can represent non-engine alphabets, but the C standard is still back in the days of only supporting the Ascii format question.<br>还有一点是，无论字节排序如何，字符的排序都是相同的。因此，字符串和C总是由一系列字节表示，其中最后一个字节为0空，称为空终止，各个字节对应于该数字的字符代码。而这些字符代码有时被称为Ascii格式，这有点过时。顺便说一下。有更现代的字符代码可以表示非引擎字母，但C标准仍然回到了只支持Ascii格式问题的时代。</p><p>发言人   01:04:54<br>Yes, so this should have been.<br>是的，所以这应该是。</p><p>发言人   01:05:02<br>Well, no, this is good. So I’m casting, I want to show the 4 B size event because this is an int. I’m representing the pointer. Let’s see the code where it’s printing the pointer. All this notation percent p is the directive to say print out a pointer. And percent x is the directive to print out a He representation. So it’s printing out both the address, the starting position of that particular byte. And the value of that byte has two different things. Does that answer your question?<br>好吧，不，这很好。所以我正在铸造，我想展示4 B大小的事件，因为这是一个整数。我代表的是指针。让我们看看它打印指针的代码。所有这些符号百分比p是指示打印出指针的指令。百分比x是打印出表示的指令。所以它打印出地址，即该特定字节的开始位置。并且该字节的值有两个不同的东西。这回答了你的问题吗？</p><p>发言人   01:05:56<br>But remember, show bytes? Is being given a pointer and a length? And so, and what it’s saying is starting at that address, print out the next series of bytes for me. How many bytes I ask for? And in this case I’m creating a pointer to this integer, but I want to show the bytes in that integer, the 4 B that make up that integer. And that’s why I’m giving the number 4 here instead of 8 is.<br>但是记住，显示字节？被给予一个指针和一个长度？所以，它所说的是从该地址开始，为我打印出下一系列字节。我要多少字节？在这种情况下，我正在创建一个指向该整数的指针，但我想显示该整数中的字节，即构成该整数的4 B。这就是为什么我在这里给出的数字是4而不是8。</p><p>发言人   01:06:37<br>Yes, it will be. And that’s fine because in this code I’m using the percent P directive to designate how to print out the pointer. And that will print it as many bytes as it takes for that particular machine that it’s running on. So percent p is actually a very handy directive if you have to print addresses, like for debugging purposes or something, because it will automatically adapt to whatever machine it’s running on question. Well I’ve defined it to be an unsigned care here. So type De is a way to introduce a name for some data type, right? And so I’ve just declared a pointer pointer to refer to an unsigned care.<br>是的，会有的。这很好，因为在这段代码中，我使用百分比P指令来指定如何打印出指针。这将打印它所需要的字节数，因为它正在运行的特定机器上。因此，如果您需要打印地址 (例如用于调试或其他目的)，百分号p实际上是一个非常方便的指令，因为它会自动适应正在运行的任何机器。我在这里将其定义为未签字的护理。所以De类型是为某些数据类型引入名称的一种方式，对吗？所以我刚刚声明了一个指针来引用未签名的护理。</p><p>发言人   01:07:30<br>If you did avoid star, it would not be happy with this reference here, right? You can’t reference a Vo star is just a way to pass around a generic pointer, but you can’t actually reference that element. So what I’m basically doing is saying this reference is treat it like an array, treat my series of bytes as an array, and print out each of the bytes in that array. And so here where I’m a is a number. And I’m taking the address of that integer and casting it to be an unsigned care star. So sort of a slightly generic pointer, but not quite as generic as a void star, and then printing it out.<br>如果你确实避免了star，这里的引用就不会让你满意了，对吧？你不能引用Vo星号只是传递通用指针的一种方式，但你实际上不能引用该元素。所以我基本上要做的是说这个引用将其视为数组，将我的一系列字节视为数组，并打印出该数组中的每个字节。所以在这里，我是一个数字。并且我正在获取该整数的地址并将其转换为未签名的关心星。有点像一个稍微通用的指针，但不像空星那么通用，然后打印出来。</p><p>发言人   01:08:28<br>These are good questions, by the way. OK, so the point being that strings are just strings. And that’s the same from one machine to the next.<br>顺便说一下，这些问题很好。好的，关键是字符串只是字符串。从一台机器到另一台机器也是如此。</p><p>发言人   01:08:43<br>Okay, let’s finish up today with some puzzles. And these have this annoying way of showing up on exams. So it’s worth being able to do these kind of things. And you’ll also notice I cleverly did not include the answers in the slides.<br>好的，让我们以一些谜题结束今天的比赛。这些在考试中出现的方式很烦人。所以能够做这些事情是值得的。你也会注意到，我巧妙地没有在幻灯片中包含答案。</p><p>发言人   01:09:05<br>So you can’t just peek ahead and figure out what the Nss are. So let’s just go through them. But I actually worked them out to make sure I have the Nss right. So, and basically, these are sort of statements that you want to say, these are either always true, and maybe there’s some logic behind why it’s always true or it’s possibly false. And you have to give some example that would make that false. So let’s go through these as many as we have time for and see where we get to.<br>所以你不能只是往前看，然后弄清楚Nss是什么。所以让我们通过它们。但我实际上已经解决了这些问题，以确保我的Nss是正确的。所以，基本上，这些是你想说的陈述，这些要么总是正确的，也许有一些逻辑为什么它总是正确的，或者它可能是错误的。你必须给出一些例子来证明这是错误的。所以，让我们尽可能地浏览这些，看看我们能走到哪里。</p><p>发言人   01:09:36<br>So if I take x and I double it, multiply it by two, if x were negative, am I guaranteed that 2x will be negative? So by the way, one general way to find counter example ins is to try t min. It’s a really good one. And that works here. If I take TN, which is 1 and a bunch of zeros, I double it. It’s like shifting it, but left, and it will become what, 0? And so again, assume that x is at any negative number and uux. Is issed I’m sorry, any two’s complement number and uux is what happens if I cast it to be unsigned? So is uux always greater than or equal to 0, yeah?<br>所以，如果我取x，我把它加倍，乘以二，如果x是负的，我可以保证2x是负的吗？所以顺便说一下，找到反例的一种一般方法是尝试t min。这是一个非常好的。这在这里是有效的。如果我取TN，它是1和一堆零，我会加倍它。这就像转移它，但是离开了，它会变成什么，0？所以再次假设x是任何负数和uux。很抱歉，任何两个的补码数和uux是如果我将其转换为无符号会发生什么？所以uux总是大于或等于0，是吗？</p><p>发言人   01:10:30<br>It is slightly more obscure. If I take x and I mask off, 7, you remember is the bit pattern 1, 1, 1. So if I mask off all but the lowest 3 b, and I find that those are all ones. I’m already giving you the answer here, and then I shift it left by 30 positions. What can I say about the result?<br>它稍微模糊一些。如果我将x和掩码关闭为7，您记得这是位模式1，1，1。所以如果我把除了最低的3 b以外的所有都掩盖掉，我发现那些都是一的。我已经在这里给你答案了，然后我把它向左移动了30个位置。我能对结果说些什么？</p><p>发言人   01:11:04<br>So I know that x must finish with three ones, right? And I shift that. By 30.<br>所以我知道x必须以三个1结尾，对吗？我改变了这个。到30。</p><p>发言人   01:11:24<br>And these will be the only 2 b that are left after the shifting. And they will be in the most significant position. So what can I say about that number? It’s negative. So this is a true statement, rather obscure, but it is true, is uux greater than -1? It’s almost true, right? The one counter example, that would be what? Zero, well, actually, no, you’re right. There’s a lot of examples. It’s hardly ever true, it’s almost always fault. I was wrong. The only thing that would make it true would be actually, it’s never true. So it’s never true. OK, if x is greater than y is minus x less than minus y?<br>这些将是转移后剩下的唯一2 b。他们将处于最重要的位置。关于这个数字，我能说些什么呢？这是负面的。所以这是一个真实的陈述，相当晦涩，但它是真实的，uux是否大于-1？这几乎是真的，对吧？唯一的反例是什么？零，实际上，不，你是对的。有很多例子。这几乎从来都不是真的，这几乎总是错的。我错了。唯一能使它成为现实的是，它永远不是真的。所以这从来都不是真的。好的，如果x大于y是负x小于负y？</p><p>发言人   01:12:39<br>No, so by the way, one thing we didn’t really cover is what is the negative of t min?<br>不，所以顺便说一句，我们没有真正涵盖的一件事是t min的负数是什么？</p><p>发言人   01:12:51<br>And to see that we can use our comp and increment trick.<br>并且看到我们可以使用我们的comp和increment技巧。</p><p>发言人   01:13:03<br>So when you complement an increment t min, you get t min. And that’s why it’s such a great counter examples. So in particular, if. Y is t min, and x is something else. Then the left hand part will be true, but the right hand part will not be true.<br>因此，当你补足一个增量t min时，你得到t min。这就是为什么它是如此好的反例。尤其是，如果。Y是t min，x是另一种东西。那么左手部分将是正确的，但右手部分将不是正确的。</p><p>发言人   01:13:31<br>X times x greater than or equal to 0. We’ve seen examples of that being fault. If this is kind of silly, if x is greater than 0 and y is greater than 0, is x plus y greater than 0? No, if x is greater than or equal to 0, is minus x less than or equal to 0? Gotcha, you’re right. It’s true, right? Because, but let’s take its counterpart, if x is less than or equal to 0, is minus x greater than equal to 0 TN So the point being that the largest, any positive number can be represented as negative, but there’s one negative number that can’t be represented as positive. And so that asymmetry is why you get different answers to these.<br>X乘以x，大于或等于0。我们已经看到了这种错误的例子。如果这有点傻，如果x大于0而y大于0，那么x加y是否大于0？不，如果x大于或等于0，那么负x是否小于或等于0？你说得对。这是真的，对吧？因为，让我们取它的对应项，如果x小于或等于0，则减去x大于等于0 tn，因此要点是，最大的任何正数都可以表示为负数，但有一个负数不能表示为正数。因此，这种不对称性就是为什么你会得到不同的答案。</p><p>发言人   01:14:30<br>If I take x and I look at minus x, and I shift them to the right by 31 AM I going to get all ones? This is a really weird statement.<br>如果我拿x，然后看负x，然后把它们向右移动31，我会得到所有的一吗？这是一个非常奇怪的声明。</p><p>发言人   01:14:53<br>So it actually kind of works if I take all zeros.<br>所以如果我取全部零，它实际上是有效的。</p><p>发言人   01:15:07<br>And I subtract 1. I’ll get -1.<br>我减去1。我会得到-1。</p><p>发言人   01:15:16<br>And I order them. That works. So what’s wrong with this? What’s that? Oh, but if I shift this to the right 31 places, it’s going to shift arithmetically.<br>我订购了它们。这很有效。这有什么问题吗？那是什么？哦，但如果我将它向右移动31位，它将在算术上移动。</p><p>发言人   01:15:46<br>What’s that? Oh I see, oh I’m sorry, I already jumped ahead to a different puzzle. X and minus x I. So you’re right, actually, if the two numbers are 0. And I order those, I get 0. But you’ll figure out, you’ll notice if it’s anything non-zero, actually, this will be true. And that’s an interesting feature. So there’s a couple other puzzles, and I’ll let you solve those on your own. We’re all set for today.<br>那是什么？哦，我明白了，哦，对不起，我已经跳到了另一个谜题。X和-x I。所以实际上你是对的，如果这两个数字都是0。我订购那些，我得到0。但是你会发现，如果它是任何非零的东西，实际上，这将是真的。这是一个有趣的特点。所以还有其他几个谜题，我会让你自己解决这些谜题。今天我们都准备好了。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>深入理解计算机系统 002-Bits,Bytes,andInteger</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/12/15213-002/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/12/15213-002/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<embed src="/images/15213-002.pdf" type="application/pdf" width="100%" height="600px" /><p>发言人   00:00<br>I see a lot of people figured out to come early, so good for you. So as you recall, my name is Randy Bryant and I’m cosins tuctoria this course along with Jay o’hallor, and for the next couple lectures, the first part of this course, really, we’ll be talking about sort of data representations, in particular, how numbers are represented in different forms in some of the properties. And you saw in that when I talked last week, I showed you things like you can multiply some numbers together that are positive and get negative results. So what we want to understand is what is a bit level representation of numbers and how does that affect some of the properties you have when you operate them on? And especially looking at the corner cases, when things overflow, don’t do what you might expect them to do. So we’ll start off with very basic stuff of how numbers are represented, especially integer valued numbers are represented in bits.<br>我看到很多人想出早点来，对你有好处。正如你所记得的，我叫兰迪·布莱恩特，我是科斯金斯·图克托利亚，和杰伊·奥哈罗一起上这门课程，在接下来的几次讲座中，在这门课程的第一部分，我们将特别讨论数据表示。数字在某些属性中如何以不同的形式表示。你可以看到，当我上周谈话时，我向你展示了一些东西，比如你可以将一些积极的数字相乘，得到消极的结果。所以我们想要理解的是，数字的位级表示是什么，以及当你对它们进行操作时，它如何影响你拥有的一些属性？特别是在角落里，当事情溢出时，不要做你期望他们做的事情。所以我们将从如何表示数字的最基本的东西开始，特别是用比特表示整数值的数字。</p><span id="more"></span><p>发言人   01:06<br>So I think you’ve pretty well figured out in this world that the whole digital world is sort of based on binary values. And that wasn’t always the case. I mean, since humans have 10 fingers and 10 toes, a lot of the world was based on the decimal system. And it was really only, and in fact, the first electronic computer, the ENIAC built in University of Pennsylvania, basically encoded, did all of its arithmetic using base 10. They had 10 vacuum tubes per digit they wanted to represent. So they basically turned on or off those tubes to represent which of the 10 possible digits you could want. And it really didn’t come to people until later than that. So that’s 1948, that they really should just think about base 2 for everything.<br>所以我认为你在这个世界上已经很好地意识到，整个数字世界都是基于二进制值的。但情况并非一直如此。我的意思是，由于人类有10个手指和10个脚趾，世界上很多东西都是基于十进制系统的。实际上，它是第一台电子计算机，宾夕法尼亚大学制造的ENIAC，基本上是用10为基数进行编码和所有算术运算。他们想要表示的每个数字有10个真空管。所以他们基本上打开或关闭这些管来代表你想要的10个可能的数字中的哪一个。而且直到后来才真正降临到人们身上。所以那是1948年，他们真的应该只考虑以2为基数的一切。</p><p>发言人   02:04<br>And the reason why bits are great is in the digital world, you can sort of take what’s otherwise an analog signal and quantify it and just say I’m going to say that one range of values, let’s say it’s a low voltage. I’m going to call that a 0. And the high range of values I’m going to call it a one. And if there’s noise or imperfections in the circuit or anything going on, as long as that doesn’t exceed these thresholds you’ve set up, then you’ll get a nice clean signal out of it. And that’s the main advantage of digital processing over analog processing. And so that’s sort of at the core why everything we do, and especially for storing information, it turns out it’s much easier to store 1 b of information or a digital value than it is to store an analog value.<br>比特之所以伟大的原因在于数字世界，你可以取一个模拟信号并量化它，然后说我要说的是一个范围的值，假设它是一个低电压。我会称它为0。以及我将称之为 “一” 的高范围价值观。如果电路中存在噪音或缺陷或任何情况，只要不超过您设置的这些阈值，那么您将得到一个干净的信号。这就是数字处理与模拟处理相比的主要优势。这就是我们所做的一切的核心原因，尤其是对于存储信息，事实证明，存储1 b信息或数字值比存储模拟值要容易得多。</p><p>发言人   03:04<br>Sorry. Slides went a little crazy on animations. So the point is that we represent all the numbers in a computer as sets of bits. And I think you generally understand that fairly well. And so, of course, the familiar binary representation of integers, which we’ll go over today, just uses a bit position for each power of two.<br>对不起。幻灯片在动画方面有点疯狂。关键是我们将计算机中的所有数字表示为一组位。我想你一般都相当了解这一点。所以，当然，我们今天会介绍的整数的二进制表示形式，只是对每个2的幂使用一个位位置。</p><p>发言人   03:29<br>We can also represent values that are fractional. And we’ll talk about that a week from today when we do floating point numbers, where what you do is to the right of the binary point is no longer a decimal point, it’s a binary point. And so something to the left of that would have weight 1, 2 to the zero, and the next one over would have weight 2 to the one. But what you do is you go to the right that has weight to the -1, to the -2. In other words, one, this is 2, this is one half, and this is 1 4. So we can represent just like you do the decimal representation of fractions, we can do the binary representation of fractions. And that’s the core of floating point number representations.<br>我们也可以表示分数形式的值。我们将在今天进行浮点数的一周后讨论这个问题，那时你要做的是在二进制小数点的右边不再是小数点，而是一个二进制小数点。因此，左边的物体的权重为1，2为零，下一个物体的权重为2。但你要做的是你走到权重为-1和-2的右边。换句话说，1，这是2，这是一半，这是1 4。所以我们可以像小数一样表示小数，我们可以用二进制表示小数。这就是浮点数表示的核心。</p><p>发言人   04:25<br>And so it gets very annoying if you have, say, 32 or even 64 b numbers to be writing these strings of ones and zeros out. And so what we use and what’s become largely the most common is to group collections of 4 b at a time.<br>因此，如果你有32个甚至64个b的数字要写出这些1和0的字符串，就会变得非常烦人。因此，我们使用的最常见的方法是一次将4个b的集合分组。</p><p>发言人   04:46<br>And then represent that in base 16, or what’s known as hexadecimal representation, using the letters A through F as values 10 through 15. And you’ll spend a lot of time staring at hexadecimal numbers this year, and you’ll get pretty good at being able to look at a hex number and just write it out in binary The way I do it, just to tell you is, I mean I’ve got the values from 0 to. Nine wired down pretty well. And then I keep track of a few special cases. One 0, 1, 0 is a 1, 0, 0 is C, and 1, 1, 1, 1 is f For b, d, and e, I kind of interpolate between those. So if you want to develop that skill, that’s the way you can do it.<br>然后用基数16表示，也就是所谓的十六进制表示，使用字母A到F作为值10到15。你今年会花很多时间盯着十六进制数字，你会变得相当不错，能够看到十六进制数字并像我一样以二进制形式写出，只是为了告诉你，我的意思是我得到了从0到的值。九个连接得很好。然后我会跟踪一些特殊情况。一个0，1，0是一个1，0，0是C，1，1，1是b，d和e的f，我有点在它们之间插值。所以，如果你想发展这项技能，这就是你可以做到的方式。</p><p>发言人   05:49<br>You’re looking for something connector, an Hdmi to what? No, I don’t think there’s any connector here.<br>你正在寻找连接器，Hdmi到什么？不，我不认为这里有任何连接器。</p><p>发言人   06:03<br>So that’s something you’re going to end up wanting to be able to do. So in C, we don’t.<br>所以这将是你最终想要能够做到的事情。所以在C中，我们没有。</p><p>发言人   06:13<br>In most declarations, you don’t actually are told exactly how many bytes a byte is 8 b each data value is represented as, and that’s partly C was designed actually back when microprocessors only had 16 b words. It was actually before microprocessors. So 16 b words were a fairway standard thing, and over time, that’s expanded from 16 to 32 to now 64. And so C, rather than sort of in advance saying, here’s how many bytes every value we’ll have, has these slightly ambiguous terms that vary actually from one machine to the next. And if you’re a very careful C programmer, you have to anticipate that sum. But what we’ll deal with is X 8664 is the class of machines we’ll be working with exclusively this term.<br>在大多数声明中，您实际上不会被告知每个数据值表示为8 b的字节数，并且这部分是在微处理器只有16 b字的时候设计回来的。它实际上是在微处理器出现之前。因此，16个b单词是球道标准的东西，随着时间的推移，它从16个增加到32个，现在已经增加到64个。因此，C并不是事先说每个值有多少字节，而是有这些稍微含糊不清的术语，实际上它们因机器而异。如果你是一个非常谨慎的C程序员，你必须预见到这个总和。但是我们将要处理的是X 8664，它是我们将专门使用这个术语的机器类别。</p><p>发言人   07:10<br>And so you can see that when you declare something to be a char, sometimes people call that a char. That’s a 1 B value. A short is 16 by bit, an int is 32. And if you want to get all 64 b, you have to declare it to be a long.<br>所以你可以看到，当你声明某物是char时，有时人们称之为char。这是一个1 B的值。一个short是16位的，一个int是32。如果你想获得全部64 b，你必须声明它是长的。</p><p>发言人   07:32<br>And then again, there’s two different precisions of floating point. There’s 4 B or 32 b of floating point numbers and 64 b. There’s also a slightly obscure holdover from ancient days of of floating point, where there’s a special representation in Intel machines that uses a 10 B or 80 b representation. And when you use that on a. 64 b machine. They sort of waste an extra 6 B out of that so that everything is aligned in 16 B increments.<br>然后，有两种不同精度的浮点运算。有4 B或32 b的浮点数和64 b的浮点数。还有一个与浮点数古代相比有些模糊的保持，在英特尔机器中有一个特殊的表示，它使用10 b或80 b的表示。当你在a上使用它时。64 b机器。他们有点浪费额外的6 B，这样所有的东西都以16 B的增量对齐。</p><p>发言人   08:09<br>The other thing, and this is an important feature, is any address is defined to be the word size of the machine when they say it’s a 64 b machine, what they really mean is that the addresses are 64 b values or 8 B values. And that’s different, For example, if you use an older machine, a 32 b machine, those will only be 32 b addresses.<br>另一个重要的特性是，当他们说机器是64 b时，任何地址都被定义为机器的字数，他们真正的意思是地址是64 b值或8 b值。这是不同的，例如，如果您使用一台较旧的机器，一台32 b的机器，这些将只是32 b的地址。</p><p>发言人   08:37<br>So the basis then, imagine you’ve had this at some point of how do we then think about bits is based on Boolean algebra, which actually comes from the 1890s, that a guy named George Boe who recognized a sort of relation between what we’d call bits, but they weren’t called bits back then.<br>因此，想象一下，在某个时候我们如何思考位的基础是基于布尔代数的，它实际上来自18 90年代，一个名叫George Boe的人认识到我们所谓的位之间的一种关系，但它们当时不被称为位。</p><p>发言人   09:04<br>0, 1, and logic are basically truth values in logic. I’m thinking of an algebra, sort of a structured set of operations you could apply that would capture some of the concepts that people assume in logic. So for example, if we think of one being true and 0 being false, then the And operation is true if both of the inputs, both of the arguments are true. So we get this chart here. And similarly, the Or operation is true if either input is true or one, the nod is just to flip the bit, and then the exclusive, or is what you get when you say it’s one or the other, but not both. And so it has this representation.<br>0、1和逻辑基本上都是逻辑中的真值。我正在考虑一种代数，一种可以应用的结构化操作集，可以捕捉人们在逻辑中假设的一些概念。因此，例如，如果我们认为一个是真的，0是假的，那么如果两个输入，两个参数都是真的，那么和操作就是真的。所以我们在这里得到这张图表。类似地，如果输入为真或为一真，则或操作为真，点头只是翻转位，然后是互斥，或者是当你说它是一个或另一个时得到的，而不是两个。所以它有这种代表性。</p><p>发言人   09:53<br>So just as a bit of history, it was master’s degree student at MIT named Claude Shannon who had taken a course in logic as an undergraduate at University of Michigan. And he was the one who made the connection between thinking about this, what was at the time very obscure branch of something or other of logic, and applying it to digital systems back in an era when they actually built these things out of electromechanical relays. And so his master’s thesis is probably the most impactful master’s thesis in the history of humankind. And you always wonder, well, what did they do before that? Then? How did they even think about these things anyways, the idea of applying this algebra then to bits is not something that’s sort of been true since the world began. It’s something that’s a relatively modern concept.<br>因此，作为历史的一部分，麻省理工学院的硕士研究生克劳德·香农在密歇根大学本科学习了逻辑学课程。他是那个将思考这个在当时非常模糊的逻辑分支和将其应用于数字系统之间联系起来的人，当时他们实际上是用机电继电器构建这些东西的时代。所以他的硕士论文可能是人类历史上最有影响力的硕士论文。你总是想知道，好吧，在那之前他们做了什么？那么呢？无论如何，他们是如何思考这些事情的，将代数应用于比特的想法并不是自世界开始以来就一直存在的事情。这是一个相对现代的概念。</p><p>发言人   10:59<br>Now, what’s an important? Thing that might be less obvious is we can also do these over words. We can do these Boolean operations where we apply them on each successive bit in that word. And these symbols, we use, the ampersand vertical bar cart and tilde are actually the ones that C uses to represent these operations. And so again, if we look at here, the one is only if both of the values are one. And for the, for the n for the, or if either of them are one, the exclusive, or if 1 is one and the other is 0, and tilde is just to invert the bits of it.<br>现在，什么是重要的？可能不太明显的是，我们也可以通过文字来实现这些。我们可以进行这些布尔操作，将它们应用于该单词中的每个连续位。我们所使用的这些符号、与符号垂直饮料服务车和代字符实际上是C用来表示这些操作的符号。因此，如果我们再看看这里，只有当两个值都是一个时，才会出现一个。对于n，对于n，或者如果其中一个是一个，则为互斥，或者如果1为1而另一个为0，则波浪号只是将其位反转。</p><p>发言人   11:45<br>Again, we will spend a lot of time making use of the fact that in C, and this is one of the features of C that people like, is that you can do these here at a very low level bit of manipulation directly in the language. And this actually turns out to be useful in practice.<br>再说一遍，我们将花费大量时间利用这个事实，即在C语言中，这是人们喜欢的C语言的特点之一，你可以在这里直接在语言中以非常低级别的操作来实现这些功能。这在实践中实际上是有用的。</p><p>发言人   12:05<br>And it’s sort of implicit of a way of representing sets of values. So this example is, imagine we want to represents sets where the elements of the set are numbers ranging between 0 and 7. So 1 B is enough to capture eight cases and will, if we number the bits and we number them from right to left, so this is bit 0. So that would represent whether or not the value 0 is an element of the set And simly here, you’ll see 0, 1, 2, 3. So we’re saying that bit 3 being one here means 3 is an element of the set, and so forth. So the idea. Is then the and operation becomes like set intersection, the Or operation becomes like set union, and the exclusive or operation is what’s called symmetric difference. And so these are and tilde is like complement.<br>它是一种隐含的表示值集合的方式。所以这个例子是，想象我们想要表示集合，其中集合的元素是范围在0到7之间的数字。因此，如果我们对比特进行编号并从右到左对它们进行编号，则1 B足以捕获8种情况，因此这就是第0位。因此，这将表示值0是否是集合的一个元素，简单地在这里，您将看到0，1，2，3。所以我们说这里的第3位表示1，意味着3是集合的一个元素，依此类推。所以这个想法。然后，和操作变得像集合交集，或操作变得像集合并集，而异或操作就是所谓的对称差。因此，这些是和波浪号就像补码一样。</p><p>发言人   13:15<br>So these are actually very common. For example, there’s.<br>这些其实很常见。例如，有。</p><p>发言人   13:24<br>Operations you’ll learn later when we look at file IO about IO that you can track, I want to know which set of possible inputs to the system. Think of different network connections. Have an input ready for me to read, and there is a data structure that it’s sort of hidden away among some seeing library calls. But it basically is using exactly this representation, about 1000 of bits worth of information to represent these sets and do manipulation on those sets.<br>当我们查看可以跟踪的有关IO的文件IO时，您将会学习操作，我想知道系统有哪些可能的输入。考虑不同的网络连接。有一个输入准备好供我阅读，并且有一个数据结构，它有点隐藏在一些看到的库调用中。但它基本上就是使用这种表示形式，大约1000位的信息来表示这些集合，并对这些集合进行操作。</p><p>发言人   14:08<br>So as I mentioned, those are available directly in C, the ampersand vertical bar tilde and cart.<br>正如我所提到的，这些可以直接在C中使用，即 &amp; 竖线波浪号和购物车。</p><p>发言人   14:17<br>One thing that’s really, really important and that programmers screw it up all the time, beginning programmers and even experienced programmers from time to time, is to mix up single ampersand and the double ampersand, or the single vertical bar and the double vertical bar and the tilde versus the exclamation mark, which is often pronounced, bang. And the reason so. Obviously, there’s sort of a. Syntactic similarity. And there’s actually a somewhat of a semantic relation too. This is another kind of and another kind of Or, and another kind of not. Mix and match these. You’re certainly going to have problems.<br>有一件非常重要的事情，即程序员，新手程序员甚至有经验的程序员，不时搞砸它，就是混淆单个和双符号，或者单个竖条和双竖条以及波浪号和感叹号。这通常被发音为bang。这就是原因。显然，有一种。句法相似性。实际上还有一种语义关系。这是另一种类型的或者，另一种类型的不是。混合搭配这些。你肯定会遇到问题。</p><p>发言人   15:03<br>So the double bar ones aren’t thinking about bitwise operations. They’re thinking about something that’s either true or false, period. And in that representation, the number 0 is the thing that’s false and anything else, any other bit pattern is considered to be true. And so the other feature that the double operations give you is what’s called early termination.<br>所以双线的人没有考虑按位操作。他们正在考虑一些不是对就是错的事情，时期。在这种表示中，数字0是假的，其他任何比特模式都被认为是真的。因此，双重操作给你的另一个功能是所谓的提前终止。</p><p>发言人   15:33<br>So in particular, if we do some examples on some hex pattern for one. So this is a. Not a 0. And so that’s considered true in this interpretation. The bang of that, the knot of that is 0. In same way, if you have 0, the knot of that is one. And if you apply bang to a number twice, you’ll get back a one, unless it was 0. And then similarly, these patterns here are the reason why this returns one is because it’s considered two cases that are true.<br>所以特别是，如果我们在一些十六进制模式上做一些例子。所以这是a。不是0。因此，在这种解释中，这被认为是正确的。那砰的一声，那的结是0。同样地，如果你有0，那么它的结就是1。如果你对一个数字应用两次，你会得到一个1，除非它是0。然后同样，这些模式在这里是返回一个的原因，因为它被认为是两种真实的情况。</p><p>发言人   16:20<br>So it’s not doing bitwise operations. It’s just trying to create true and false. It’s interpreting arguments to be either true or false and returning either true or false. But when it returns true, it returns one and not whatever number you happen to give it.<br>所以它不进行按位操作。它只是试图创造真实和虚假。它将参数解释为真或假，并返回真或假。但当它返回true时，它会返回一个，而不是你给它的任何数字。</p><p>发言人   16:36<br>So obviously, this is a very different operations than you have with the single versions of those. But it’s easy just because you mentally slip or because you type something wrong to do the wrong thing. But in particular, this early termination is something that, of course, people use a lot.<br>显然，这是一个与单个版本的操作非常不同的操作。但这很容易，只是因为你精神上的失误，或者因为你输入了错误的东西而做错事。但特别的是，这种提前终止当然是人们经常使用的东西。</p><p>发言人   16:57<br>If you want to make sure that you’re not accessing a null pointer, you can test whether that’s a null pointer first before accessing it. And if this is zero or a null, then it won’t do the dereferencing of null. So it’s a fairly useful feature as well. Anyways, that’s an aside. At this level, we’re mostly looking at bits, but just as a programming note, don’t mix these up.<br>如果你想确保你没有访问空指针，你可以在访问它之前先测试它是否为空指针。如果这是零或null，则它不会取消null的引用。所以这也是一个相当有用的功能。不管怎样，这是旁白。在这个层面上，我们主要看的是比特，但只是作为编程说明，不要混淆这些。</p><p>发言人   17:34<br>The other class of operations will make use of a lot are shifting, which again, is not something that you normally sort of as beginning programmers think about too much. And there’s a curious feature that left shifts are always the same, but there’s two different flavors of right shift. And we’ll see in a little bit later why there’s two different flavors of right-shift but.<br>另一类操作将会利用很多东西正在转移，这不是你通常作为新手程序员考虑得太多的事情。而且有一个奇怪的特征，即左移总是相同的，但右移有两种不同的风格。稍后我们会看到为什么有两种不同风格的右移位。</p><p>发言人   17:58<br>The idea then of shifting is that you have some argument x, and you want to shift it some number of positions either to the left or to the right, given by y, and so when you shift left, you just fill in whatever value there was. So you pick up the I’m shifting by three. So I’ll take the lower order, 5 b, move them over three positions, and then fill in with a 0 and whatever was in the upper positions of that original, where they just sort of disappear into the into nowhere. Similarly, if I do a right shift, I take the upper 6 b, I move them over two positions, and I fill in with zeros. So that’s a logical shift and that’s it’s logical.<br>移位的想法是，你有一些参数x，你想要将它向左或向右移动一些位置，由y给出，所以当你向左移动时，你只需填写任何值。所以你拿起我正在移动三个。所以我会选择较低的顺序，5 b，将它们移动到三个位置，然后填充0和原始位置较高的任何东西，在那里它们就会消失在无处。同样地，如果我右移，我取上部的6 b，将它们移动到两个位置上，然后用零填充。这是一个合乎逻辑的转变，这就是合乎逻辑的。</p><p>发言人   18:46<br>There’s another flavor called the arithmetic shift, which differs in the rule for what bits you fill in with are not based on, are not zeros necessarily, but whatever the most significant bit was in the original value. So it doesn’t matter here because the most significant bit was 0, but you’ll see in the case here of where the leading bit was a one, that when I shift it to the right arithmetically I’ll fill it in with once. And that’ll make sense more when we understand how negative numbers get represented in a machine. And that’s the purpose of it and why it’s called arithmetic. The other thing that is kind of confusing to people is what should happen if you say, I want to shift an 8 b number, 8 positions to the left?<br>还有另一种叫做算术移位的方法，它的不同之处在于您填充的位不是基于的规则，也不一定是零，而是原始值中最重要的位。所以在这里并不重要，因为最高有效位是0，但你会看到在这里的前导位是1的情况下，当我将其算术向右移动时，我将用一次填充它。当我们理解负数在机器中的表示方式时，这将使感知更加重要。这就是它的目的，也是它被称为算术的原因。另一件让人们有点困惑的事情是，如果你说我想把一个8 b的数字向左移动8个位置，应该会发生什么？</p><p>发言人   19:55<br>And x is a single byte. What do you think you should get? Zero, that would be a pretty logical thing.<br>x是一个单字节。你认为你应该得到什么？零，这将是一件相当合乎逻辑的事情。</p><p>发言人   20:06<br>You kind of shift all those bits out, you fill them with zeros. On most machines, you’ll get whatever x was. Because what it will do is it will compute this number mod a. And the reason that happens is, if you think about it, it’s looking at just the low order 3 b of the shift amount and ignoring all the rest. So that’s effectively like module 8. So that’s just a warning. And on some machines, it does what you just thought it should, and other machines it does this. And so there’s no guarantee in C that it will be one way or the other.<br>你把所有这些位都移动出来，用零填充它们。在大多数机器上，你会得到x是什么。因为它将会计算这个数字mod a。发生这种情况的原因是，如果你仔细想想，它只看移位量的低阶3 b，而忽略了所有其余的部分。所以这实际上就像模块8一样。所以这只是一个警告。在某些机器上，它会做你刚才认为它应该做的事情，而在其他机器上，它会这样做。因此，在C中并不能保证它会是一种方式还是另一种方式。</p><p>发言人   20:54<br>Same with if you try to shift left by a negative number, that might be logically, well, I guess you really want to shift right then, but that usually doesn’t work either. So now let’s talk about number representations. This is sort of a very core idea that you have to really have wired in you. And I’m going to illustrate it with some examples.<br>同样，如果你试图向左移动一个负数，这可能是逻辑上的，好吧，我猜你真的想向右移动，但这通常也不起作用。现在让我们来谈谈数字表示。这是一个非常核心的想法，你必须真正与之相连。我会用一些例子来说明。</p><p>发言人   21:29<br>So these two equations, then, are everything that we’ll talk about sort of stems from them. So one is if you have an unsigned number, then basically. So he keeps jumping on me.<br>那么这两个方程式，就是我们将要谈论的一切都源于它们。所以一个是，如果你有一个无符号的数字，那么基本上。所以他一直跳到我身上。</p><p>发言人   21:48<br>If you have an unsigned number, then this is just the conversion. Then Btu means from bit, a bit level representation to an unsigned number of some bit pattern. It just says, well, just add up the sum of the weighted bits where each bit is weighted by a power of two. And the only difference when we look at two’s complement, which is a way to represent both negative and positive numbers, we’ll consider the most significant bit to be what’s called the sine bit. So it will have a negative value. So let me just illustrate this with I’ll use some running examples, and we’ll just use 5 b numbers just as a way it really helps often if you’re trying to understand this stuff, to do it for some smaller cases. So if we think about bit positions.<br>如果您有一个无符号数字，那么这只是转换。然后Btu意味着从位，一个位级表示到某个位模式的无符号数字。它只是说，好吧，只需将加权位的总和相加，其中每个位加权2的幂。当我们看2的补码时唯一的区别是，这是一种表示负数和正数的方式，我们会认为最重要的位是所谓的正弦位。因此它将具有负值。所以让我用一些运行的例子来说明这一点，我们只使用5 B数字，如果你试图理解这些东西，对于一些较小的情况来说，它经常会有所帮助。所以，如果我们考虑位的位置。</p><p>发言人   22:50<br>Zero through 4.<br>从零到四。</p><p>发言人   23:00<br>Then those represent different powers of two weights, as I’ve shown. And so now if we take some bit pattern.<br>那么这些代表两个权重的不同幂，正如我所展示的那样。所以现在如果我们采取一些模式。</p><p>发言人   23:20<br>Like so. So that’s what I’ll call x, and I want to convert that to an unsigned number. I will just combine 8 plus 4 plus 1, and I’ll get 13. So that’s all that equation says, the left hand equation. Bit positions that are ones use the corresponding power of 2, and you’re done. And similarly, if I have a number where there’s a leading bit.<br>就像这样。所以这就是我称之为x的东西，我想将它转换为无符号数字。我只需要把8加4加1结合起来，就能得到13。这就是这个方程所说的一切，左手方程。位位置使用相应的2的幂，你就完成了。类似地，如果我有一个数字，其中有一个前导位。</p><p>发言人   24:03<br>It will be 16 plus 4 plus 2, so that will be 22. And so that’s the unsigned case.<br>它将是16加4加2，因此将是22。这就是未签署的案例。</p><p>发言人   24:16<br>And the sine case is the same idea, except that most significant bit. Has a negative value? So this is I. And our weights will be 1, 2, 4, 8. But this will now be -60. So that’s what the equation on the right is saying. But this bit, now we’re going to change it from being a negative number to a positive. So obviously, if I have, this is my bit pattern, it’s going to be the same because the other bit stay the same. So let’s do it for this case of 1 0 1 1, 0. So that will be -16 plus 4 plus 2. So that will equal -10. So you see in this case, we have the same bit pattern.<br>和正弦情况是相同的想法，除了最高有效位。有负值吗？这就是我。我们的权重将是1、2、4、8。但现在这将是-60。这就是右边的方程式所说的。但是这个位，现在我们要将它从一个负数改为正数。所以很明显，如果我有，这是我的位模式，它将是相同的，因为其他位保持不变。所以让我们为这个1 0 1，0的情况做这件事。这将是-16加4加2。这将等于-10。所以你可以看到，在这种情况下，我们有相同的位模式。</p><p>发言人   25:20<br>It’s just if we interpret it how we think about what number this represents, then in one case, it’s a positive number, 22, and in another case, it’s a negative number -10. And that’s what these equations are saying.<br>这只是如果我们如何解释它，我们认为这代表什么数字，那么在一种情况下，它是一个正数22，在另一种情况下，它是一个负数-10。这就是这些方程式所说的。</p><p>发言人   25:42<br>And so the most significant bit is sometimes called the sine bit, because if it’s a 1, the number is going to be negative. So? Let’s sort of think about. What are the sort of extreme ranges of numbers we can get with these two different representations?<br>因此，最重要的位有时被称为正弦位，因为如果它是1，则数字将是负数。所以呢？让我们思考一下。使用这两种不同的表示方式，我们可以得到什么样的数字极端范围？</p><p>发言人   26:14<br>So obviously, if these are all zeros, my number is going to equal 0. And if it’s all one?<br>所以显然，如果这些都是零，我的数字将等于0。如果都是一个呢？</p><p>发言人   26:28<br>It will be 16 plus 8 plus 4 plus 2 plus 1 will be 31. And over here, for the two’s complement, the smallest number, well, the largest number, well, actually the let. Me do it this way. Actually, the most negative number, so the smallest number in the strictest sense of the word, is this. It’s -16. And you can argue this, by the way, is the that has a negative weight, all the other ones have positive one. So certainly one, all the rest being zeros is going to be the smallest number. And similarly, the largest number you can represent.<br>它将是16加8加4加2加1将是31。在这里，对于两个补码，最小的数字，最大的数字，实际上是let。我是这样做的。实际上，最负的数字，也就是这个词最严格感知中最小的数字。这是-16。你可以争辩说，顺便说一下，是负权重的，其他所有的都有正权重。所以可以肯定的是，所有其余的都是零，将是最小的数字。同样，您可以代表的最大数字。</p><p>发言人   27:22<br>Will be 8 plus 4 plus 2 plus 1, which is 15. And so we call this number u max. And we call this number T max. And we call this number t min.<br>将是8加4加2加1，即15。所以我们称这个数字为u max。我们称这个数字为T max。我们称这个数字为t min。</p><p>发言人   27:50<br>So there’s a few things to observe about these numbers. Remember, this is a 5 b word size. So you’ll see that 31 is pretty close to 32. In fact, it’s 2 to the 5th -1. And in general, and that’s for a 5 b word size. So you would say in general, it will have value 2 to the w, if I have a w bit number -1. And that’s what this shows. And similarly, over here, this is -2 to the fourth. And so we’d say in general, that will be -2 to the w, if it’s a w number -1. All these make sense.<br>关于这些数字，有几点需要观察。记住，这是一个5 b的单词大小。所以你会看到31非常接近32。实际上，它是2的5th -1。一般来说，这适用于5 b的单词大小。所以你会说，一般来说，如果我有一个w位数字-1，它的w值将为2。这就是它所展示的。同样地，在这里，这是-2到第四个。因此，我们通常会说，如果是w编号-1，那么w的值将是-2。所有这些都使感知。</p><p>发言人   28:53<br>By the way, You’ll notice one other feature is. A whole string of one like this. If you sum up those digits, 8 plus 4 plus 2 plus 1 will be one less than the next bit position up. And you can think about that if to count this, if you were to increment this number by one, you’d get 1, 1 is 0, carry one, and so forth. And you’d carry that value up to this position. So there’s various ways you can think about that. And then similarly, this number is 2 to the 4th -1, and so that’s equal to 2 to the w -1 -1.<br>顺便说一句，你会注意到另一个特点是。像这样的一串。如果你把这些数字加起来，8加4加2加1将比下一个位位置少一。你可以考虑一下，如果要计算这个数字，如果你将这个数字增加一，你会得到1，1是0，携带一，等等。你会把这个价值带到这个位置。所以你可以有各种各样的方法来考虑这个问题。然后同样地，这个数字是2的第四个1，因此等于2的w-1-1。</p><p>发言人   29:49<br>As is shown here so. There’s a lot of the book goes through formulas and does derivations. But if you just think about it in these smaller scale ways, the intuition is pretty easy to get and don’t get lost in formulas when really at the gut level, it’s a fairly straightforward set of ideas. Or if you ever see some equations and you’re confused, try out some small examples and see what they’re saying.<br>如这里所示。这本书有很多内容都经过公式和推导。但是如果你只是以这些较小规模的方式思考，直觉很容易得到，不要迷失在公式中，当真正在直觉层面上时，这是一组相当直接的想法。或者如果你看到一些方程式而感到困惑，尝试一些小例子，看看它们在说什么。</p><p>发言人   30:24<br>Another interesting number in the world of two’s complement is what happens when you have all ones in your bit pattern. And that will have -16 plus 8, plus 4 plus 2 plus 1. And that will equal -1. The bit pattern, all one is always a -1. In this representation, I should mention two S complement is not the only way to represent positive and negative numbers, what’s sometimes called S numbers. But it’s so universal that you’ll hardly ever encounter another case. So if you understand who’s compliment, you have a pretty good understanding of what really is going on.<br>在两个补码的世界中，另一个有趣的数字是当你的位模式中有所有一个时会发生什么。那将有-16加8，加4加2加1。这将等于-1。位模式，所有一个总是-1。在这种表示中，我应该提到两个补码并不是表示正数和负数的唯一方法，有时也被称为S数。但它是如此普遍，以至于你几乎不会遇到其他案例。所以，如果你理解了谁的赞美，你就对真正发生的事情有了很好的理解。</p><p>发言人   31:23<br>So these numbers I call, max the biggest unsigned number, t min, the smallest, most negative two’s comple and TX the largest, most positive two’s complement. This chart shows the range of values for different word sizes or different numbers of bytes.<br>所以我称之为这些数字，max是最大的无符号数，t min是最小的、最负的2的comple，TX是最大的、最正的2的comple。此图表显示不同单词大小或不同字节数的值范围。</p><p>发言人   31:45<br>And so you’ll see that with an 8 b number, you only have 256 possibilities and. So we can either choose to. Think of those as presenting the range from 0 to 255, or basically with two complement numbers, we just doing sort of a wraparound. We’re saying, well, we’re going to have half of them be negative, and the other half will be either zero or positive. And so that’s a pretty limited range of values, of course. And then 16. And believe me, back when computers had 16 b word sizes, it was a nuisance to keep your numbers within that range. And 32 gives you a pretty decent range.<br>所以你会看到，对于一个8 b数字，你只有256个可能性。所以我们可以选择。把它们想象成表示从0到255的范围，或者基本上用两个补码数，我们只是做了一个环绕。我们说，嗯，我们将会有一半是负数，另一半要么是零，要么是正数。因此，这当然是一个相当有限的数值范围。然后是16。相信我，当计算机有16个b的单词大小时，把你的数字保持在那个范围内是一件麻烦事。而32为您提供了一个相当不错的范围。</p><p>发言人   32:34<br>It used to be said Microsoft had to go to 64 b word size to represent Bill Gates’s net worth. For me at least, this would easily handle my range of normal day to day transactions. But now, with 64 b, at least to us nowadays, those seem like really big numbers, hard to imagine exceeding the bounds of those. So one interesting feature that you noticed here was I was. Like this case here.<br>过去人们常说，微软必须使用64 b的字数大小来代表比尔盖茨的净资产。至少对我来说，这将很容易处理我的正常日常交易范围。但是现在，有了64个b，至少对我们现在来说，这些数字看起来真的很大，很难想象会超越它们的界限。所以你在这里注意到的一个有趣的特征是我是。就像这个案例。</p><p>发言人   33:27<br>In this case here. You ready?<br>在这种情况下。准备好了吗？</p><p>发言人   33:38<br>And then this case here of all ones. I was comparing it to this case here of all ones. So in other words, in both these cases, it’s a little hard to jump boards here.<br>然后是这里的所有一种情况。我把它和这里的所有案例进行比较。换句话说，在这两种情况下，在这里跳板都有点困难。</p><p>发言人   33:58<br>You’re seeing that you have the same bit pattern in either case, but they represent different numeric values because one is a twos complement case and the other is an unsigned. And you can actually see the relation between them is pretty simple because basically what we’re doing is we jumping between a plus 16 and a -16 between those. And so you’d expect it to change by 32. And you see that here, that this is 31 here, and -1, this is 22 and -10. So they’re different from each other by plus or -32, 2 to the 5th two to the word size. And so there’s sort of a long derivation in the book things here. But that connection is actually fairly important because when you jump back and forth between unsigned numbers and two complement numbers in C, that’s the jump that you get, in other words.<br>你会看到在任何一种情况下你都有相同的位模式，但它们代表不同的数值，因为一个是二进制补码的情况，另一个是无符号的。你实际上可以看到它们之间的关系非常简单，因为基本上我们所做的就是在这些之间跳跃在 + 16和-16之间。所以你预计它会改变32。你可以看到，这里是31，-1，这是22和-10。因此，它们彼此之间的差异是加或-32，2到单词大小的第五个二。因此，这里的书籍中有一些冗长的推导。但这种联系实际上相当重要，因为当你在C中的无符号数和两个补码数之间来回跳转时，换句话说，这就是你得到的跳跃。</p><p>发言人   35:14<br>You’ll often find cases where what used to be a very large number, because it was unsigned, all of a sudden becomes a negative number because it’s considered two’s complement. So that’s what this next part covers.<br>你经常会发现这样的情况: 曾经是一个非常大的数，因为它是无符号的，突然变成了一个负数，因为它被认为是2的补码。这就是下一部分的内容。</p><p>发言人   35:28<br>We’ll say that. If we take a chart of 4 b numbers and we write out all the possible values as unsigned or as choose these complement numbers, then the ones where the higher order bit is 0 will be the same. In both cases, the ones where the higher order bit is a one in this case will differ by 16 2 to the fourth. And similarly, you’ll notice that these numbers, there’s a unique, it goes unique in both directions. For any given bit pattern, there’s a unique number it represents, and similarly, for any number within the given range, there’s a unique bit pattern.<br>我们会这么说。如果我们采用4 b数字的图表，并将所有可能的值写出为无符号或选择这些补数，那么高阶位为0的那些将是相同的。在这两种情况下，高阶位是1的情况将相差16 2比4。同样地，你会注意到这些数字，它们是独一无二的，在两个方向上都独一无二。对于任何给定的位模式，它都有一个唯一的数字，同样，对于给定范围内的任何数字，都有一个唯一的位模式。</p><p>发言人   36:19<br>So we can sort of jump between those two and say I can make up a rule for converting between a two’s complement number x and an unsigned number uux that basically says I’ll use the same bits. I’ll just think of them as being different numbers. And so, and you can go either way. So for example, if we thought of this as a. A two’s complement representative representation, It’s -1. This function I’m calling t to u goes from that number -1 to this number 31, where in between the two I’m saying they both have the same bit pattern.<br>所以我们可以在这两者之间跳转，并说我可以制定一个规则，用于在两个补码x和无符号数uux之间进行转换，基本上说我将使用相同的位。我会把它们看作是不同的数字。所以，你可以走任何一条路。因此，例如，如果我们认为这是一个。一个2的互补代表表示，它是-1。这个我调用t到u的函数从那个数字-1到这个数字31，在这两者之间，我说它们都有相同的位模式。</p><p>发言人   37:19<br>And the reason why this rather function that would otherwise seem to have no particular use is important is because that’s basically what happens in C, or actually in the program on the.<br>这个函数似乎没有特别的用处，重要的原因是因为这基本上就是在C中发生的事情，或者实际上在程序中发生的事情。</p><p>发言人   37:33<br>Computer itself has no clue whether a given bit pattern, if it’s something you’re thinking of as being a unsigned number or two’s complement number, it just a bunch of bits to it. And similarly, so we can go back and forth between chooses, comple unsigned, keeping the bit patterns the same. And so I’ll call that t to u when I go from sine to unsigned twos, complement to unsigned and similar. I’ll call it u to t if I go from unsigned to signed.<br>计算机本身不知道给定的位模式是什么，如果它是你认为的无符号数还是2的补数，它只是一堆位。类似地，我们可以在选择之间来回切换，保持位模式相同。因此，当我从正弦到无符号二时，我会将t称为u，从补充到无符号和类似。如果我从无符号转到有符号，我会称它为u到t。</p><p>发言人   38:09<br>And as I mentioned, the difference for the numbers where the high order bit is a one will be by a factor 2 to the w, where w is the word size of the word. And so this can be thought of as a function. Where?<br>正如我所提到的，高位为1的数字之间的差异将是w的2倍，其中w是单词的单词大小。因此，这可以被看作是一个函数。在哪里？</p><p>发言人   38:37<br>Let me just dry it out.<br>让我把它擦干。</p><p>发言人   38:49<br>Over here with my 5 b numbers. This is? Two’s complement again. So that was the number -16. And then there’ll be some other negative numbers up to all ones. It the number negative one, and then I’ll have 0. And so forth, and then all up to. Going to run out of room? Plus 15, right? Just I. Got myself in trouble. Blackboard management is they didn’t teach me this school. So I’m going to. Use two boards at once here.<br>这里有我的5个b数字。这是什么？二是再次补充。这就是数字-16。然后会有一些其他负数，直到所有的一。如果数字是负一，那么我就得到0。以此类推，然后一切都由上而下。要跑出房间吗？加上15，对吧？只是我。让自己陷入了麻烦。黑板管理是他们没有在这所学校教我的。所以我要去。在这里同时使用两个板子。</p><p>发言人   40:05<br>Okay? What are you setting this up?<br>好吗？你是怎么安排的？</p><p>发言人   40:15<br>Okay, we’ll make it work. So now when we go from the Ttu function, then these numbers are going to just carry over, will get 0 up through 15. But now this number here will become positive 16.<br>好的，我们会让它起作用的。所以现在当我们从Ttu函数开始时，这些数字将只是延续，将从0上升到15。但现在这个数字将变成正数16。</p><p>发言人   40:44<br>And all ones. Will become positive 31. And so that’s what this picture is showing. Is it for the pink numbers are the ones that flip between negative and actually the largest of the positive numbers. And then the green numbers are the ones that stay the same because they’re leading bits are zeros.<br>所有的。将成为阳性31。这就是这张照片所展示的。粉色数字是在负数和实际最大的正数之间翻转的数字。绿色数字是保持不变的数字，因为它们的前导位是零。</p><p>发言人   41:17<br>So why does this matter? You never thought if you programmed in Python, say, or even Java, you don’t see that. And the reason is because C is one of the few languages where unsigned is actually an explicit data type. And so you can declare a value being unsigned. If you just say unsigned, what you’re really saying is unsigned int, or you can call something an unsigned care, an unsigned short, or an unsigned long. And you’re declaring in C that it should think about using this representation we show on the right when it’s working on those numbers. So that’s sort of one thing.<br>这有什么关系呢？你从来没有想过，如果你用Python编程，比如说，甚至是Java，你都看不到这一点。原因是因为C是少数几种实际上无符号是显式数据类型的语言之一。所以你可以声明一个无符号的值。如果你只是说unsigned，你真正说的是unsigned int，或者你可以称之为unsigned care、unsigned short或unsigned long。你在C中声明，在处理这些数字时，它应该考虑使用我们在右侧显示的这种表示。所以这是一件事。</p><p>发言人   42:07<br>It’s one thing if you declare a number and use it that way. But what gets people and often got you is if you declare something, if you have, in this case, something that’s declared as a tooth complement number x TX and you assign it a value u at y x, it’ll do an implicit casting, which is exactly based on this conversion that we’ve been talking about, and vice versa.<br>如果你声明一个数字并以这种方式使用它，那就是一回事。但是让人们经常得到的是，如果你声明了一些东西，在这种情况下，如果你有一些被声明为牙齿补码x TX的东西，并且你在y x处为它分配一个值u，它将进行隐式转换，这正是基于我们一直在谈论的这种转换，反之亦然。</p><p>发言人   42:40<br>This example, this goes through some examples that if I look at two numbers and I compare them, or actually I do any operation on them, I add them, divide them, anything implicitly, it will try to make these two be of the same type. And the way it will do that is to say, if both of them are ased, then I’ll treat them as assigned. Case if either of them is unsigned, then I’ll convert the other one to be an unsigned number and do the operation. And so in particular, this set of examples is imagine I’m comparing these.<br>在这个例子中，经过一些例子，如果我看两个数字并比较它们，或者实际上我对它们进行任何操作，我将它们相加，相除，任何隐式的东西，它都会尝试使这两个是相同类型。这样做的方式就是说，如果他们两个都被杀了，那么我会把他们视为指定的。如果其中一个是无符号的，那么我会将另一个转换为无符号数字并进行操作。特别地，想象一下我正在比较这些例子。</p><p>发言人   43:20<br>I’m saying these numbers are either equal, less or greater. What will the outcomes be? And the key to answering that question is to, first of all, figure out OK, is it assigned or an unsigned comparison? Should I convert one of these numbers to an either of these numbers to an unsigned form before I do it? And the rule is, if either argument is unsigned, then you’ve got to do it.<br>我是说这些数字要么相等，要么更少，要么更大。结果会是什么？回答这个问题的关键是，首先要弄清楚它是分配的还是无符号的比较？在我这样做之前，我应该将这些数字中的一个转换为这些数字中的任何一个转换为无符号形式吗？规则是，如果其中一个参数是无符号的，那么你必须这样做。</p><p>发言人   43:47<br>And as you see, when you put a u at the end, either a lowercase u or an uppercase u at the end of a numeric constant, you’re saying this is an unsigned value. So for example, if we compare 0 and 0 unsigned, they’re equal. And if we combine negative one, compare negative one to 0, we’ll get that the first one is less because negative one is less than 0. But what would happen with the next one when we compare negative one to an unsigned zero? Greater, right? So this is the surprise. And it has to do with.<br>正如你所看到的，当你把一个u放在数字常量的末尾，无论是小写的u还是大写的u，你就是在说这是一个无符号的值。例如，如果我们比较0和0无符号，它们是相等的。如果我们将负一个结合起来，将负一个与0进行比较，我们会得到第一个较小，因为负一个小于0。但是当我们将负1与无符号0进行比较时，下一个会发生什么？更大吧？这就是惊喜。这与。</p><p>发言人   44:41<br>A number that I erased. But we can still get it. Remember, this is negative one. But when I cast that to an unsigned number I’m flipping this from -60 into positive 16 and turning this into 31. I’m turning it into actually the largest number I can represent. And so it will be greater than 0. So it’s a little bit weird to think about. I took an unsigned zero, which after all, is just 0, and compared it to negative one. And it said, oh, you really meant 31, didn’t you? Or whatever word size we’re using. And so it said it’s greater. And basically the rest of these you can answer in a similar way.<br>一个被我擦掉的数字。但我们仍然可以得到它。请记住，这是负面的。但是当我将其转换为一个无符号数字时，我将其从-60翻转为正16并将其转换为31。我正在把它变成我能代表的最大数字。因此它将大于0。所以思考起来有点奇怪。我取了一个无符号的零，毕竟它只是0，并将其与负1进行比较。它说，哦，你真的是说31，不是吗？或者我们使用的任何单词大小。所以它说它更大。基本上，其余的你可以用类似的方式回答。</p><p>发言人   45:36<br>These two numbers are, this is query one smaller than this? No I’m sorry, this is a negative number. I compare those and the positive will be greater than the negative. I’ll tell you in a minute why this number is written this way. The next one, it’s the same pair of numbers, but you see it’s flipped and the reason is. That this number on the left is T max for?<br>这两个数字是，这个查询比这个小吗？不，对不起，这是一个负数。我比较它们，正面的会大于负面的。我马上告诉你为什么这个数字是这样写的。下一个，它是一对相同的数字，但你看到它被翻转了，原因是。左边的这个数字是T max吗？</p><p>发言人   46:22<br>So it’s the bit pattern in a 32 b number.<br>所以它是32 b数字中的位模式。</p><p>发言人   46:53<br>And to this day I’ve not memorized this number, by the way. But, and then this number is actually t min.<br>顺便说一下，直到今天我还没有记住这个数字。但是，然后这个数字实际上是t min。</p><p>发言人   47:18<br>And that when I subtract, you can think of it as this is negative t max -1. So that’s t min. So if I do an unsigned comparison between those two, now think of those, this weighting bit not being a negative weight, but a positive weight. You’ll see that this is a bigger number than this one.<br>当我减去时，你可以把它看作是负的t max -1。所以这就是t min。所以，如果我在这两者之间进行无符号比较，现在想想这些，这个加权位不是负权重，而是正权重。你会发现这个数字比这个更大。</p><p>发言人   47:44<br>And so it goes. That -1 is greater than -2 if they’re unsigned, because -1 is, you can think of it as converts into u max. It’ll be the biggest number possible. And -2 will. Would be 1 1 1, 1, 0.<br>就这样下去了。如果它们无符号，则-1大于-2，因为-1是，您可以将其视为转换为u max。这将是最大的数字。和-2将。将是1 1，1，0。</p><p>发言人   48:20<br>So that can get fairly confusing. One final quirk this way of writing this number is there’s a little side in the book about it. If you write the number as you’d expect to as minus blah, blah, blah, 6 and 48. It will actually get the C compiler gets kind of confused by that for obscure reasons. One other thing I should point out that it’s a property that I don’t think we cover well enough here. Well, let me see.<br>这可能会变得相当混乱。这样写这个数字的最后一个怪癖是，书中有一个关于它的小方面。如果你按照你期望的那样写下数字-等等，等等，6和48。它实际上会让C编译器因为一些模糊的原因而感到困惑。还有一件事我应该指出，这是一项我认为我们在这里没有充分涵盖的财产。好的，让我看看。</p><p>发言人   49:05<br>There’s a few things that the slides don’t really cover here, and I don’t know why not, I like to point out.<br>这里的幻灯片没有真正涵盖一些事情，我不知道为什么不，我想指出。</p><p>发言人   49:17<br>So they’re kind of useful properties to keep track of.<br>所以它们是跟踪的有用属性。</p><p>发言人   49:29<br>Is that you notice that if you look at the absolute value of T max? And you compare it to the absolute value of t min. That it’s off by one? So the number is more negative. The smallest negative number is more negative than the largest positive number is positive. And the reason for that actually is fairly simple, if you think about it, is that. The cases where you have zeros. Include the number 0.<br>你注意到，如果你看T max的绝对值吗？并将其与t min的绝对值进行比较。它已经被一个关闭了吗？所以这个数字更负。最小的负数比最大的正数更负。如果你仔细想想，其实原因相当简单，就是这样。当你有零的情况下。包括数字0。</p><p>发言人   50:24<br>So you can see it better. And there’s two to the half year ranges occupied by those numbers. And the negative numbers are all negative.<br>这样你就可以看得更清楚。这些数字占据了两到半年的范围。负数都是负数。</p><p>发言人   50:45<br>And so the other half of the range is in there. And the point is that you had to use one of these for 0. And so only there was one left, one less value left over. And that’s why you end up with this sort of asymmetry. And this asymmetry is the cause of no end of pain in various ways, like a few. The classic example is if you implement absolute value.<br>所以范围的另一半在那里。重点是你必须使用其中一个来表示0。所以只剩下了一个，剩下的价值少了一个。这就是为什么你最终会得到这种不对称。这种不对称性以各种方式引起了无止的疼痛，就像一些方式一样。经典的例子是，如果你实现绝对值。</p><p>发言人   51:36<br>Like, so what does this return for t min? Yeah, it returns t min. We’ll talk a little bit. Basically, when you try to negate this number that’s here. You’ll end up with it back again.<br>像，那么这对t-min有什么回报呢？是的，它返回t min。我们稍微聊一下。基本上，当你试图否定这里的这个数字时。你最终会再次得到它。</p><p>发言人   52:11<br>So it’s always a corner case. And whenever we do program testing, we always throw that case in there to break things. You said, well, like he, you said earlier about, I. Yes?<br>所以这总是一个角落。每当我们进行程序测试时，我们总是把那个情况扔进去破坏事情。你说，就像他一样，你之前说的，我。是吗？</p><p>发言人   52:36<br>No, they do that if you ever look at the. In the C constants, they use this as a way of representing t min, and they do it for that reason. You see, it’s exactly, and they put parentheses around it, president’s problem. But you see that number that in 647, that’s T max. And so basically, it’s just saying that t min is minus t max -1 question.<br>不，如果你看到他们，他们就会这样做。在C常量中，他们使用这个作为表示t min的方式，并且他们出于这个原因这样做。你看，这确实是总统的问题，他们在后面加了括号。但是你可以看到647中的数字，那就是T max。所以基本上，它只是说t min是-t max -1问题。</p><p>发言人   53:22<br>Yes, so comparison is just a special case of the more general one, which is addition, subtraction, all of those. If either argument is unsigned, then it interprets the remaining one as being unsigned, It turns out, and we’ll get into this more next time as far as bit patterns, but it turns out at the bit level, addition, subtraction, even multiplication are the same, whether it’s an unsigned number or two’s complement number. So we’ll talk about that more next time. And the other thing to observe sort of property.<br>是的，所以比较只是更一般的一种特殊情况，即加法、减法。如果其中一个参数是无符号的，那么它会将剩余的一个解释为无符号的，事实证明，我们下次会更深入地讨论位模式，但事实证明，在位级别上，加法，减法，甚至乘法都是相同的，无论它是无符号数还是2的补码数。所以下次我们会更多地谈论这个。另一件事是观察某种性质。</p><p>发言人   54:21<br>You saw that umax is sort of like? Twice t max plus one.<br>你看到umax有点像吗？两次t最大值加1。</p><p>发言人   54:36<br>So before Mas was 15 in our 5 b numbers and that’s again, not too hard to figure out. Here’s one way to think about it. T max is a 0 followed by a bunch of ones. And if I want to double that number, I basically shift it left by one position, and that would end up with a 0 here. So this is T max, and this is twice t max. And now if I add a 1 to that I’ll just set this bit to one and get this. So there’s various ways you can think about it, but that’s one way to do it.<br>所以在我们的5 b数字中Mas之前是15，这并不难弄清楚。这是思考它的一种方式。T max是一个0后面跟着一堆1。如果我想将这个数字翻倍，我基本上会将它向左移动一个位置，最终会得到一个0。这是T max，这是两倍t max。现在，如果我加一个1，我只需要将这个位设置为1，就可以得到这个。所以有各种各样的方法可以考虑它，但这是一种方法。</p><p>发言人   55:43<br>There’s one other thing that I wanted to mention too. This can get you into a lot of trouble. Programming Y, so let me just show you what I mean.<br>还有一件事我也想提一下。这可能会给你带来很多麻烦。编程Y，那么让我向你展示我的意思。</p><p>发言人   56:10<br>So imagine I wanted to. Go backwards through an array. So I write a loop of the form for I equals n -1. I is greater than. Or equal to zero, I minus, minus. And then I do something with array element A of I. I’ll just call some function of whatever you want to do in that loop. So that’s a pretty standard pattern in a loop, right? Except that you write this greater equal to 1, 0. You can imagine various uses for that.<br>所以想象一下我想要。在数组中向后移动。所以我写了一个形式为I等于n -1的循环。我大于。或等于零，I-，-。然后我对I的数组元素A做了一些事情。我会在循环中调用任何你想做的函数。所以这是一个相当标准的循环模式，对吧？除了你写的大于等于1，0。你可以想象它的各种用途。</p><p>发言人   57:01<br>So here’s an interesting question. I were declared as being unsigned. Because it’s array index, after all. What will happen with this loop? Yeah? What’s that, yes? So the loop will go forever. What would most likely happen is I would go from being 0 to being u max, and that’s a really big number. And the ray’d most likely cause a memory fault because it’s so far out of bounds. But the point is, it wouldn’t do what you want. It wouldn’t stop where you want it to. And because of the simple reason that I, of course, I is always going to be greater or equal to 0, because it’s an unsigned number.<br>这里有一个有趣的问题。我被宣布为无符号。因为它毕竟是数组索引。这个循环会发生什么？是吗？那是什么，对吗？所以循环将永远持续下去。最有可能发生的情况是我从0变成u max，这是一个非常大的数字。而射线很可能会导致记忆故障，因为它已经超出了界限。但关键是，它不会做你想做的事。它不会停在你想要的地方。原因很简单，当然，I总是大于或等于0，因为它是一个无符号数字。</p><p>发言人   57:58<br>One, you’d say OK, well, you should have figured that one out. It can be more subtle, though. If you have something like int I. And then we say something like, let me just change it here a little bit. So this will be.<br>你会说，好吧，你应该已经想出了那个。不过，这可能更加微妙。如果你有像int I这样的东西。然后我们说，让我在这里稍微改动一下。这将是如此。</p><p>发言人   58:44<br>Something like this where I’m mixing metaphors here, I have to confess. But if you use the standard term size of which is the way you get how many bytes it takes to represent some given data type, so this will actually be the number one. So it’s not the same loop as before. But imagine I’m sort of mixing in my arithmetic and making use of some of these built in forms. What would happen with this group?<br>像这样的事情，我在这里混合隐喻，我必须承认。但是如果你使用标准的术语大小，它是你获取表示某种给定数据类型所需的字节数的方式，那么这实际上将是第一。所以它不像以前那样循环。但想象一下，我在算术中混用了一些内置的形式。这个群体会发生什么？</p><p>发言人   59:24<br>Yes exactly, so size of returns an unsigned value. It’s not actually a function, it’s a built in. The result of size of is considered to be unsigned.<br>完全是，所以大小返回无符号值。它实际上不是一个功能，而是一个内置的。size的结果被认为是无符号的。</p><p>发言人   59:39<br>Just like I was saying, if you have a sine value and an unsigned in any kind of arithmetic, it’ll treat the combination of the two as unsigned. And so it will actually do an unsigned comparison here, which is almost surely not what you wanted. And this will just.<br>就像我说的，如果你有一个正弦值和一个无符号的算术，它会将这两者的组合视为无符号。因此，它实际上将在这里进行未签名的比较，这几乎肯定不是您想要的。而这将只是。</p><p>发言人   01:00:02<br>You’ll look at this program and you won’t have any idea why it’s crashing. You’ll be so confused. And that’s the kind of thing you have to know. It’s one of the quirks of C that probably if they could start over again and redesign it, they’d come up with some different set of conventions than they did. But unfortunately, it’s way too late for that. So this is just one of those things you have to remember. But yes, my point is there’s some subtleties in C about this business of sed versus unsigned arithmetic.<br>你会看到这个程序，但你不知道它为什么会崩溃。你会很困惑。这就是你必须知道的事情。这是C的怪癖之一，如果他们能重新开始并重新设计它，他们可能会提出一些与以前不同的约定。但不幸的是，现在已经太晚了。所以这只是你必须记住的事情之一。但是，是的，我的观点是，关于sed与无符号算术的业务，C中有一些微妙之处。</p><p>发言人   01:00:40<br>Okay, so now let’s look at a sort of final class of operations, which is, suppose I have a number that’s so many bits, say 8 b, and I want to now expand it to be a 16 b number. There’s a fairly cute rule for doing this that’s called sine extension. I’m talking about twos complement numbers here of how you go take a number, make it bigger without changing its value. The basic rule is you do it by copying the sine bit to the left. So let me give you the intuition behind it.<br>好的，现在让我们来看一种最终的操作类，也就是说，假设我有一个位数，比如8 b，我现在想将它扩展为一个16 b的数字。有一个相当可爱的规则来做这件事，叫做正弦扩展。我在这里谈论的是二补码，即如何在不改变其值的情况下将一个数字变大。基本规则是通过向左复制正弦位来完成。让我给你背后的直觉。</p><p>发言人   01:01:33<br>So let’s look at some 4 b values.<br>让我们来看看一些4 b的值。</p><p>发言人   01:01:45<br>Well, it’s pretty straightforward if the leading bit is a 0. I’m just going to do a left shift and then fill in.<br>如果前导位是0，那就非常简单了。我只是要做一个左移，然后补上。</p><p>发言人   01:02:02<br>Right, wait, what am I talking about? I got ahead of myself. I’m talking about something totally different. No, sorry, the same number. I’m not changing the number. I’m keeping it the same, so I just added a 0 to the lead and this will be the number 6 still.<br>对，等等，我在说什么？我超前了。我说的是完全不同的东西。不，对不起，是同一个号码。我不会换号码的。我保持不变，所以我只是在引线上加了一个0，这将是数字6。</p><p>发言人   01:02:20<br>This is plus 4 plus 2 equals 6. But now let’s think about it as where there’s a leading sign bit. So this is -8 plus 4 plus 2 is equal to -2. So now look at what happens if I copy that sine bit over one position. So this becomes a 1, 1, 1, 1, 0. And what happens is this is now has value plus 8 here, but the sine bit has value -16. And then this is still plus 2 and plus 4. And so it will still equal -2.<br>这是加4加2等于6。但现在让我们把它想象成一个前导符号位。所以这是-8加4加2等于-2。所以现在看看如果我在一个位置上复制那个正弦位会发生什么。所以这变成了1，0。发生的情况是，现在这里的值加8，但正弦位的值为-16。然后这仍然是 + 2和 + 4。因此它仍然等于-2。</p><p>发言人   01:03:17<br>So here’s what happened before. My sine bit had a weight of -8, and my new sine has a weight of -16. But I converted that old sine bit into a positive number, which is plus 8, and those two canceled out. You combine those two and you get minus A, which is exactly this. So you see by sort of copying that sine bit over, giving it twice the way, turning it, what was the sine bit into a positive number, you don’t change the net effect of the sum.<br>这就是之前发生的事情。我的正弦波位的权重为-8，而我的新正弦波位的权重为-16。但是我把那个旧的正弦位转换成了一个正数，也就是加8，然后这两个被抵消了。你把这两者结合起来，得到-A，也就是这个。所以你通过复制那个正弦位，给它两倍的方式，把它，正弦位变成一个正数，你不会改变总和的净效应。</p><p>发言人   01:03:58<br>And that’s exactly the idea of extension. Just keep going with that as far as you need to carry it over. And each time you’re doing it, you’re effectively doing this business of of coming up with a pair of bits that end up with the same value as this original bit. So that’s the idea of sine extension. And you’ll see that a lot. Bit patterns, especially if you see a bit pattern that starts with a bunch of F’s.<br>这正是扩展的想法。只要继续下去，直到你需要把它带过去。每次你这样做的时候，你都在有效地进行这项业务，即想出一对与原始位具有相同值的位。这就是正弦扩展的想法。你会经常看到这一点。位模式，特别是如果你看到一个以一堆F开头的位模式。</p><p>发言人   01:04:40<br>What that tells you, remember f is just four ones.<br>这告诉你的是，记住f只是四个一。</p><p>发言人   01:04:50<br>Is a whole bunch of leading ones that tells you the number is negative, negative, but not too far away from 0. And you’ll see that over and over again. You’ll see bit patterns. And you just sort of, when you see meeting F’s, you say, oh, that’s a negative number. I know what’s going on there. And so here’s some examples. But you can see the main idea is you carry that leading bit from the 16 b case over, make as many copies as you need to expand the word size.<br>是一堆领先的数字，告诉你数字是负数，负数，但离0不太远。你会一遍又一遍地看到这一点。你会看到比特模式。当你看到遇见F的时候，你会说，哦，那是一个负数。我知道那里发生了什么。这里有一些例子。但是你可以看到主要的想法是你从16 b的情况下开始，根据需要制作尽可能多的副本来扩展单词大小。</p><p>发言人   01:05:29<br>And I should mention with the unsigned case, obviously, you just want to fill in with zeros.<br>我应该提到未签名的情况，显然，你只想用零填充。</p><p>发言人   01:05:41<br>Do we talk about truncation? Is there any any missing slides in this?<br>我们在谈论截断吗？这个幻灯片有缺失的吗？</p><p>发言人   01:05:52<br>A final case to look at is what happens if I make something shorter? So if I had my unsigned number from before.<br>最后一个需要考虑的案例是，如果我把东西缩短会发生什么？如果我有之前的无符号号码。</p><p>发言人   01:06:11<br>If this were an unsigned number, this would be 1, 2, 8, 16, 1417, right? What if I decided, oh, I can’t afford? For a bit. I don’t have enough money. For 5 b. I’m only going to give you 4. Well, you basically just dropped the most significant bit. And you get 8 plus 2 plus one, which is 11, which is 9. And the relation there is that it’s like modular arithmetic.<br>如果这是一个无符号数字，那么它将是1，2，8，16，1417，对吧？如果我决定，哦，我负担不起怎么办？有一点。我没有足够的钱。5个b。我只会给你4。好吧，你基本上只是掉了最重要的一点。你得到8加2加1，也就是11，也就是9。那里的关系就像模块化算术一样。</p><p>发言人   01:07:03<br>Mod 16, you’re taking no. Thank you? It’s the risk of improvising. So 27.<br>Mod 16，你要不要。谢谢？这是即兴创作的风险。所以27。</p><p>发言人   01:07:26<br>And 11? Yeah, that makes sense. Difference is 16, I knew that. Okay, excuse me for my stumbling.<br>And 11?是的，这很感知。差异是16，我知道。好的，请原谅我的绊倒。</p><p>发言人   01:07:42<br>The point being that when you drop this thing effectively, you’re just taking the mod some power of two of it. Like I mentioned, the case where you’re taking modulo 8, if you just keep only the lowest order of 3 b, you’re having a module 8. Now, one, really, this is sort of logical in the unsigned world. Modular arithmetic is something that was understood by the ancient Greeks, so not too far away from human experience, but it gets a little bit funky if. Dealing with two these complement numbers because this is now. 1011 -5, right? But this number, if I just drop this bit. And call it a 4 b number. This now becomes -8, 2, and 1.<br>关键是，当你有效地放下这个东西时，你只是在利用它的一些力量。就像我提到的，在你取模8的情况下，如果你只保留最低的3 b的顺序，你就有一个模块8。现在，第一，真的，这在未签名的世界里是合乎逻辑的。模块化算术是古希腊人所理解的东西，因此与人类经验不太遥远，但如果它变得有点古怪。处理这两个补数，因为这是现在。1011 -5，对吧？但是这个数字，如果我只是放下这一点。称之为4 B数字。这现在变成了-8、2和1。</p><p>发言人   01:08:54<br>Which is -5?<br>哪个是-5？</p><p>发言人   01:09:01<br>You say, how’d that happen? Well, actually, if you look at it, this is just what you’d get by S extension, right? So this wasn’t a very interesting example. But if we changed it to this?<br>你说，这是怎么发生的？嗯，实际上，如果你看一下，这正是你通过S扩展得到的，对吗？所以这不是一个非常有趣的例子。但是如果我们把它改成这个？</p><p>发言人   01:09:27<br>Then this would be -13. And this would be plus 3. And. It’s a little harder to think about in terms of modular arithmetic, The way you basically have to think about it is, well, you know, this is -13, but it’s really kind of like 27 and 27 mod 16 is sort of like, or no, this isn’t 20.<br>那么这将是-13。这将是加3。而且。从模块化算术的角度考虑有点困难，你基本上要考虑的方式是，你知道，这是-13，但它真的有点像27和27 mod 16有点像，或者不，这不是20。</p><p>发言人   01:10:01<br>We changed our number, right? So this is really kind of like 19 and 19 mod 16 is 3, and this is 3. So you can sort of do it by coming back around to it. But it’s not some arithmetic property that would jump out at you as being something logical. But that happens all the time. And it’s very common for numbers to get truncated for one reason or another.<br>我们换了号码，对吧？所以这真的有点像19和19 mod 16是3，这是3。所以你可以通过回到它身边来做到这一点。但这并不是一些算术属性会突然出现在你身上，成为合乎逻辑的东西。但这种情况经常发生。由于某种原因数字被截断是很常见的。</p><p>发言人   01:10:30<br>And you can see that you can have a negative number become a positive number. You can have a positive number become a negative number, and all kinds of goofy stuff can happen. And we’ll see plenty of examples of that when we look at arithmetic. So that’s. That is what I want to cover for today. And we’ll cover the other arithmetic operations on Tuesday. So thank you very much.<br>你可以看到你可以让一个负数变成正数。你可以让一个正数变成负数，各种愚蠢的事情都可能发生。当我们看算术时，我们会看到很多这样的例子。就是这样。这就是我今天想要涵盖的。我们将在周二介绍其他算术运算。非常感谢。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>深入理解计算机系统 001-课程概览</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/12/15213-001/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/12/15213-001/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<embed src="/images/15213-001.pdf" type="application/pdf" width="100%" height="600px" /><p>发言人   00:00<br>Hello everyone I’d like to welcome you all to this Falls. This term’s instance of this course is officially either 15 to 13 from computer science or 18 to 13 from electrical and computer engineering. But a large number of the people enrolled in this course are in one called 513, which is for graduate students.<br>大家好，欢迎大家来到这个学期。这学期的课程正式名称要么是计算机科学的15到13，要么是电气和计算机工程的18到13。但是，参加这门课程的很多人都在一个名为513的课程中，这是针对研究生的。</p><span id="more"></span><p>发言人   00:24<br>And to be totally honest, you’re not supposed to be here because you’re supposed to watch the videos, the lectures by video later. But we’re not checking any cards. So I don’t really know who you are. Anyways, this course is, as you can see, a very popular course on campus. We have over 700, 700, 600 shouldn’t exaggerate. Students on campus enrolled in one of those three versions of the course, which if you think about a university the size of CMU, it’s like about 5% of the total student population.<br>而且说实话，你不应该在这里，因为你应该观看视频，稍后通过视频进行讲座。但我们不会检查任何卡片。所以我真的不知道你是谁。无论如何，正如你所看到的，这门课程在校园里是非常受欢迎的课程。我们有超过700，700，600不应该夸大。校园内的学生就读于这三个版本的课程之一，如果你考虑一个CMU大小的大学，大约占学生总数的5%。</p><p>发言人   01:06<br>So we’re very glad to have you here. And this game is too high. I think we overdid the game. Try that, that’s better. So my name is Randy Bryant and my co instructor is Da O’hare. And those names might be familiar if you have been to the bookstore because the book was written by us and we actually wrote this book.<br>所以我们很高兴你在这里。而且这个游戏太高了。我认为我们把游戏做得太过人了。试试那个，那更好。所以我的名字是兰迪·布莱恩特，我的联合导师是达奥黑尔。如果你去过书店，这些名字可能会很熟悉，因为这本书是我们写的，而我们实际上写了这本书</p><p>发言人   01:36<br>We started 213 as a course in 1998. And I know that you were children then and all that stuff Out of response for a new type of course, that you’ll see today that sort of gives people in depth understanding of systems, but more from a high level of or programmer’s perspective. And we’ll talk some about the philosophy of the course later.<br>我们在1998年开始了213门课程。我知道你当时还是孩子，所有这些都是出于对一种新型课程的回应，你今天会看到这种课程让人们对系统有了深入的理解，但更多是从高层次或程序员的角度来看。我们稍后会谈论这门课程的理念。</p><p>发言人   02:02<br>So this book, as you saw, just came out its third edition last March. And that’s the required text for the course. And there is nothing you can do to avoid buying that book.<br>所以正如你所看到的，这本书在去年三月刚刚出版了第三版。这是本课程的必修教材。你无法避免购买那本书。</p><p>发言人   02:17<br>And it’s not because we’re greedy, actually. We take the money we get from royalty for students in this course or any CMU course, and we donate it to CMU. So we’re not actually making any money out of you buying the book. But it’s a simple reality that the new version is different than the old. We expect you to be using the new version. There are no electronic copies, there are no pirated versions, so you basically have to buy the book. And I don’t really apologize for that because I know you or your parents or somebody is paying a lot of money for you to be here. And so the price of the book is really a relatively small amount relative to that.<br>事实上，这并不是因为我们贪婪。我们将从版税中获得的钱用于本课程或任何CMU课程的学生，并将其捐赠给CMU。所以我们实际上并没有从你购买这本书中赚钱。但这是一个简单的现实，新版本与旧版本不同。我们希望您使用新版本。没有电子副本，没有盗版，所以你基本上必须购买这本书。我并不为此道歉，因为我知道你或你的父母或某人为你在这里付出了很多钱。因此，这本书的价格相对于这个价格来说确实是相对较小的。</p><p>发言人   03:03<br>And this course, by the way, is, is not some courses there. Oh, yeah, this book, you might want to look at it once in a while, but actually the course has nothing to do with it.<br>顺便说一下，这门课程并不是那里的一些课程。哦，是的，这本书，你可能想偶尔看看，但实际上这门课与它无关。</p><p>发言人   03:13<br>This course, the book and the course are one. They’re very tied together. They’ll be parts of the book that we don’t go into. All the details that are in the book sometimes, but we expect you to be able to figure it out. And so really the course in the book are tied together and they very much the progress of the course, the topics covered, how it’s covered, everything about it is consistent with the book.<br>这门课程，这本书和这门课程是一体的。他们非常紧密地联系在一起。它们将成为这本书的一部分，我们不会进入其中。书中的所有细节有时会出现，但我们希望你能够理解。因此，书中的课程是紧密联系在一起的，课程的进展、涵盖的主题、涵盖的方式以及有关课程的一切都与书中的内容非常一致。</p><p>发言人   03:45<br>And we wrote the book because of the course. Think of them as course notes. So, and the reason why we are teaching this term, by the way, we haven’t taught together in several years, but because this is the first rollout of this book, and not only is it being used here, but it’s actually used by about 250 schools around the world. And many of those people are also going through the same activities of teaching from this new edition for the first time. So we wanted to make sure all the material for the course was sort of put in order and things because other universities and other colleges use this material, the supporting material we’ve developed. So that’s course today as the first lecture, we’re sort of doing a tag team here. I’ll talk the high level, what the course is about, what the main themes are, and Dave will talk more about the logistics. So we refer the saying we have when.<br>我们因为课程而写了这本书。把它们想象成课程笔记。所以，我们教这个学期的原因，顺便说一下，我们已经好几年没有一起教了，但是因为这是这本书的第一次推出，它不仅在这里被使用，而且实际上被全球大约250所学校使用。其中许多人也正在经历与新版相同的教学活动。所以我们想确保这门课程的所有材料都井井有条，因为其他大学和学院都在使用我们开发的支持材料。这是今天的第一堂课，我们在这里组建了一个标签团队。我将谈论高级别的课程，课程内容是什么，主题是什么，戴夫将更多地谈论物流。所以我们指的是我们的说法。</p><p>发言人   04:55<br>The very first time I typed the number of this course into a text editor, I realized I’ve typed those five digits many times in my career because it’s the zip code of CMU 1 5 2 1 3. So that’s where we come up with the same.<br>第一次将本课程的编号输入文本编辑器时，我意识到在我的职业生涯中，我已经多次输入这五个数字，因为它是CMU 1 5 2 1 3的邮政编码。所以这就是我们想出相同的方法的地方。</p><p>发言人   05:17<br>So there’s a few things about this course. For the most part, you know, in your normal undergraduate curriculum, when you’ve learned programming, you’ve been very much separated from the realities of the machine. You just think about code. Just you put some text into some little box somehow, and outcomes of behavior that hopefully is what you intended the program to do. The purpose of this course is to give you enough understanding of what that box is doing when it executes your code and through that to help you become better what you’re trying to do.<br>所以关于这门课程有几件事情。大多数情况下，你知道，在你正常的本科课程中，当你学习编程时，你已经与机器的现实非常分离。你只需要考虑代码。你只需在某个小盒子里放一些文本，然后得到一些行为结果，希望这就是你想要程序做的事情。本课程的目的是让您足够了解该框在执行代码时的作用，并通过它来帮助您变得更好，您正在尝试做什么。</p><p>发言人   06:02<br>So some of the outcomes is there’s really two types of outcomes from this course. One is that if this is the only systems course you ever take in your whole life, you will get useful material from it. You will learn tools, tricks, methods that will help you if you ever are involved in software development, large scale software engineering projects, systems, hardware design, any aspect of computer technology, this will help you be better at what you do. You’ll understand what programs do, how they work, what the machines support them do, why sometimes they work really well, and why sometimes they don’t work so well. It also is intended as a sort of stepping stone into a whole number of other courses at CMU that will give you more in depth understanding of computer technology, but are sort of specialized by topical area, whether it’s computer networking or operating systems or embedded systems where you’ll take the sort of ideas from this course and be able to then learn in a somewhat narrower but deeper sense what’s really going on. And so it really is trying to serve those two goals of making you more effective, giving you useful ideas and tools right away, but also preparing you for waiter courses.<br>因此，这门课程的一些结果实际上有两种类型的结果。一是如果这是你一生中唯一的系统课程，你将从中获得有用的材料。如果你参与软件开发、大规模软件工程项目、系统、硬件设计、计算机技术的任何方面，你将学习工具、技巧和方法，这将有助于你更好地完成你的工作。你会理解程序的作用，它们是如何工作的，机器支持它们做什么，为什么有时它们工作得很好，以及为什么有时它们工作得不好。它还旨在作为CMU其他课程的踏脚石，让您更深入地了解计算机技术，但这些课程在主题领域上是专业化的，无论是计算机网络、操作系统还是嵌入式系统，你都将从这门课程中汲取一些想法，然后能够以更狭窄但更深入的感知了解实际发生的事情。因此，它确实在努力实现这两个目标: 让你更有效率，立即给你有用的想法和工具，同时也让你为服务员的课程做好准备。</p><p>发言人   07:30<br>So one way we talk about this is sort of what kind of stuff will you learn from this course is to go through a series of what we call great realities, places where sort of computers meet up, real life computers meet up against your expectations, and maybe they’re not quite the same. So one of them is, and the first part of the course is going to take a fairly detailed look how numbers are represented in computers. And you’ll learn some things that are on one hand surprising, and on another hand will start to make sense when you understand it better.<br>所以我们谈论这个问题的一种方式是，你将从这门课程中学到什么样的东西，是通过一系列我们称之为伟大现实的地方，在这些地方，计算机会相遇，现实生活中的计算机会与你的期望相遇，也许它们并不完全相同。所以其中一个是，本课程的第一部分将相当详细地了解数字在计算机中的表示方式。你会学到一些一方面令人惊讶的东西，另一方面当你更好地理解它时会开始感知。</p><p>发言人   08:06<br>So a simple case is for numbers. I don’t know when it was, but it was probably in about 8th grade algebra that I learned that if you square a number, it will be at least 0, if it’s not an imaginary number. So either an integer or a real number, you’d expect to square and it to be a positive value, or perhaps 0. And that’s actually generally true with float through representation of floating point numbers. But with integer or ints, the computer representation of integers, it’s not so clear.<br>一个简单的案例就是数字。我不知道它是什么时候，但可能是在大约8年级的代数中，我学到了如果你平方一个数字，如果它不是虚数，它至少会是0。所以无论是整数还是实数，你都期望平方并且它是一个正值，或者可能是0。这实际上通常适用于浮点数到浮点数的表示。但是对于整数或整数的计算机表示形式，它不是那么清楚。</p><p>发言人   08:50<br>So for example, if you square 40000 on most computers, then you’ll get whatever that should be as you’d expect. But what if you square 50000, So you could do this in your head. But I actually built into this laptop as a computer. So I’m going to go ahead and use it.<br>因此，例如，如果您在大多数计算机上平方40000，那么您将获得应有的任何预期。但是，如果你平方50000，这样你就可以在脑海中做到这一点。但实际上我将这台笔记本电脑内置为电脑。所以我将继续使用它。</p><p>发言人   09:17<br>Let me just size this a little better for you here. And use a tool, which on Unix systems is called No, it’s going on. This is working before. Try again? Here we are on Linux systems is called Gdb, but on a Macintosh OSX it’s called lldb, but they’re pretty much the same program. You will get to know this program really, really well this term. So like I said, if you square 40000, you’ll get what you’d expect, but let’s change this to 50000.<br>让我在这里给你稍微调整一下这个的大小。并使用一个在Unix系统上被称为 “不” 的工具，它正在进行中。这是以前的工作。再试一次？这里我们在Linux系统上被称为Gdb，但在Macintosh OSX上它被称为ldb，但它们几乎是相同的程序。这个学期你会非常非常了解这个项目。就像我说的，如果你平方40000，你会得到你所期望的，但让我们把它改为50000。</p><p>发言人   10:18<br>And you get a very peculiar number that doesn’t look anything like you’d expect 50000 squared to be. And in fact, it’s negative. And so that might just seem like, well, there must be a mistake or something. No, that’s just the way it is. This computer is expecting numbers to be represented as 32 b values. And the bit pattern that you get when you do this multiplication happens to be the representation of a negative number. So that’s an example of where your normal expectations about integer arithmetic may or may not hold. On the other hand, there are some places.<br>你会得到一个非常奇特的数字，看起来与你预期的50000平方完全不同。事实上，这是负面的。因此，这可能看起来像是，肯定有错误或其他什么。不，事情就是这样。此计算机期望数字表示为32 b值。当你进行这个乘法时，你得到的位模式恰好是一个负数的表示。这是一个例子，说明您对整数算术的正常期望可能成立，也可能成立。另一方面，有一些地方。</p><p>发言人   11:09<br>Like if I try to do the same thing, multiplying 300 by 400 by 500 by 600, then all of a sudden I also get a number that clearly is not what you’d expect, because the same thing has happened. I’ve gotten an overflow. It happens that it’s overflowed to a value that’s positive, not negative. But it still is obviously not the integer product of those four numbers.<br>就像如果我尝试做同样的事情，用300乘以400乘以500乘以600，然后突然间我也得到了一个显然不是你期望的数字，因为同样的事情已经发生了。我已经溢出了。碰巧它溢出到一个正的值，而不是负的值。但显然它仍然不是这四个数字的整数乘积。</p><p>发言人   11:32<br>On the other hand, one thing you’ll find is even though this arithmetic is not normal sort of integer arithmetic, it actually has some well behaved properties. So for example, if you look at. What I’ve done is I just moved the 300 around from the beginning of the product of the product. And so now if you think about how associativism and commutativity works I’m basically multiplying these four numbers in a different order. But what you see is you get the same funny looking result no matter how you do it. So what you can say from this is integer arithmetic is commutative and associative. So it obeys some of the conventional mathematical properties. It just isn’t what you’d expect it to be.<br>另一方面，你会发现，尽管这种算术不是普通的整数算术，但它实际上具有一些良好的性质。例如，如果你看。我所做的是，我刚刚从产品的开始就移动了300。所以现在如果你考虑一下结合性和交换性是如何工作的，我基本上是以不同的顺序乘以这四个数字。但你看到的是，无论你怎么做，你都会得到同样有趣的结果。所以你可以说整数算术是交换和联合的。因此，它遵循一些传统的数学属性。这不是你所期望的。</p><p>发言人   12:32<br>A normal sort of mathematical integer arithmetic so. The cartoon here. Shows an example that’s a similar possibility to get to it?<br>一种普通的数学整数算术。这里的漫画。展示了一个类似可能性的例子，可以达到这个目标吗？</p><p>发言人   13:00<br>I guess it comes at the end. So then the next question is, is addition associative?<br>我想它会在最后出现。那么下一个问题是，加法是联合加法吗？</p><p>发言人   13:07<br>Can you order the numbers? And as you probably might have figured, both the integer arithmetic, even though it has this potential for overflow, it is associative and it’s commutative too. But for floats, it’s not really quite the same because the range of values you can get in floating point are so extreme that some numbers kind of disappear on you. So the example I’ll show without having to use a computer to do it is if you take a big number and subtract it from itself, you’ll get 0. So if you add that to 3.14, you’ll get 3.14. But if you take those two numbers and you reorder how you combine them, so that 3.14 compared to -10 to the 20th is so insignificant, that result gets turned into -10 to the 20th. And you add that to 10 to the 20th, and you end up with 0. So it’s not associative.<br>你能订购号码吗？而且正如您可能已经想到的那样，整数算术尽管有可能溢出，但它是联合的，也是交换的。但对于浮点数来说，它并不完全相同，因为在浮点数中可以获得的值范围非常极端，以至于一些数字在你身上消失了。所以我将展示的例子是，如果你从一个大数中减去它自己，你会得到0。所以如果你把它加到3.14，你会得到3.14。但是如果你拿这两个数字并重新排序如何组合它们，那么3.14相对于-10的20是如此微不足道，那么结果就会变成-10的20。然后你把这个加到20的10上，最后得到的是0。所以它不是联想的。</p><p>发言人   14:11<br>And so what you see is.<br>所以你所看到的是。</p><p>发言人   14:16<br>Both these number systems have some peculiarities, and it all comes down to the fact that they use finite representations of things that are potentially infinite in their expanse. And so there’s some compromises in how those work and what the compromise is. You can overflow an integer and run out of room. And in floating point numbers, you have round off problems where you sort of drop the digits that aren’t significant. You can also overflow floating point, the more common problem is round-off.<br>这两个数系都有一些特点，这一切都归结于它们使用有限的事物表示，这些事物在它们的空间中可能是无限的。因此，在这些工作方式和妥协是什么方面存在一些妥协。你可以溢出一个整数并耗尽空间。而在浮点数中，你会遇到舍入问题，会丢弃不重要的数字。你也可以溢出浮点运算，更常见的问题是舍入。</p><p>发言人   14:49<br>So this is shown in this cartoon, this idea of overflow of somebody counting sheep, which in the us is in English language at least, a way to fall asleep. And when he or she goes from 32767 and then increment set by one, gets -32768. And we’ll see exactly why that happens. But basically, the numbers are going up to the larger value it represent. And then when it goes one more, it becomes a negative number. So these are really important things to understand.<br>所以在这幅漫画中，有人数羊的想法溢出，在美国至少在英语中是一种入睡的方式。当他或她从32767开始，然后以1为增量设置时，会得到-32768。我们会看到为什么会发生这种情况。但基本上，这些数字正在上升到它所代表的更大的价值。然后当它再多一个时，它就变成了负数。这些都是需要理解的非常重要的事情。</p><p>发言人   15:29<br>I mean, 90% of the time, maybe you can just get by writing programs and not worrying about whether your numbers are going to exceed their possible range. But sometimes when this could be really important, like controlling a rocket, you really don’t want the positive thrust to become negative or something like that. So you can see this could be an important consideration. Similarly, there’s well andnow all instances of security vulnerabilities where somebody wrote code that sort of expected a positive number in some place and clever person figured out, if I supply a negative number, I can fool the system and get it to do bad things. So these are the kind of corner cases that you need to understand better if you’re either working in programs where it’s really, really important that it worked correctly or you’re really worried about security vulnerabilities. Anytime you have possible for corner cases, you have to understand these nuances better.<br>我的意思是，90% 的时间，也许你可以通过编写程序而不必担心你的数字是否会超过它们可能的范围来获得。但有时当这可能非常重要时，比如控制火箭，你真的不希望正推力变为负推力或类似的东西。所以你可以看到这可能是一个重要的考虑因素。同样，现在所有安全漏洞的实例都存在，有人编写的代码在某些地方期望为正数，聪明的人发现，如果我提供一个负数，我可以欺骗系统并让它做坏事。因此，如果您正在处理非常重要的程序，或者您真的担心安全漏洞，则需要更好地理解这些情况。任何时候你都有可能出现角落案例，你必须更好地理解这些细微差别。</p><p>发言人   16:35<br>Similarly for floating point, if you’re going to use floating point for serious computation, whether it’s scientific research or for designing bridges or nuclear power plants or something, you better understand what the characteristics are. So that’s our first one. And we’ll spend a couple of weeks talking about numbers and number of representations in their properties here.<br>同样，对于浮点数，如果你打算将浮点数用于严肃的计算，无论是科学研究还是设计桥梁或核电站等，你最好理解它们的特点。这是我们的第一个。我们将用几周的时间来讨论它们属性中的数字和表示数量。</p><p>发言人   17:00<br>The second is we’re going to spend a lot of time in this course learning about machine level programming, meaning what the instructions are that actually get executed by the computer. And that can be described in assembly language, which is a text version of it, or an object code, which is the actual bit level binary encoding of instructions. And we’ll learn a fair bit about that and spend a fair amount of time seeing how code that you write in C gets turned into machine code and how that gets executed on the machine.<br>第二点是，我们将在这门课程中花很多时间学习机器级别编程，这意味着计算机实际执行的指令是什么。这可以用汇编语言描述，这是它的文本版本，或对象代码，这是指令的实际位级二进制编码。我们将对此进行相当多的了解，并花费相当多的时间来观察你用C编写的代码如何变成机器码，以及它如何在机器上执行。</p><p>发言人   17:36<br>One thing I’ll say is that historically, courses like this would teach assembly code by having you write programs and assembly that do various things. Not usually very interesting because it’s a lot of work to write assembly program. This course is much more about taking the assembly code that’s been generated by a compiler, AC compiler, and looking at it and understanding it. And that’s a different set of skills than you need to write it on your own. And in particular, we’re going to look at the language of Intel processors. The most recent versions of them are called x 80 two-six, a dash 64, the 64 b version of their instruction set. And one thing that’s new in this course compared to previous ones, we used to teach 32 b stuff. This course is 64 b all the time.<br>我要说的一件事是，历史上，像这样的课程会通过让你编写程序和执行各种任务的汇编来教授汇编代码。通常不是很有趣，因为编写汇编程序需要大量的工作。这门课程更多地讲述了如何将编译器生成的汇编代码，交流编译器，并观察和理解它。这是一套不同的技能，与你自己写的技能不同。特别是，我们将着眼于英特尔处理器的语言。它们的最新版本被称为x80 2-6，破折号64，即它们指令集的64 b版本。和以前的课程相比，这门课程有一个新的地方，我们以前教32个b的东西。这门课程一直是64 b。</p><p>发言人   18:34<br>Another one that we’ll talk about a fair amount that is really fairly visible to programmers, surprisingly visible aspects of the memory system. So modern computers have a very complex layered memory system to try and give you high performance and high capacity at the same time. And there are some results of that system that can mean that if you program, write a program well, it might work really well. And if you don’t, it could run very poorly because it’s not making use of this hierarchical memory system. So, and also, there’s a lot of bugs that show up, especially in C programs that have to do with memory referencing errors. And so understanding what those errors are, what their manifestation is, how to prevent them as a big part of the course.<br>另一个我们将讨论的问题，对程序员来说相当明显，令人惊讶的是内存系统的可见方面。因此，现代计算机具有非常复杂的分层内存系统，以尝试同时为您提供高性能和高容量。这个系统的一些结果可能意味着，如果你编程、编写一个好的程序，它可能会工作得很好。如果不这样做，它可能会运行得非常糟糕，因为它没有利用这种分层存储系统。因此，还有很多bug出现，特别是在与内存引用错误有关的C程序中。因此，了解这些错误是什么，它们的表现是什么，如何防止它们是课程的重要组成部分。</p><p>发言人   19:25<br>So for example, if I define a struct that contains a two integer values, A in an array, and a double precision floating point number d? This function fu n, you’ll see what it does is it’s given an argument I, and it sets the i-th element of A to some strange looking value. So as you know, I should really only be either 0 or one with this code, because that’s the range of possible values of this array.<br>因此，例如，如果我定义一个包含两个整数值的结构，一个在数组中，和一个双精度浮点数d？这个函数fu n，你会看到它的作用是给定一个参数I，并将A的第i个元素设置为某个奇怪的值。如你所知，这段代码我实际上应该只为0或1，因为这是此数组可能值的范围。</p><p>发言人   20:06<br>A, we can try other things too. So in particular, if you run it on either one or two, you’ll get what you’d expect that you assign 3.14 to element D of this structure. And when you read it back, you get the same thing. And in fact, but now if I set a of 2, two of this number, all of a sudden you’ll see that my floating point number, which it seems to have nothing to do with A, has changed. And if I do that same thing with I equal to 3, you’ll see I get a number that’s closer to two than to 3.14. And if I keep going, well, nothing much happens until I hit. Six, and then the program crashes.<br>我们也可以尝试其他的事情。所以特别是，如果你在一个或两个上运行它，你会得到你所期望的，你将3.14分配给这个结构的元素D。当你读回它时，你会得到同样的结果。事实上，但现在如果我将这个数字设置为2和2，突然之间你会看到我的浮点数已经改变了，它似乎与a没有任何关系。如果我对I等于3做同样的事情，你会看到我得到一个更接近2而不是3.14的数字。如果我继续下去，那么在我击中之前，什么都不会发生。六，然后程序崩溃了。</p><p>发言人   21:06<br>So something interesting is going on here.<br>所以这里发生了一些有趣的事情。</p><p>发言人   21:09<br>At least something quirky is going on. And the reason is, again, it has to do with how data is weighed out in memory and how it’s accessed. And one of the features of C and C++ is it doesn’t do any bounds checking on arrays. It will happily let you reference element number 5 million of a two element array and not complain. But the operating system might complain, as it did here in this particular, structure. And we’ll see more about how structures are implemented and weighed out.<br>至少有一些古怪的事情正在发生。原因是，这与数据在内存中的称重方式以及访问方式有关。C和C ++ 的特点之一是它不对数组进行任何边界检查。它将很高兴让您引用两个元素数组中的500万元素，而不会抱怨。但是操作系统可能会抱怨，就像在这个特定的结构中所做的那样。我们将看到更多关于结构如何实施和权衡的信息。</p><p>发言人   21:46<br>But basically the two, if each of these blocks in this vertical chain represents 4 B. And so the two elements of A each are 4 B, d is 8 B. And then there’s some other stuff in the other beyond that that’s not actually in the struct itself. So you’ll see that if I reference either A of zero or a of one, then I will just modify that array as designed, but what I’m calling fun of two or fun of three, what I’m actually doing is altering the bytes that encode this number d, and that’s why you saw the sort of funny numbers come out of it. And as I go up, at some point, when I hit 6 I’m modifying some state of the program that it’s using to kind of keep things organized, most likely how it keeps track of allocated memory and that’s causing the program to crash.<br>但基本上这两个，如果这个垂直链中的每个块代表4 B。因此，A的两个元素各是4 B，d是8 B。除此之外，还有一些其他的东西实际上不在结构本身中。所以你会看到，如果我引用零或一的，那么我只会按照设计修改该数组，但我所说的两个或三个的乐趣，我实际上是改变编码这个数字的字节d，这就是为什么你看到其中出现了一些有趣的数字。随着我的上升，在某个时候，当我点击6时，我正在修改程序的一些状态，它正在使用它来保持事物的组织，很可能是它如何跟踪分配的内存，这导致程序崩溃。</p><p>发言人   22:49<br>So this is a pretty good demonstration of YC programming can drive you crazy because as you saw, it doesn’t do bounds checking. So it’s easy to write code that does invalid stuff.<br>这是一个很好的演示，说明YC编程可以让你发疯，因为正如你所看到的，它不进行边界检查。所以很容易编写做无效内容的代码。</p><p>发言人   23:05<br>It’s also often the case that you’ll cause some problem and it has this sort of action a distance feature that you can modify, some think modifying some data structure and what you’re doing because of the way things are organized in memory, you’re changing something totally unrelated somewhere else in the program.<br>这也经常会导致一些问题，并且它具有这种操作距离特征，您可以修改，有些人认为修改某些数据结构和您正在做的事情是因为内存中的组织方式，您正在更改程序中完全不相关的某些内容。</p><p>发言人   23:26<br>And imagine they’re not just one apart, but they’re 10000 apart, and things might just run fine hours, days, or weeks, and then all said at some point that data that got corrupted a long time ago gets accessed and something goes wrong. So this can be some of the worst debugging nightmares that exist on Earth is to try and figure out memory referencing errors.<br>并想象它们不仅仅是一个，而是相距10000个，事物可能只运行了几个小时、几天或几周，然后在某个时候所有人都说，很久以前损坏的数据会被访问，出了问题。所以这可能是地球上存在的一些最糟糕的调试噩梦，那就是试图找出内存引用错误。</p><p>发言人   23:56<br>So this is actually one argument not to program C or C, and it’s a valid argument I’ll admit. But also as a person who’s written in a lot of C programming, you just get more experienced. And you know at times that you should actually put bounds checking in your own code. And there’s also tools available that will help you sort of. Bulletproof your code so that it will detect these kind of problems. So it’s not like you have to change languages, but it is a particular feature of these languages. And so understanding sort of the machine level representation of data structures and how they work is really makes a huge difference in your ability to deal with these kind of vulnerabilities and things. Vulnerabilities, by the way, also from a security perspective.<br>所以这实际上是一个不编程C或C的参数，我承认它是一个有效的参数。而且作为一个用很多C编程编写的人，你只会得到更多的经验。有时你知道你应该在自己的代码中进行边界检查。还有一些工具可以帮助你。你的代码可以防弹，这样它就能检测到这些问题。所以这并不是说你必须改变语言，而是这些语言的一个特定特征。因此，理解数据结构的机器级别表示及其工作方式确实会对您处理这些漏洞和事物的能力产生巨大影响。顺便说一下，漏洞也是从安全角度来看的。</p><p>发言人   24:51<br>The fourth sort of theme we’ll cover in the course is getting performance out of programs. Other parts of the curriculum and CS do much more emphasis on getting the right algorithm with the right data structure.<br>我们将在课程中涵盖的第四种主题是从程序中获得性能。课程的其他部分以及CS更加强调使用正确的算法和正确的数据结构。</p><p>发言人   25:05<br>And that’s really well and good. It’s important stuff, I don’t deny it, but there’s some amount of the sort of low level optimization that you need to do. You need to understand what the system does, what makes it run well, what makes it run poorly, in order to be able to do that kind of optimization.<br>这真的很好。这是很重要的东西，我不否认，但是你需要进行一些低级别的优化。你需要了解系统做什么，是什么使它运行良好，是什么使它运行不佳，以便能够进行这种优化。</p><p>发言人   25:25<br>So the example we like to use is these two functions do exactly the same thing in terms of their their behavior. What they do is copy a matrix or an array from called source or src to a destination Dst. They’re both size to be 2048 rows, 2048 columns, two dimensional arrays. And you’ll see that the programs do the obvious thing. You have a nested pair of loops to do the row and column indices, and you just copy from one source element to a destination element. The only thing that’s different you’ll see is that the two loops, their nesting is different. Their nesting order is different. In one case I’m going kind of row first, going through all the rows and then the columns, and the other is for any given row I’m copying all the columns.<br>所以我们喜欢使用的例子是这两个函数在行为方面做完全相同的事情。他们所做的是将一个矩阵或数组从被称为源或tgt复制到目标Dst。它们的大小都是2048行，2048列，二维数组。你会发现这些程序做了显而易见的事情。你有一对嵌套循环来执行行和列索引，你只需要从一个源元素复制到目标元素。你会看到的唯一不同的是这两个循环，它们的嵌套是不同的。它们的嵌套顺序不同。在一种情况下，我会先做行，遍历所有行，然后是列，而另一种情况是对于任何给定的行，我正在复制所有列。</p><p>发言人   26:29<br>That’s really the only difference between these two programs. But what you’ll find if you run it on a typical system is that one is much faster than the other. And this particular machine we ran it on, it was about close to 20 times difference in performance.<br>这实际上是这两个程序之间唯一的区别。但是如果你在一个典型的系统上运行它，你会发现其中一个比另一个快得多。和我们运行它的这台特定机器相比，性能差异接近20倍。</p><p>发言人   26:46<br>Fishing is going on if the same program that differs only in the seemingly insignificant way, a way that has no effect whatsoever on its functionality, can have this much performance difference.<br>如果相同的程序只是在看似无关紧要的方式上有所不同，但对其功能没有任何影响，那么钓鱼就是在进行中，可能会产生如此大的性能差异。</p><p>发言人   27:00<br>And so to understand this, you need to stare at the cover of the book. Because basically, you’re at two different points of this strange looking picture that’s on your book. And since there’s no axes or Wls on it, it makes no sense whatsoever. But it’s there. So what you see is this picture shows for different memory access patterns, and I won’t go into the details, what the throughput measured in megabytes per second on basically a copying program was. And without going into the details, what you’ll see is these two functions sort of sit at different points in this memory access pattern, The one that goes through row by row is much better than the one that goes through column by column. And as a result, you’re getting a lot better performance. And it has to do with this memory hierarchy and what they call the cache memories that you’re getting way better performance out of it in one case than the other.<br>因此，要理解这一点，你需要盯着书的封面看。因为基本上，你在这本书上这张奇怪的图片的两个不同点上。而且由于上面没有斧头或Wls，所以它没有任何感知。但它在那里。所以你所看到的是这张图片展示了不同的内存访问模式，我不会详细说明，基本上在复制程序上以兆字节每秒测量的吞吐量是什么。而且不深入细节，你会看到的是这两个函数在这种内存访问模式中处于不同点，逐行遍历的函数比逐列遍历的函数好得多。因此，您将获得更好的性能。这与内存层次结构以及他们所谓的缓存内存有关，在这种情况下，您可以获得比其他情况更好的性能。</p><p>发言人   28:08<br>So that explains what the cover of the book is about, and we’ll talk about it more later in the course.<br>这就解释了这本书的封面是关于什么的，我们将在课程的后面更多地谈论它。</p><p>发言人   28:17<br>And then a final part of the course talks more about not just getting computers to run little programs in isolation, but getting computers that talk to each other over networks and implement services like web servers and other functions like that, which of course, is where most of the world of computing sits today. It’s not just isolated machines, but computers that interact with each other over the network. They’re embedded controllers that are interacting with the physical world. Really, the world of computers is much richer environment. And we’ll cover at least some aspects of that in the final part of this course.<br>然后课程的最后一部分更多地讲述了不仅仅是让计算机孤立地运行小程序，而是让计算机通过网络相互通信并实现诸如web服务器等服务和其他类似功能，这当然是当今大多数计算领域的所在地。它不仅仅是孤立的机器，而是通过网络相互交互的计算机。它们是嵌入式控制器，与物理世界进行交互。实际上，计算机世界的环境要丰富得多。在本课程的最后一部分，我们将至少涵盖其中的某些方面。</p><p>发言人   29:00<br>So as I mentioned, the other feature of this course is it will get you ready for other systems courses you might take at CMU. And here we’ve listed actually a subset of the courses at the university that require this course is a prerequisite. And they’re mostly in computer science and ECE, but you’ll see it’s quite a range of of different courses. And each of them builds on, say, one or multiple aspects of the material you learn in the course. So the reason why we make everyone take this course, including incoming masters students, is that all these other courses at the university have come to rely on students being familiar and having done the work of 213 or 513 as a prerequisite. And they can build on that material and sort of cover more ground as a result, rather than having to do what would otherwise be somewhat remedial work on it.<br>正如我所提到的，本课程的另一个特点是它可以让你为在CMU学习其他系统课程做好准备。在这里，我们列出了大学中一部分要求这门课程是先决条件的课程。他们大多在计算机科学和希腊，但你会发现它有很多不同的课程。它们中的每一个都建立在你在课程中学习的材料的一个或多个方面之上。因此，我们让每个人 (包括即将入学的硕士生) 都上这门课的原因是，这所大学的所有其他课程都依赖于学生熟悉并完成了213或513的工作作为先决条件。他们可以在这些材料上构建并覆盖更多的土地，而不必做一些本来可能是补救的工作。</p><p>发言人   30:03<br>And in fact, one part of the genesis of this course was the people who taught the operating system course of 410 sort of complained that they were spending too much time at the beginning of the course talking about some very basics of machine programming. And Dave and I said, oh, well, we can cover that. So that was part of what got this course started.<br>事实上，这门课程的起源之一是那些教授操作系统课程的人抱怨他们在课程开始时花了太多时间谈论一些非常基础的机器编程。戴夫和我说，哦，好吧，我们可以覆盖它。所以这就是这个课程开始的一部分。</p><p>发言人   30:27<br>And as I mentioned that the course has a sort of perspective that’s very different from traditional systems courses. Most systems courses, including that whole array you saw there, were about how do I build some particular feature? How do I implement an operating system? How do I design a pipeline, microprocessor? And those, that’s all important stuff to know. We really want the people who are out there building operating systems and designing microprocessors to have learned how to do it.<br>正如我所提到的，该课程的视角与传统系统课程非常不同。大多数系统课程，包括你在那里看到的整个数组，都是关于如何构建某些特定功能的？我如何实现一个操作系统？如何设计流水线，微处理器？这些都是需要知道的重要事情。我们真的希望那些在构建操作系统和设计微处理器的人学会如何做到这一点。</p><p>发言人   31:00<br>And as a way to sort of get new into this and get the introduction and get the experience, we find it more useful to take what we call a programmer’s perspective, meaning understanding what you as a person who sits in front of a computer screen and types code, a need to know about that machine you’re typing code for in order to be effective at doing it as opposed to somebody who’s someday going to be designing the actual machine itself. So by taking that perspective, it gives you sort of an understanding. So now when you go off to implement it, you’ll actually know what these features are and why it’s important to implement them well, but also that by doing this programmer’s perspective, it letsen right away get tools that you can use in other places where you’re writing programs or doing anything related to it, and be more effective at that. So this programmer’s perspective really gives this dual benefit to it that we feel is very useful. And students who’ve taken the course in the past I’ve expressed that as well. So as I mentioned, we have two instructors for the course, and they also happen to be authors. And the longest we’ve probably taught this course more than anyone else, but it’s also taught by other people on campus as well. So what I’m going to do now is hand my pair of microphones over to Dave.<br>作为一种获得新知识、介绍和经验的方式，我们发现采用我们所谓的程序员视角更有用，这意味着理解你作为一个坐在电脑屏幕前输入代码的人，需要了解你正在键入代码的机器，以便有效地完成它，而不是某个人有一天会设计实际机器本身。所以从这个角度来看，它会给你一种理解。所以现在当你开始实现它时，你会真正知道这些功能是什么，以及为什么实现它们很重要，而且通过这个程序员的角度来看，它会立即获得可以在其他地方使用的工具，在那里你正在编写程序或做任何与之相关的事情。并且在这方面更有效。因此，这种程序员的观点确实给它带来了双重好处，我们认为这非常有用。过去参加过这门课程的学生，我也表达了同样的看法。正如我提到的，我们有两位讲师，他们也恰好是作者。这是我们教授这门课程最长的，可能比任何人都多，但也有其他人在校园里教授这门课程。所以我现在要做的是把我的一对麦克风交给戴夫。</p><p>发言人   32:36<br>All right, welcome, Good afternoon, it’s great to see you. My name is da hellern, and I’m just delighted to have the opportunity to be one of your instructors this term. This course is one of the reasons I’m so excited to be teaching this course. I mean, I just love this course. And the real reason is the opportunity it represents to have an impact on people’s lives. We really believe that the material you learn this semester can have a really positive and long lasting impact on your careers. And it’ll help you not only with your future classes, but also future positions you have.<br>好的，欢迎，下午好，很高兴见到你。我的名字是da hellern，我很高兴有机会成为你们这学期的导师之一。这门课程是我很高兴能教授这门课程的原因之一。我的意思是，我只是喜欢这门课程。真正的原因是它所代表的机会可以对人们的生活产生影响。我们真的相信，你这学期学习的材料可以对你的职业生涯产生非常积极和持久的影响。它不仅会帮助你未来的课程，还会帮助你未来的职位。</p><p>发言人   33:22<br>And I hear this from people all the time, former CMU students, students around the world who have taken the equivalent of 213 at their schools.<br>我经常从人们那里听到这个消息，这些人包括前CMU学生，以及世界各地在学校学习相当于213的学生。</p><p>发言人   33:35<br>Even a couple years ago, we were interviewing a faculty member, a tenure track faculty member who went to, did his undergrad at CMU, and then went off to Stanford, got his Phd at Stanford, and was coming back to join the faculty. And he told me that 213 changed his life in our interview. Now, I don’t know if he was trying to butter me up, but I think I believe him. He said it changed his whole life in the sense that it gave him a research direction. He didn’t really know what he knew. He kind of liked computer science, but he didn’t really know what direction to go. And after he took 213, he knew they wanted to do his life’s work in systems. Now, it was just remarkable, right, to come back And we ended up actually hiring him.<br>甚至在几年前，我们还在采访一位教职员工，他是一位终身教职员工，曾在CMU上过大学，然后去了斯坦福，在斯坦福获得了博士学位，即将回来加入教职。他告诉我，213在我们的采访中改变了他的生活。现在，我不知道他是否想讨好我，但我想我相信他。他说它改变了他的一生，感知它给了他一个研究方向。他并不真正知道他所知道的东西。他有点喜欢计算机科学，但他不知道该往哪个方向走。在他拿了213之后，他知道他们想在系统中完成他一生的工作。现在，回来真是太了不起了，我们最终聘用了他。</p><p>发言人   34:28<br>And he told me that everybody in his lab at Stanford, all of the grad students, had a copy of the book on their desk. And they were from all over, you know, all different schools.<br>他告诉我，他在斯坦福实验室的每个人，所有的研究生，都在桌子上放着这本书。他们来自各地，你知道的，所有不同的学校。</p><p>发言人   34:38<br>And so, I mean, even I was in a bookstore in Beijing a couple years ago, right outside the PKU campus, And I was up on the fifth floor trying to see if I could find a copy of the textbook. And I found the English version in one aisle. And then a couple hours over, I found the Chinese version. And I was going through the Chinese version, and this guy taps me on my shoulder, and I turn around, he says, oh, man, that book is really good. You should. The English version is two aisles over. And I mean, it just blew me away to be in the head of someone halfway around the world.<br>所以，我的意思是，几年前我甚至在北京的一家书店里，就在PKU校园外面，我在五楼试图找到一本教科书。我在一个通道中找到了英文版本。然后几个小时后，我找到了中文版本。我正在看中文版本，这个家伙拍拍我的肩膀，我转过身去，他说，哦，伙计，那本书真的很好。你应该。英文版是两条过道。我的意思是，它让我大吃一惊，成为半个世界的人的头脑。</p><p>发言人   35:23<br>It was, it was just one of those moments. And so I’m not trying to boast. I want to give you the sense of what an opportunity this course represents for Randy and I too, to have what we hope will be a really positive impact on your lives.<br>这只是那些时刻之一。所以我不是在自夸。我想给你一个感知，这门课程对兰迪和我来说是一个怎样的机会，我们希望能够对你们的生活产生真正积极的影响。</p><p>发言人   35:45<br>So let me, we have kind of a kind of a funny organization for the course in response to just the tremendous demand we found that we have for it. So there’s actually three course numbers, but it’s all the same courses, the identical courses, 513, 15, 513 is for our master’s students. And the 5 and 13, 513 doesn’t have a formal lecture, so there’s no seats assigned to it. Instead, we’ll videotape the lectures and we’ll make those available on the course web page for our for our graduate students. And the reason we do this is just because in the past, we didn’t have enough seats for everyone, And there would be cases where there might be 100 or 150 Masters students on the wait list. They wouldn’t be able to get into the course. And we didn’t really want that because they need this course to take other courses. So that’s the reason why we have this sort of does not meet version of 213 and 513 because we can admit as many, all the master’s students that need to take the course now, 15 to 13 and 18 to 13, or are for undergraduates in computer science and ECE respectively.<br>所以让我说，我们有一个有点有趣的课程组织，以响应我们发现的巨大需求。所以实际上有三个课程编号，但都是相同的课程，相同的课程，513，15，513是给我们的硕士生的。而5号和13号，513没有正式的讲座，因此没有分配座位。相反，我们会把讲座录下来，放在课程网页上，供我们的研究生使用。我们这样做的原因只是因为在过去，我们没有足够的座位给每个人，有时可能会有100或150名硕士生在等候名单上。他们将无法进入课程。我们其实并不想这样，因为他们需要这门课程来选修其他课程。这就是为什么我们有这种不符合213和513版本的原因，因为我们可以承认现在需要学习这门课程的所有硕士研究生，分别是15到13和18到13，或者是计算机科学和计算机科学本科生。</p><p>发言人   37:14<br>The undergraduates will go to lectures and recitations, okay? In person. Graduate students will watch videotapes of those, but otherwise, videotape available to all. Yeah, we’re making them available to everyone, actually. And lecture slides as well. Everything’s available on the course web page. So you’ll be doing?<br>本科生会去听课和朗诵，好吗？亲自。研究生将观看这些录像带，但除此之外，所有人都可以观看录像带。是的，实际上，我们正在使每个人都可以使用它们。还有讲座幻灯片。一切都可以在课程网页上找到。那你要做什么？</p><p>发言人   37:48<br>All students will have equal access to office hours, the staff mailing list, and everybody does the same labs and the same exams. So it’s just a question. It’s just a matter of whether you go to lecture in person or if you watch it on video. Since it’s available to everybody, if you miss lecture, it’ll be there on the web page and you can catch up, which I know you’ll probably do. Actually. I know most of you will never miss class, but the few of you who do, you’ll be able to watch the video.<br>所有学生都将有平等的使用办公时间和职员邮件列表的权利，每个人都做同样的实验和考试。所以这只是一个问题。这只是一个问题，你是亲自去讲座还是通过视频观看。因为每个人都可以使用它，如果你错过了讲座，它会在网页上出现，你可以赶上，我知道你可能会这样做。实际上。我知道你们大多数人永远不会错过课程，但你们中很少有人会错过课程，你可以观看视频。</p><p>发言人   38:22<br>Okay, all right, this is the one part. This is the part I hate. I love teaching, but this is the one part teaching that none of us really like, but we have to talk about it, and that’s academic integrity if you’re new on campus. Or coming from an international school, if you’re an international student new on campus, there might be different notions of academic integrity and different notions of cheating at undergraduate school, your old school. So if you’re new on campus, pay very close attention to this because at Carnegie Mellon, we take academic integrity very seriously. It’s not a wink, wink, nod, nod we’re very serious about. It, and we want everybody doing their own work to preserve the integrity of the courses.<br>好的，好的，这是其中的一部分。这是我讨厌的部分。我喜欢教学，但这是我们中没有人真正喜欢的教学部分，但我们必须谈论它，如果你是新来的，这是学术诚信。或者来自国际学校，如果你是校园里的新国际学生，在你原来的学校，本科学校可能会有不同的学术诚信和作弊的观念。所以，如果你是新来的校园，请密切关注这一点，因为在卡内基梅隆，我们非常认真对待学术诚信。这不是眨眼，眨眼，点头，点头我们非常认真。我们希望每个人都做好自己的工作，以保持课程的诚信。</p><p>发言人   39:28<br>So what exactly is cheating? So if you share code with anybody, either copying, retyping, looking at somebody’s code, like if you look at somebody’s code on the screen, or if you give somebody a file, all of those. Examples of sharing are cheating. If you describe your code like line by line to somebody, that’s cheating. If you coach somebody line by line, that’s cheating.<br>那么作弊到底是什么呢？因此，如果您与任何人共享代码，无论是复制，重新键入，查看某人的代码，就像您在屏幕上查看某人的代码，或者您给某人一个文件，所有这些。分享的例子就是欺骗。如果你对某人一行一行地描述你的代码，那是作弊。如果你一行一行地指导某人，那就是作弊。</p><p>发言人   40:09<br>Searching the web for solutions Just the act of searching is cheating. This is a real problem for us in particular because the courses are offered all around the world. People either maliciously or sometimes just they’re proud of their work and they post it for employers on like public GitHub sites. So it might be tempting to search for these solutions. But even the act of searching is cheating indefinitely. If you find some solution and use it, that’s cheating, even if you modify it afterwards. And I just want you to remember, I know how to use Google just as well as anybody else. I can search for solutions, too.<br>在网上搜索解决方案，仅仅搜索这个行为就是欺骗。这对我们来说是一个真正的问题，因为这些课程在世界各地都有提供。人们要么恶意地，要么有时只是为自己的工作感到自豪，并在公共GitHub网站上向雇主发布。所以寻找这些解决方案可能很有诱惑力。但即使是搜索行为也是无限期的欺骗。如果你找到了一些解决方案并使用它，那就是作弊，即使你后来修改了它。我只是想让你记住，我和其他人一样知道如何使用谷歌。我也可以寻找解决方案。</p><p>发言人   41:04<br>So copying code, you might be temp, you might be tempted to copy code from someone who took the class in a previous semester. Don’t do it, that’s cheating. Now what’s not cheating? So you can help each other use tools if somebody’s having trouble using Gdb or they have questions about how to run, use a text editor. That stuff’s all great. You help each other out using the tools, how to log in the shark machines, all of that kind of stuff. And you can discuss sort of high level design issues. And that’s probably a good idea. Yeah, Did you take it at a previous semester?<br>所以复制代码，你可能是个临时工，你可能会想从一个上学期上过这门课的人那里复制代码。不要这样做，那是作弊。现在，什么不是作弊？因此，如果有人在使用Gdb时遇到问题，或者他们对如何运行有疑问，可以使用文本编辑器，您可以互相帮助使用工具。这些东西都很棒。你们互相帮助使用工具，如何登录鲨鱼机器，所有这些东西。你可以讨论一些高层次的设计问题。这可能是个好主意。是的，你是在前学期学的吗？</p><p>发言人   41:58<br>Okay, yeah, the question was, if you took it in a previous semester, can you use your work? And the answer is yes. So you can also talk to each other about high level design issues, how you are you using an explicit list or are using a segregated list for your mallet lab? That kind of stuff is okay, high level OK, low level not OK. And basically what we want you to write your own code, this is not, it’s kind of a cut and paste world these days, right? You look stuff up on Google Stack Overflow, you cut and paste it, But that’s not the way we do it here. We want you to do the work yourself. We want you to enjoy the experience of figuring things out and learning how to solve problems.<br>好的，是的，问题是，如果你在上一学期学过，你能用你的工作吗？答案是肯定的。因此，您还可以相互讨论高级设计问题，如何在您的木槌实验室中使用明确列表或隔离列表？那种东西没关系，高水平的没关系，低水平的没关系。基本上，我们希望你编写自己的代码，这不是，现在它有点像剪切和粘贴的世界，对吧？你在谷歌堆栈溢出上查找内容，你剪切并粘贴它，但这不是我们在这里做的方式。我们希望你自己做这项工作。我们希望您享受弄清楚事情和学习如何解决问题的经验。</p><p>发言人   42:57<br>Now, the consequences for cheating, there’s a single sanction. If you’re caught cheating, you’ll be expelled from the course with an R, there’s no exceptions. If you drop the course, we’ll just reinstate you and then plunk you. It’s really, it’s a very serious, very serious penalty. Just we take it so seriously and. It’s just something we don’t want you to do. We have amazing tools to detect code plagiarism.<br>现在，作弊的后果只有一个制裁。如果你被抓到作弊，你会被开除了课程，没有例外。如果你退学，我们只会让你复职，然后解雇你。这是一个非常严重、非常严重的惩罚。我们只是非常认真地对待它。这只是我们不想让你做的事情。我们有惊人的工具来检测代码抄袭。</p><p>发言人   43:51<br>We have amazing tools to detect plagiarism. That are resilient to renaming, reformatting? They operate at a very deep syntactic level. So just please, please don’t do it.<br>我们有惊人的工具来检测抄袭。具有抗重命名、重新格式化的弹性？它们在非常深刻的语法层面上运作。所以请不要这样做。</p><p>发言人   44:10<br>We have, I think, 18 Tas will have office hours almost every day of the week. There’s plenty of opportunities and ways to get help. Start early. If you get stuck, start early enough so that if you get stuck, you can go ask for help. We have automatic extensions built in if you need more time. I’ll talk about that later form of grace days, but please, please, whatever you do, don’t cheat. It’s just tragic when it happens.<br>我想我们每周几乎每天都会有18个办公时间。有很多机会和方法可以获得帮助。早点开始。如果你被卡住了，尽早开始，这样如果你被卡住了，你可以去寻求帮助。如果您需要更多时间，我们会内置自动扩展功能。我将谈论以后形式的宽限期，但请无论你做什么，不要作弊。当它发生时，这只是悲惨的。</p><p>发言人   44:47<br>Last fall, 25 students were expelled from the course. Some were expelled from the university because it was a second offense. Many were sent home. I talked to students who were like the only person in their family to go to college, the only person in their village to go to college, and they were going home without a degree, and it’s just tragic. So please, please, please don’t do it. Do your own work and it’ll be a wonderful experience.<br>去年秋天，有25名学生被该课程开除。有些人被大学开除，因为这是第二次进攻。许多人被送回家。我和一些学生交谈，他们好像是家里唯一上大学的人，他们村里唯一上大学的人，但他们没有学位就回家了，这真是个悲剧。所以请，请，请不要这样做。做好自己的工作，这将是一次美妙的经历。</p><p>发言人   45:25<br>Okay, as Randy mentioned, the textbook is computer Systems, a programmer’s perspective, third edition. You can, there’s a whole bunch of supporting material on the book website at CSP docs dot CMU dot edu do. And as Randy mentioned, this book really matters for the course because it actually the came out of the course. The book is the course, of course is the book. And so it’ll really help you.<br>好的，正如兰迪提到的，教科书是计算机系统，程序员的视角，第三版。你可以在图书网站上找到很多支持材料，网址为CSP docs dot CMU dot edu do。正如兰迪所提到的，这本书对这门课程非常重要，因为它实际上是出自这门课程。书是课程，当然是书。所以它会真正帮助你。</p><p>发言人   45:57<br>The labs that we do come directly from material that we discuss in the book. So what I would encourage all of you to do, and I’m not sure if anybody has ever taken this advice, but I say it every year anyway, because I believe it. But I think a really good strategy for studying and preparing for this course would be to read each chapter 3 times, okay? Read it three times, work the practice problems. So we have litter throughout the book or practice problems with solutions at the end of the end of the chapter. And these practice problems are like little sort of bite size morsels just to kind of check your kind of a sanity check of your understanding of the material. So I think if you read this, if you read the book each chapter three times and worked at practice problems, that would be an excellent way.<br>我们所做的实验室直接来自我们在书中讨论的材料。所以我会鼓励你们所有人做什么，我不确定是否有人采纳了这个建议，但我每年都会说，因为我相信它。但是我认为学习和准备这门课程的一个非常好的策略是将每章阅读3次，好吗？读三遍，解决实际问题。所以我们在整本书中都有乱扔的东西，或者在章节末尾处用解决方案来练习问题。这些实践问题就像一口大小的小块，只是为了检查你对材料理解的理智检查。所以我认为，如果你读这篇文章，如果你把这本书每一章读三遍，并练习问题，那将是一个很好的方法。</p><p>发言人   46:48<br>To go through the semester and prepare, the other book we use is kenaan and Richie’s classic C programming book. I think this is still, this was written a long time ago. It’s still the best book around. I think for C, it’s a beautiful example of technical writing. It was one of the inspirations I used when I was writing the book. I tried to find that same clarity, precision that they, that kernaghan and Richie. Have in their book. So this is a really good book. I mean, this is a kind of book. It’s a reference, but it’s a kind of book you can just read from beginning to end and get a really good understanding of C?<br>为了完成学期和准备，我们使用的另一本书是kenaan和Richie的经典C编程书。我认为这仍然是很久以前写的。这仍然是最好的书。我认为对于C来说，这是一个很好的技术写作例子。这是我写书时使用的灵感之一。我试图找到与kernaghan和Richie相同的清晰度和精确度。在他们的书中。所以这是一本非常好的书。我的意思是，这是一种书。这是一个参考，但它是一种你可以从头到尾阅读并对C有很好的理解的书？</p><p>发言人   47:41<br>There’s four main components to the course. There’s lectures where we go over the high level concepts, recitations where which meet once a week for an hour, led by a Ta. The purpose of the recitations is really to help you with the labs. So it’s very practical and hands on.<br>这门课程有四个主要组成部分。有讲座，我们会讨论高级概念，背诵课，每周一次，每次一个小时，由Ta领导。复习篇的目的真的是为了帮助你进行实验。所以它非常实用和实用。</p><p>发言人   48:02<br>There’s 7 of those labs, and these are really the heart and soul of the course. This is where all the real learning comes in. I think when you actually have to do this stuff. And that’s why we take the cheating part so seriously, because if you do these labs, you’re going to learn an incredible amount of really cool stuff. If you don’t do them, you won’t learn anything, right? So each one of these labs is one or two weeks each and involves typically some kind of programming or measurement.<br>有7个这样的实验室，这些是课程的核心和灵魂。这就是所有真正学习的地方。我认为当你真的必须做这些事情的时候。这就是为什么我们如此认真地对待作弊部分，因为如果你做这些实验，你会学到很多非常酷的东西。如果你不这样做，你什么也学不到，对吧？所以这些实验室中的每一个都需要一周或两周的时间，通常涉及某种编程或测量。</p><p>发言人   48:40<br>There’s also two exams, a midterm and a final. The exams are Proctor, they’re online Proctor in Wean and Gates. And what we do for the exams is we have we take like four days from 10 to 10, and then you can sign up. And then we have like multiple clusters that are network isolated. And then you can sign up for a slot, like a six hour slot.<br>还有两次考试，一次期中考试和一次期末考试。这些考试是监考，它们是在断奶和门的在线监考。我们为考试做的是从10到10，我们需要四天的时间，然后你可以报名。然后我们有多个网络隔离的集群。然后你可以注册一个时段，比如六个小时的时段。</p><p>发言人   49:08<br>And the midterm is like nominally like an hour, 80 minute exam. It’s the same exam we gave when we used to have people sitting in person. So it’s nominally like 80 minutes, but we give you like a five or six hour window to do it. So you can sign up anytime, any day that there’s a slot. So there’s flexibility. So you can kind of tailor it to your your schedule. And I think we’ve also removed all the time pressure. So which is you can go back, you can check your work, you can just kind of relax and not be worried about how quickly you do it.<br>期中考试名义上就像一小时80分钟的考试。这和我们以前让人们亲自坐在一起的考试是一样的。所以它名义上像是80分钟，但我们给你五到六个小时的窗口来完成它。这样你就可以在任何时间、任何有空位的日子注册。所以有灵活性。所以你可以根据你的日程安排来定制它。我认为我们也消除了所有的时间压力。所以你可以回去，你可以检查你的工作，你可以放松一下，不用担心你做得有多快。</p><p>发言人   49:54<br>Now, there’s many different ways to get help. The main source of information is the course web page. That’s Www dot c.s.c.m. U Edu tilde 213 and all the information is there.<br>现在，有很多不同的方法可以获得帮助。主要的信息来源是课程网页。这是Www.c.S.c.m.。 U Edu tilde 213，所有信息都在那里。</p><p>发言人   50:09<br>We’ve got a complete schedule of lectures and assignments, we don’t change it, it’s fixed, and so you can look at that and plan your semester knowing that those dates won’t change. We’ve actually even got all of the lectures posted ahead of time for the other instructors around the world who are using the book, so we needed to get them all ready. There’s also news at the very beginning. There’s sort of news if we need to make announcements, we’ll post it there.<br>我们有一个完整的讲座和作业时间表，我们不会改变它，它是固定的，所以你可以看看它并计划你的学期，知道这些日期不会改变。我们甚至已经提前为世界各地使用这本书的其他讲师发布了所有的讲座，所以我们需要让他们准备好。最开始也有新闻。如果我们需要发布一些新闻，我们会在那里发布。</p><p>发言人   50:41<br>We don’t use either Blackboard or Piazza in the course. Instead, we have a staff mailing list that you can send mail to if you have questions and all of the Tas and all of the faculty are or subscribe to that staff mailing list. And so we’ll all see it. And we usually, we try to have really fast feedback. So there’s so many people, so many people looking at your emails that chances are very high an answer back quickly. The disadvantage of having the advantage of this mailing list is that it allows us to control the message. And control what feedback we’re giving back to you.<br>我们在课程中不使用黑板或广场。相反，我们有一个员工邮件列表，如果您有问题，您可以发送邮件，并且所有的Tas和所有的教职员工都订阅了该员工邮件列表。所以我们都会看到它。通常，我们会尝试获得非常快速的反馈。所以有这么多人，这么多人在看你的电子邮件，很快得到回复的机会非常高。拥有这个邮件列表的缺点是它允许我们控制消息。并控制我们向您提供的反馈。</p><p>发言人   51:30<br>The disadvantage is that we often get the same question over and over again. And so for that, we’ve established a fact. If we find we’re getting same questions over and over, we’ve established a fact on the course web page sort of organized by labs, you can see the answers to frequently asked questions on there.<br>缺点是我们经常一遍又一遍地遇到同样的问题。因此，我们已经确立了一个事实。如果我们发现我们反复收到相同的问题，我们已经在课程网页上建立了一个事实，该事实按实验室组织，您可以在那里看到常见问题的答案。</p><p>发言人   51:56<br>We have office hours. We’re still trying to meet with the staff and figure out the exact office hours. What we’re thinking now is that we’ll have office hours 6 days a week, every day if it’s Saturday. They will be at the same time and same place every day. So from 545 to 830 in, we the Ween 5207 cluster, we’ll have 213 Tas there to help to answer your questions so you don’t have to make appointments. I mean, you can make an appointment to see any staff member, of course, but you know that at the same time, the same place every day, there’s somebody you can go to for help.<br>我们有办公时间。我们仍在努力与员工见面，并弄清楚确切的办公时间。我们现在的想法是，如果是星期六，我们将每周有6天的办公时间。他们每天都会在同一个时间和同一个地方。所以从545到830，在我们这个5207集群中，我们将有213个Tas来帮助回答您的问题，这样您就不必预约了。我的意思是，当然，你可以预约会见任何工作人员，但你知道，每天在同一时间，同一个地方，你可以去找人帮忙。</p><p>发言人   52:51<br>Okay, for our labs and exams, every assignment, every lab is single person. So we don’t have any group projects. We want you to do the work yourself. Now, you know, it’s important to work in groups and you will learn how to work in groups and other classes, CS classes, but not in T 13.<br>好的，对于我们的实验室和考试，每个任务，每个实验室都是一个人完成的。所以我们没有任何团体项目。我们希望你自己做这项工作。现在，你知道，分组工作很重要，你将学习如何在小组和其他课程中工作，但不是在t13中。</p><p>发言人   53:09<br>This is a kind of a core course. We want you to figure stuff out yourself. All of our hand ins will be due at 1159 PM on either a Tuesday or Thursday. And this is, you can see which on the schedule page, on the course web page, and all of our hand ins are using Auto lab where you’ve probably used it for some of your other classes, but it’s an auto grading service that allows you to get instant feedback on your hand in. So when you hand it in, you get feedback right away.<br>这是一门核心课程。我们希望你自己解决问题。我们所有的下午都将在周二或周四1159点到期。这是，你可以在日程安排页面，课程网页上看到，我们所有的手都在使用自动实验室，你可能已经在其他一些课程中使用过它。但这是一项自动评分服务，可以让你即时得到反馈。所以当你交出来的时候，你会马上得到反馈。</p><p>发言人   53:44<br>The exams, like I mentioned, are going to be in network isolated clusters held over multiple days and you can just sign up for a slot that’s available. Now, what usually happens if we offer like the exam Tuesday, Wednesday, and Thursday? The Thursday slots fill up immediately. I guess you should try to sign up soon if you want, but people will always seem to want to defer to the end rather than. I mean, if it was me I’d want to get it over with, but. So I just, that is sort of a constraint, right? You can only sign up for slots that are available, okay?<br>就像我提到的，考试将在网络隔离的集群中进行，持续多天，您只需注册一个可用的时间段即可。现在，如果我们提供像星期三、星期四这样的考试，通常会发生什么？星期四的档位立刻被填满。我猜如果你想的话，你应该尽快报名，但人们似乎总是想推迟到最后而不是。我的意思是，如果是我，我想结束它，但是。所以，这只是一种限制，对吧？你只能注册可用的插槽，好吗？</p><p>发言人   54:29<br>Now, you know, we make mistakes. We always make mistakes, especially with just so many students.<br>现在，你知道，我们犯错了。我们总是犯错误，特别是有这么多学生。</p><p>发言人   54:35<br>So there’s, there’s a specific process for appealing grades if you think that there was that your work wasn’t graded properly. So what you do after either an exam or after your labs are graded, you have seven days to file an appeal. And appeals have to be in writing and hard copy. So no, we won’t consider email any appeals via email. It has to be in writing in hard copy and you give those to me and if I’m not there, you can just slide it under the desk. And what the reason we do it that way is it allows us to treat. Everybody fairly. So we get all the appeals together at once, and then we can treat everybody the same way rather than just sort of doing them one at a time like that, okay?<br>所以，如果你认为你的作业评分不正确，有一个特定的过程可以上诉评分。因此，无论是考试后还是实验室评分后，您都有七天的时间提出上诉。上诉必须是书面形式和硬拷贝。所以不，我们不会考虑通过电子邮件发送任何上诉。它必须是书面形式的硬拷贝，你把它们给我，如果我不在，你可以把它滑到桌子下面。我们这样做的原因是它让我们能够治疗。每个人都相当。所以我们一次把所有的呼吁集中在一起，然后我们可以以同样的方式对待每个人，而不是像那样一次一个地做，好吗？</p><p>发言人   55:37<br>Now for our labs we have. 10 machines that were donated by Intel called the Shark Machines. So initially, our first version of 213 in, I guess we started using Intel machines in 1999. We used the Alpha processors for the first year. I like to fish, so all of our machines, they were called the fish machines. They were freshwater fish. And then we upgraded a few years after that, and those were the saltwater fish machines. And then we upgraded like in 2011 to these nehale class servers had run out of freshwater fish and saltwater fish.<br>现在我们有了实验室。10台由英特尔捐赠的机器，称为鲨鱼机。所以最初，我们在213的第一个版本中，我想我们在1999年开始使用英特尔机器。我们第一年使用了Alpha处理器。我喜欢钓鱼，所以我们所有的机器都被称为 “鱼机”。它们是淡水鱼。几年后我们对咸水鱼机进行了升级，这些就是咸水鱼机。然后我们像在2011年一样升级到这些nehale级服务器，淡水鱼和咸水鱼用完了。</p><p>发言人   56:19<br>So the next grade up was sharks, right? So every fish is named after some kind of shark, but these are the same machines that that you that auto La uses for grading. So there’s some consistency for performance oriented labs like Mali lab, and you can access them. The names are listed on the course web page.<br>所以下一个年级是鲨鱼，对吧？因此，每条鱼都以某种鲨鱼命名，但这些机器与自动La用于分级的机器是相同的。因此，像Mali实验室这样的以性能为导向的实验室有一些一致性，您可以访问它们。这些名字列在课程网页上。</p><p>发言人   56:45<br>And so you can SSH to a specific machine. They’re all identical. If you have an Android account, you’ve already got accounts on the machines, so there’s nothing special to do. Or you can just SSH to Sharp do Ics, and it’ll just randomly put you on on one of the shark machines, okay? If you have any trouble logging in, just send mail to the staff mailing list.<br>所以你可以SSH到特定的机器上。他们都是一样的。如果你有安卓账户，那么你已经在机器上有账户了，所以没有什么特别的事情可做。或者你可以只使用SSH到Sharp做Ics，它会随机把你放在鲨鱼机器上，好吗？如果您在登录时遇到任何问题，只需发送邮件到员工邮件列表。</p><p>发言人   57:12<br>Okay, we know that during the semester things come up, grandparents die, especially near the they’re the final. That’s harsh, I know, but things come up right? And youve got you’re very busy, you’re taking a lot of courses. So instead of sort of dealing with requests for extensions and all these special cases, what we do is we give you 5 grace days that you can then spend as you wish.<br>好的，我们知道在这个学期里会出现祖父母去世的情况，特别是在他们接近期末考试时。这很严厉，我知道，但事情会发展到对吧？而且你很忙，你正在上很多课程。因此，我们不会处理延期请求和所有这些特殊情况，而是给你5个宽限期，你可以随意度过。</p><p>发言人   57:47<br>So if you hand your work in late one day late, you’ll automatically consume a grace day. We don’t allow you to sort of allocate the gray stays. You spend one of your grace stays handing in late. So if you have a grace day left and you hand in late, you’ll spend that grace day, but you won’t be penalized for the late hand in. And so we have five grade days over the entire semester. A maximum of 2 grace stays for the assignments.<br>所以，如果你晚一天把工作交给工作，你将自动享受宽限期。我们不允许您分配灰色停留。你花费了你的恩典之一，熬夜上交。所以，如果你还有宽限期，而你交晚了，你会度过这个宽限期，但你不会因为迟交而受到惩罚。因此，我们在整个学期中有五个年级日。分配的最大宽限期为2。</p><p>发言人   58:20<br>Now we’re going to set up since the first three assignments are kind of not as programming intensive and don’t take as much time, we’re not going to allow any grace stay for those because, oh, one grace day, sorry, 1 grace day. And then for the latter 4 labs, which are much more intense, we’re going to allow you a max of two grace days. And the reason we’re doing this is because we don’t want you to burn your.<br>现在我们要设置，因为前三个任务不是编程密集型的，也不需要花费太多时间，我们不会允许任何宽限期停留，因为，哦，一个宽限期，对不起，一个宽限期。对于后四个更密集的实验室，我们将给你最多两天的宽限期。我们这样做的原因是因为我们不希望你烧掉你的。</p><p>发言人   58:48<br>These grace days are valuable. They’re critical, especially later in the semester when you’re really, really busy. So we don’t want you to burn up your grace days early in the semester. And this happens every semester. And then when Malik Lab comes up, there’s no grace stays left. And it’s really sad to see that. And so we’re going to limit it to one for those first three just to help you save you from yourself. Now?<br>这些宽限期很有价值。它们很关键，尤其是在你非常忙碌的学期后期。所以我们不希望你在学期初就把你的宽限期烧掉。每学期都会发生这种情况。然后，当马利克实验室出现时，就没有留下的恩典了。看到这一点真的很难过。所以我们将前三个限制在一个，只是为了帮助你摆脱自己。现在？</p><p>发言人   59:24<br>The nominal late penalty, if you don’t have a grace stay is 15% per day. And we don’t allow any hand ins three days after the due date at all. So that auto lab shuts off and then that’s it. Now, if there’s some kind of catastrophic event, then please contact us for an extension. So we’re not, we try to be reasonable. Most of the reasons that for requesting extensions, you can handle yourself using your great stays.<br>如果您没有宽限期，则名义延迟罚款为每天15%。我们不允许在到期日后三天内进行任何操作。这样自动实验室就关闭了，就这样了。现在，如果有某种灾难性事件，请与我们联系以获取延期。所以我们不是，我们试图讲道理。大多数请求扩展的原因，你可以使用你的优质住宿来处理自己。</p><p>发言人   01:00:06<br>This is advice I give every semester too. But people often don’t, don’t pay attention, or just they’re unable to. But really, for every one of these assignments, you want to start early. And the reason is you need to give yourself time to go seek help if you get stuck, because the nature of these very programming intensive assignments like we have in 213, is that you’re going to get stuck. And often it’s very hard to bound the time you spend on some of these assignments. It’s not like problem sets where you can kind of predict this will take, this will take me like three hours to do these problem sets for a lot of the 213 assignments. It’s very difficult to sort of manage your time and bound your time. So for that reason, you really want to start early to give yourself a chance to get help when you get stuck.<br>这也是我每学期都会给出的建议。但人们通常不会，不注意，或者只是他们无法注意。但实际上，对于每一个任务，你都希望尽早开始。原因是如果你卡住了，你需要给自己时间去寻求帮助，因为这些非常需要编程的任务的性质就像我们在213中所做的那样，你会卡住的。而且通常很难限制你在这些任务上花费的时间。这不像习题那样，你可以预测这将需要多少时间，对于213个作业中的很多作业，我需要花三个小时来做这些习题。管理你的时间并限制你的时间是非常困难的。因此，当你遇到困难时，你真的想早点开始给自己一个获得帮助的机会。</p><p>发言人   01:01:02<br>Now in the lecture hall, you’re permitted to have your laptops. But we ask you not to send email or instant messaging or cell phone texting or anything like that. If you’re here, we want you to be attentive and engaged. Your presence in lectures and recitations is voluntary. So we don’t take, we don’t take role at either of those. We encourage you to come, but it’s not required. And no recordings of any kind except this one. Okay, the exams in labs are weighted equally, 50%, midterms, 20, finals, 30, and final grades are based on a straight 90, 80, 70 scale.<br>现在在演讲厅里，你可以有你的笔记本电脑。但我们要求您不要发送电子邮件、即时消息、手机短信或类似的东西。如果你在这里，我们希望你能专注和投入。你参加讲座和朗诵是自愿的。所以我们不承担，我们不承担其中任何一个的角色。我们鼓励你来，但这不是必需的。除了这一个，没有任何形式的录音。好的，实验室考试的权重相等，50%，期中考试，20分，期末考试，30分，而最终成绩则基于直90、80、70分。</p><p>发言人   01:01:56<br>Now, rough outline of the semester. The first three labs cover the machine representations of programs and data. Data Lab is how we teach you about bit level of representations of data.<br>现在，这学期的大致轮廓。前三个实验涵盖了程序和数据的机器表示。数据实验室是我们教授数据的位级表示的方式。</p><p>发言人   01:02:13<br>So you’ll solve collection of puzzles in C, like a puzzle might be, is a little function that you have to implement, like absolute value. So a function that returns the absolute value of its our input argument. The kicker is that we restrict the set of operators that you can use, and it has to be straight line code, no conditionals or loops. And so to solve these puzzles.<br>所以你将解决C中的谜题集合，就像一个谜题可能是，是一个你必须实现的小函数，比如绝对值。因此，这是一个返回其输入参数绝对值的函数。关键在于我们限制了您可以使用的运算符集，并且它必须是直线代码，没有条件或循环。所以要解决这些难题。</p><p>发言人   01:02:37<br>So imagine how you might try to solve absolute value without using an if statement. The normal way to do it would be if x less than 0 would return x or negative x? See, I told you we make mistakes, right? But imagine how you might do that without using conditionals and only using bit-level c operator. So this is our way of teaching you how data is really represented in the machine.<br>所以想象一下，你可能会尝试在不使用if语句的情况下解决绝对值。通常的方法是，如果x小于0会返回x或负x？看，我告诉过你我们会犯错误，对吧？但是想象一下，你可能会如何在不使用条件语句而只使用位级c运算符的情况下做到这一点。这是我们教你如何在机器中真正表示数据的方式。</p><p>发言人   01:03:10<br>Now, the bomb lab, which you’ve probably heard of, this is kind of famous all over the world now. And at CMU, the BA lab is the way we teach you how to read and understand assembly language.<br>现在，炸弹实验室，你可能听说过，它在世界各地都很有名。在CMU，BA实验室是我们教你如何阅读和理解汇编语言的方式。</p><p>发言人   01:03:26<br>And a bomb. Just briefly, a bomb is AC program that consists of a collection of six phases. And each phase wants you to type something in at the keyboard. If you type in the wants you to type what it expects you to type, then you’ve diffused that phase and it goes to the next phase. Then you have to type what that phase wants. And if you defuse all the phases, then you’ve defused the bomb. However, if you type in the wrong thing, then the bomb explodes by printing boom, and you have to try it again, and the kicker is, in either case, if you explode the bomb or diffuse a phase, that information gets sent to auto lab.<br>一颗炸弹。简而言之，“炸弹” 是交流由六个阶段组成的程序。每个阶段都需要你在键盘上输入一些东西。如果你输入了 “想要”，你要输入它期望你输入的内容，那么你就分散了那个阶段，它就进入了下一个阶段。那么你必须输入那个阶段想要的东西。如果你化解了所有的阶段，那么你就化解了炸弹。但是，如果你输入了错误的内容，那么炸弹就会通过打印炸弹爆炸，你必须再试一次，而关键是，无论是在哪种情况下，如果你引爆炸弹或扩散一个阶段，该信息都会被发送到自动实验室。</p><p>发言人   01:04:16<br>If you and we use the diffusing string that your bomb sends us and we check it out on a copy of your bomb that we keep on the server, well, that’s another thing. Everybody gets a different bomb, slightly different bond. So we check when you diffuse, when you diffuse a phase, auto La takes a string that it that your bomb sends us and then compares against the local copy of your bomb. If you explode phase, you lose half a point. So there’s a real consequence to exploding your bomb. It’s very tense.<br>如果你和我们使用你的炸弹发送给我们的扩散线，我们会在服务器上保存的炸弹副本上进行检查，那就是另一回事了。每个人都得到不同的炸弹，略有不同的联系。所以我们会检查你何时扩散，当你扩散一个相位时，自动洛杉矶会获取你的炸弹发送给我们的字符串，然后与你的炸弹的本地副本进行比较。如果你爆炸了阶段，你会失去半个点。所以爆炸你的炸弹会有真正的后果。它非常紧张。</p><p>发言人   01:04:57<br>Until you learn how to use Gdb to set a breakpoint before the function that sends the information to the server. And we want you to do that. So the bombs are really, the bombs are really beautiful.<br>直到您学习如何使用Gdb在将信息发送到服务器的函数之前设置断点。我们希望你这样做。所以这些炸弹真的很漂亮。</p><p>发言人   01:05:11<br>It’s kind of fun. It’s kind of like a video game. It teaches you how to read compiler generated code because, oh, the kicker is, sorry. The kicker is we don’t give you the source code. All we give you is the binary, hence the binary bomb. So in order to diffuse a bomb, you’ve got to fire up gdb single, find where the code is for each phase, single trace through that code, and sort of reverse engineer and figure out what it wants you to type in. And then you’ll quickly find out where that function that explodes the bomb is, and you’ll put a breakpoint there. And so we want you to do that because the bomb besides teaching you how to program assembly language, it also teaches you sort of organically how to use Gdb, because you really can’t do it if you don’t run Gdb.<br>这有点有趣。这有点像电子游戏。它教您如何阅读编译器生成的代码，因为，哦，踢球者是，抱歉。关键是我们不给你源代码。我们给你的只是二进制，因此是二进制炸弹。所以，为了扩散炸弹，你必须启动gdb，找到每个阶段的代码在哪里，通过该代码进行单一跟踪，并进行逆向工程，找出它要你输入的内容。然后你很快就会发现那个引爆炸弹的功能在哪里，你会在那里设置一个断点。所以我们希望你这样做，因为这个炸弹除了教你如何编写汇编语言之外，它还教你如何有机地使用Gdb，因为如果你不运行Gdb，你真的无法做到这一点。</p><p>发言人   01:06:08<br>And then the third lab, this is a new lab this semester that Randy’s developed. It’s called the Attack Lab. And we developed this lab specifically for a sixty-fourth architecture. So this is a reflection of the change from 32 b to 64 b. And this is, we’re really excited about this one. You’ll learn, you’ll learn how to. Write exploits using. To a sort of a modern technique called return to return oriented programming, which is kind of the modern way that hackers deal with the fact that stacks in newer machines move around. Prohibitive and make it impossible to execute code on the stack. So this is a brand new lab. I think it’s really, really going to be neat.<br>然后是第三个实验室，这是兰迪在本学期开发的一个新实验室。它被称为攻击实验室。我们专门为64架构开发了这个实验室。所以这是从32 b到64 b的变化的反映。我们对此感到非常兴奋。你会学到，你会学会如何做。利用编写漏洞利用。一种被称为 “面向返回编程” 的现代技术，这是黑客处理新型机器中堆栈移动这一事实的一种现代方式。禁止，使代码无法在堆栈上执行。所以这是一个全新的实验室。我认为这真的会很整洁。</p><p>发言人   01:07:06<br>In the memory hierarchy, when we study the memory hierarchy, we have a lab called the Cache lab, where you’ll build your own cache simulator. So this is how you sort of learn how this hardware that Randy was mentioning called cache memory works. You’ll build a simulator and C for that, and then you’ll take a small transpose function, and you’ll try to make that code run with as few misses as possible on your simulator. And this will involve sort of understanding of how the memory hierarchy works and how to exploit it.<br>在内存层次结构中，当我们研究内存层次结构时，我们有一个名为缓存实验室的实验室，您将在其中构建自己的缓存模拟器。这就是你如何学习Randy提到的硬件高速缓存的工作原理。你将为此构建一个模拟器和C，然后你将使用一个小的转置函数，并尝试使该代码在模拟器上尽可能少的失误运行。这将涉及对记忆层次结构如何工作以及如何利用它的理解。</p><p>发言人   01:07:45<br>The part of the course where we sort of transition from hardware to interacting with the system software, the operating system, there’s sort of a concept that we call exceptional control Fo that exists in all parts of the system. And it sort of represents that intellectual transition from hardware to software. So this is how this was sort of a key idea that allowed us to kind of smoothly move from hardware to software in some intellectually consistent way. And so the idea that you cover an exceptional control floor, like low, hard, low level hardware interrupts and exceptions.<br>在课程中，我们从硬件过渡到与系统软件交互的部分，操作系统，有一种我们称之为特殊控制的概念，存在于系统的所有部分。它代表了从硬件到软件的智力转变。所以这就是一个关键的想法，它使我们能够以某种智力上一致的方式从硬件到软件顺利转移。因此，覆盖一个特殊的控制层，如低、硬、低级的硬件中断和异常。</p><p>发言人   01:08:30<br>And then at the higher level, sort of evolving hardware and operating system software is the idea of a process context switch. So this is where you start to learn what processes are and how to ask the kernel to create manage processes for you at the next higher level or a software form of exceptional control flow called a signal. So this exists solely in the Linux kernel and then, and then even at a higher level, there’s an application in C language version of exceptional control flow called set jump and long jump. So this notion of exceptional control flow kind of exists in all parts of the system. And we cover it all at once.<br>然后在更高层次上，不断发展的硬件和操作系统软件是流程上下文切换的想法。因此，这就是您开始学习什么是进程以及如何要求内核在下一个更高的级别或称为信号的异常控制流的软件形式中为您创建管理进程的地方。所以这只存在于Linux内核中，然后，甚至在更高的层面上，在c语言版本中有一个特殊控制流的应用程序，称为set jump和long jump。因此，这种异常控制流的概念存在于系统的所有部分。我们一次性覆盖了所有内容。</p><p>发言人   01:09:17<br>And the lab that we use to sort of exercise all these ideas called the shell lab. And in the shell lab, you’ll write your own Linux shell is really cool. So that’s the program, the command line program that you interact with Whenever you log into a Linux box, you’re going to write your own. And I know for me, that was really exciting when I could write something that looked like a real shell. It was pretty neat.<br>而我们用来锻炼所有这些想法的实验室被称为贝壳实验室。在shell实验室中，您将编写自己的Linux shell真的很酷。这就是程序，每当你登录到Linux系统时与之交互的命令行程序，你将编写自己的程序。我知道对我来说，当我可以写出看起来像真正贝壳的东西时，那真的很令人兴奋。这相当整洁。</p><p>发言人   01:09:49<br>The next area we’ll study is called virtual memory. Virtual memory is a sort of combination of hardware and software that presents an abstraction to you of this of memory as a very large array of bytes, when in reality, memory is a hierarchy of hardware of cache memories and Drams, Virtual memory provides a very high level abstraction as just a linear sequence of bytes. It also does provides a lot of other useful abstractions that make many different parts of the system much easier to manage. So we’ll learn about virtual memory, we’ll learn how it works, we’ll learn about the performance impact, potential performance impact that it has on your programs, and we’ll also learn how to manage that large pool of memory that it makes available to you and the lab that we do that the lab where you’ll do that is called Malloc Lab.<br>我们要研究的下一个领域叫做虚拟内存。虚拟内存是一种硬件和软件的组合，它向您呈现了一种非常大的字节数组的内存抽象，而实际上，内存是缓存内存和dRAM的硬件层次结构，虚拟内存提供了非常高级别的抽象，只是一个线性字节序列。它还提供了许多其他有用的抽象，使系统的许多不同部分更容易管理。所以我们将学习虚拟内存，我们将学习它是如何工作的，我们将学习它对性能的影响，它对你的程序的潜在性能影响，我们还将学习如何管理它提供给您的大量内存池，以及我们进行的实验室，您将进行这项工作的实验室称为Malloc lab。</p><p>发言人   01:10:52<br>And in the malloc lab, you’ll write your own malloc and free functions.<br>在malloc实验室中，您将编写自己的malloc和free函数。</p><p>发言人   01:10:58<br>So you’ll reimplement the functionality of the LII, Mali, and free, and this is a. Maybe it’s two pages of code, but will be a guarantee. It’ll be the most sophisticated, difficult two pages of code you’ve written, not only because since it’s managing the memory system, you can’t use all of, I mean, c doesn’t have many. C doesn’t help you out a lot with abstractions for data structures when you’re writing, but at least it does give you ideas like structs and unions that you can use to structure your memory. When you’re writing a Mali package, you can’t use any of those. You have to ride exclusively on pointers and casting because malloc package is working at such a low level. And so it’s a very difficult piece of code for that reason. But also the design space for Mali is enormous.<br>所以你将重新实现LII、Mali和free的功能，这是一个。可能只有两页代码，但这将是保证。这将是你写过的最复杂、最困难的两页代码，不仅因为它管理内存系统，你不能全部使用，我的意思是，c没有很多。当你编写数据结构时，C并不能帮助你完成很多抽象，但至少它可以为你提供像结构和联合这样的想法，让你可以用来构建你的记忆。当你编写一个Mali包时，你不能使用其中的任何一个。你必须专注于指针和强制转换，因为malloc包的工作水平如此之低。因此，由于这个原因，这是一段非常困难的代码。同时，马利的设计空间也是巨大的。</p><p>发言人   01:12:02<br>You have many options. They all have implications that trade off performance and memory efficiency.<br>你有很多选择。它们都具有权衡性能和内存效率的含义。</p><p>发言人   01:12:12<br>And finally, in the last part of the course. We deal with IO input output. So, so far in the course, we’ve just talked about sort of running programs on machines. In the last part of the course, we’ll talk about input and output, sending data into and out of the machine. So we’ll look at basic concepts of Linux IO. Well, and since I think the most interesting form of IO is networking, which allows you to talk to machines anywhere in the world using the internet, We’ll also talk, we’ll learn how to do network programming.<br>最后，在课程的最后一部分。我们处理IO输入输出。到目前为止，在课程中，我们刚刚讨论了在机器上运行程序的方式。在课程的最后一部分，我们将讨论输入和输出，将数据发送到和从机器发出。所以我们来看看Linux IO的基本概念。嗯，因为我认为最有趣的IO形式是网络，它允许你使用互联网与世界上任何地方的机器交谈，所以我们也会讨论，我们将学习如何进行网络编程。</p><p>发言人   01:12:51<br>You’ll learn how to write programs that use the sockets interface, which is the basic interface for the internet to talk to machines, potentially any machine in the world. And that’s really exciting. I can still remember when developing this course, I had two windows open on my machine. I was sshd into two different machines, and I wrote a program to send a message like hello world from one machine to the other. And when that hello world appeared on the second window, it was like so exciting. I mean, if you’re a nerd, it’s really exciting. But just the thought that that have been any machine, right? That could have been any machine, opens up a whole new world.<br>你将学习如何使用套接字接口编写程序，套接字接口是互联网与机器进行通信的基本接口，可能是世界上的任何机器。这真的很令人兴奋。我还记得在开发这门课程时，我的机器上有两个窗口打开。我被分成了两台不同的机器，并编写了一个程序来将类似于 “hello world” 的消息从一台机器发送到另一台机器。当那个你好世界出现在第二扇窗户上时，感觉太令人兴奋了。我的意思是，如果你是一个书呆子，这真的很令人兴奋。但只是想到那是任何机器，对吧？这可能是任何机器，打开了一个全新的世界。</p><p>发言人   01:13:45<br>All of our hand ins are using a system called Auto La, which was developed here. And you can access it if you are on the roster as of this morning, if you go to the Auto lab link and you’ll see this course listed on your page, if you’re not enrolled, you won’t have an Auto La account and you have to be enrolled to get an Auto La account if you want to try to wait it out and wait for people to drop. I’ll make the first couple of at least the first assignment available from the course web page so you can work on it without actually handing into auto lab, but at least you can keep going.<br>我们所有的人手都在使用一个叫做Auto La的系统，这是在这里开发的。如果您在今天早上的名单上，您可以访问它，如果您转到自动实验室链接，您将看到此课程列在您的页面上，如果您没有注册，您将没有自动登录帐户，如果您想尝试等待它并等待人们退出，则必须注册才能获得自动登录帐户。我会在课程网页上提供至少第一个作业的前几个，这样你就可以在不需要真正进入自动实验室的情况下完成作业，但至少你可以继续进行。</p><p>发言人   01:14:32<br>Okay, if you were enroll, actually, I didn’t update this, but I updated the auto La accounts today. Now, one final thing, if you have wait list questions, please don’t. Don’t send email to the staff because we don’t control the wait list. You should contact one of these, either Cathy, Catherine, or Zara, depending on which class you’re in. Okay, so that’s it. Welcome again. Looking forward to a great semester, and we’ll see you on Thursday.<br>好的，如果你注册了，实际上，我没有更新这个，但我今天更新了自动洛杉矶账户。现在，最后一件事，如果您有等候名单问题，请不要。不要给员工发送电子邮件，因为我们无法控制等待名单。你应该联系其中一个，要么是凯西，要么是凯瑟琳，要么是扎拉，这取决于你在哪个班级。好的，就这样。再次欢迎。期待一个美好的学期，我们将在星期四见到你。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>深入理解计算机系统</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/12/15213/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/12/15213/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<table><thead><tr><th align="left">主题</th><th align="left">为什么学习？</th><th align="left">视频课程</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">Course Overview</td><td align="left">课程导读</td><td align="left"></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>自学大纲</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/12/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/12/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<table><thead><tr><th align="left">主题</th><th align="left">为什么学习？</th><th align="left">视频课程</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">编程</td><td align="left">快速学习一门编程语言，入门</td><td align="left">MIT 6.100L 计算机导论，以及如何使用 Python 编程: <a href="https://example.com/video1">视频</a></td></tr><tr><td align="left">计算机体系结构</td><td align="left">有助于你对计算机从“黑箱”操作转变为“白箱”理解，知其然也知其所以然。</td><td align="left">CMU 15-213 深入理解计算机系统: <a href="https://example.com/video2">视频</a></td></tr><tr><td align="left">算法与数据结构</td><td align="left">如果你不知道如何使用像栈、队列、树和图这样的普遍数据结构，你就无法解决具有挑战性的问题。</td><td align="left">Princeton Algorithms, 4th Edition: <a href="https://example.com/part1">Part 1</a>, <a href="https://example.com/part2">Part 2</a></td></tr><tr><td align="left">计算机科学数学</td><td align="left">学习数学将给你带来竞争优势。</td><td align="left">MIT 6.042J 计算机科学数学: <a href="https://example.com/video3">视频</a></td></tr><tr><td align="left">操作系统</td><td align="left">你编写的大多数代码都是由操作系统运行的，所以你应该知道它们是如何交互的。</td><td align="left">MIT 6.S081 操作系统工程: <a href="https://example.com/video4">视频</a></td></tr><tr><td align="left">计算机网络</td><td align="left">互联网是计算机系统伟大的发明。</td><td align="left">Stanford CS 144 计算机网络介绍: <a href="https://example.com/video5">视频</a></td></tr><tr><td align="left">数据库</td><td align="left">数据是大多数重要程序的核心，但很少有人真正理解数据库系统是如何工作的。</td><td align="left">CMU 15-445, CMU 15-721 数据库系统原理初级，高级: <a href="https://example.com/15-445">15-445</a>, <a href="https://example.com/15-721">15-721</a></td></tr><tr><td align="left">语言和编译器</td><td align="left">如果你理解语言和编译器的实际工作原理，你会写出更好的代码，并更容易学习新语言。</td><td align="left">Stanford CS143 编译器: <a href="https://example.com/video6">视频</a></td></tr><tr><td align="left">分布式系统</td><td align="left">如今，大多数系统都是分布式系统。</td><td align="left">MIT 6.824 分布式系统: <a href="https://example.com/video7">视频</a></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
